<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<answer_sheet ver="0.1">
  <answer_section label="D792W10_[1]" id="D792W10-1">
    <locale id="en">
      <instruction>
        <p> Regarding the development of transportation and communication means to promote colonialization of Asia and Africa and to raise ethnic awareness in various places, always use one of the nine phrases below, use 510 (a) answer column Discuss within words. </p>
      </instruction>
      <reference_set>
        <reference format="data" id="d01" is_directly_referred="0"> We live in the era of the information revolution and the integration of the world is progressing more and more rapidly. In addition to people and things going frequently, information is almost instantly conveyed to the whole world. Behind this, it can be said that there is a dramatic advance in transportation and communication technology. Looking back on history, there are not many cases where new development of transportation and communication means played a major role. In particular, from the mid-nineteenth century to the beginning of the 20th century, wired and wireless telegraphs, telephones, photographic machines, movies, etc. were put into practical use, and the revolution of audiovisual media also occurred. These technological innovations also draw attention as a background for Europe and the United States to extend their invasion into Asia and Africa. For example, Reuters Corp. gathered information from the world in the UK, supporting the overseas development of the British Empire. On the other hand, information shared around the world and the movement of people accelerated by the development of transportation means have also been a factor in stimulating local ethnic awareness. </reference>
        <reference format="data" id="d02" is_directly_referred="1"> Suez Canal, Steamship, Baghdad Railway, Morse code, Marco Island, Yoshikazu, Russo-Japanese War, Iranian Constitutional Revolution, Gandhi </reference>
      </reference_set>
      <keyword_set>
        <keyword>Suez Canal</keyword>
        <keyword>steamship</keyword>
        <keyword>Baghdad railway</keyword>
        <keyword>Morse code</keyword>
        <keyword>Marco Initi</keyword>
        <keyword>Yoshikazu</keyword>
        <keyword>Russo-Japanese War</keyword>
        <keyword>Iranian constitutional revolution</keyword>
        <keyword>Gundy</keyword>
      </keyword_set>
      <answer_set number="1" type="singleton">
        <answer length_limit="no more than 255 English words" format_string="" choices="" order="- 1" match_type="broad">
          <expression_set>
            <expression writer="writer1" is_gold_standard="true">In the 19th and 20th centuries, innovations in transportation and communication technology occurred, including the development of railway networks, invention of steamships, telegraphs by Morse code, and inventions of Marconi's radio equipment. These technologies were also used by Western countries to enter Asia and Africa. For example, the opening of the Suez Canal greatly shortened the travel time between Europe and Asia, while the United Kingdom put the canal under control and secured the way to India. Also, in Africa policy, he supported Cecil Rose promoting a plan to connect Cape Town and Cairo with railway and telegraph. Germany also aimed to advance into the Middle East by 3B policy including the construction of Baghdad railroad. Also, it was due to quick information transmission that POWER could quickly suppress suppression of the Yoshiwa disturbance in Qing Dynasty. On the other hand, Russia, which aims to advance to the Far East by the Siberian Railroad, etc., the victory of Japan in the Russo-Japanese War was quickly communicated to the world through the communication network, affecting the youth Turkish movement and the Iranian constitutional revolution, The national consciousness was raised. In addition, the development of means of transportation has also led to an increase in the number of talented persons who wish to study abroad in Europe and the United States from various places. This is one example that the origin of the career of Gandhi, a leader of Indian independence movement, was active as a lawyer in South Africa after studying in the UK.</expression>
            <expression writer="writer2" is_gold_standard="true">The opening of the Suez Canal has brought about a sharp shortening of Asian routes, and furthermore, when a steamer using steam appeared, it became easier for European countries to advance into Asia, which had a major impact on the progress of trade and colonization. In the 19th century, Morse code and Marconi's wireless telegraph were invented, the speed of information transmission improved dramatically, enabling colonial management on a global scale. Railway construction is regarded not only as an economic aspect but also as a means in colonial management, and Germany, which aimed to expand the power to the Middle East, has acquired the right to lay Baghdad railway from the Ottoman Empire. However, improvement of communication technology and activation of mobility have had a great influence on the development of nationalist movement in Asia and Africa. Japan's victory in the Russo-Japanese War triggered by problems relating to withdrawal after the Yoshiwa incident was instantaneously disseminated to the world and stimulated the Asian-African national movement. After that, in Iran, people who gained knowledge through media such as newspapers triggered the Iranian constitutional revolution, and in the Ottoman empire the young Turkish revolution broke out. In addition, many of the people who experienced overseas study abroad in Europe and the United States because it became easy to move, then participated in ethnic movements. Gandhi also studied in the UK and formed a resistance thought of nonviolent disobedience movement.</expression>
            <expression writer="writer3" is_gold_standard="true">From the mid-nineteenth century to the early twentieth century, the means of communication and transportation advanced dramatically. Speaking about communication, there are inventions of Morse code and radio communication by Marconi. As far as transportation is concerned, opening the Suez Canal in 1869 significantly shortened the steamer's shipping route to Asia, as compared to the traditional celebration peak, supporting the British 3C policy. In addition, the Baghdad Railroad, which Germany gained in 1899 to lay the ground, connected Berlin, Byzantium and Baghdad and lead to the Persian Gulf, boosted 3 B policy. This improved access to the home country and the colonies invited European countries to strengthen the colonial rule of Asia and Africa, while raising ethnic consciousness in Asia. For example, the Yoshiwa incident occurred in China in 1900, the Iranian Constitutional Revolution from 1905 to 1111, and the anti-British movement based on Gentile since Gangdi since 1919, all from anti-imperialism met. Also the Russo-Japanese War in 1904 was also a popular aspect as a color race victory against Caucasians.</expression>
          </expression_set>
        </answer>
      </answer_set>
    </locale>
    <locale id="ja">
      <instruction>
        <p> 運輸・通信手段の発展が，アジア・アフリカの植民地化をうながし，各地の民族意識を高めたことについて，下記の９つの語句を必ず１回は用いながら，解答欄(イ)を用いて510字以内で論述しなさい。 </p>
      </instruction>
      <reference_set>
        <reference format="data" id="d01" is_directly_referred="0"> 私たちは，情報革命の時代に生きており，世界の一体化は，ますます急速に進行している。人や物がひんぱんに往きかうだけでなく，情報はほとんど瞬時に全世界へ伝えられる。この背後には，運輸・通信技術の飛躍的な進歩があると言えよう。　歴史を振り返ると，運輸・通信手段の新展開が，大きな役割を果たした例は少なくない。特に，19世紀半ばから20世紀初頭にかけて，有線・無線の電信，電話，写真機，映画などの実用化がもたらされ，視聴覚メディアの革命も起こった。またこれらの技術革新は，欧米諸国がアジア・アフリカに侵略の手を伸ばしていく背景としても注目される。例えば，ロイター通信社は，世界の情報をイギリスに集め，大英帝国の海外発展を支えることになった。一方で，世界中で共有される情報や，交通手段の発展によって加速された人の移動は，各地の民族意識を刺激する要因ともなった。 </reference>
        <reference format="data" id="d02" is_directly_referred="1"> スエズ運河, 汽船, バグダード鉄道, モールス信号, マルコ一ニ, 義和団, 日露戦争, イラン立憲革命, ガンディー </reference>
      </reference_set>
      <keyword_set>
        <keyword>スエズ運河</keyword>
        <keyword>汽船</keyword>
        <keyword>バグダード鉄道</keyword>
        <keyword>モールス信号</keyword>
        <keyword>マルコ一ニ</keyword>
        <keyword>義和団</keyword>
        <keyword>日露戦争</keyword>
        <keyword>イラン立憲革命</keyword>
        <keyword>ガンディー</keyword>
      </keyword_set>
      <answer_set number="1" type="singleton">
        <answer length_limit="510字以内" format_string="" choices="" order="-1" match_type="broad">
          <expression_set>
            <expression writer="writer1" is_gold_standard="true">19・20世紀には、鉄道網の発達や汽船の発明、またモールス信号による電信や、マルコーニの無線機の発明など、運輸・通信技術の革新が起こった。これらの技術は、欧米諸国によるアジア・アフリカ進出にも利用された。例えば、スエズ運河の開通はヨーロッパ・アジア間の移動時間を大幅に短縮したが、イギリスは、運河を支配下に置き、インドへの道を確保した。また、アフリカ政策において、ケープタウンとカイロを鉄道と電信で結ぶ計画を推進するセシル・ローズを支援した。またドイツは、バグダード鉄道の建設を含む3B政策によって中東への進出を狙った。また、清末における義和団の乱を列強が迅速に鎮圧できたのは、素早い情報伝達によるものである。他方、シベリア鉄道などによって極東進出を狙うロシアに対して、日本が日露戦争で勝利したことは、通信網によって迅速に世界に伝達され、青年トルコ運動やイラン立憲革命に影響を及ぼすなど、各地の民族意識を高揚させた。また、輸送手段の発達は、各地から欧米に留学する人材の増加にもつながった。インド独立運動の指導者ガンディーの経歴の原点が、イギリス留学後に南アフリカで弁護士として活躍した事であったのはこの一例であろう。</expression>
            <expression writer="writer2" is_gold_standard="true">スエズ運河開通はアジア航路の大幅な短縮をもたらし、さらには蒸気を利用した汽船が登場するとヨーロッパ諸国のアジア進出はいっそう容易になり、貿易や植民地化の進展に大きな影響をもたらした。19世紀にはモールス信号やマルコーニよる無線電信が発明され、情報伝達の速度が格段に向上し、世界規模での植民地経営を可能にした。また、鉄道建設は植民地経営を行う上で経済的側面だけでなく手段としても重要視され、中東への勢力拡大を目指したドイツはオスマン帝国からバグダード鉄道の敷設権を獲得している。しかし、通信技術の向上や移動の活性化はアジア・アフリカの民族主義運動の展開にも大きな影響を与えていた。義和団事件後の撤兵に関する問題を契機とした日露戦争での日本の勝利は瞬く間に世界へと発信され、アジア・アフリカの民族運動を刺激した。その後、イランでは新聞などのメディアを通じて知識を獲得した人々がイラン立憲革命を起こし、オスマン帝国では青年トルコ革命が勃発した。また、移動が容易になったことで欧米への海外留学を経験した人々の多くは、その後民族運動に参加していった。ガンディーもイギリス留学を経て、非暴力不服従運動の抵抗思想を形成している。</expression>
            <expression writer="writer3" is_gold_standard="true">19世紀半ばから20世紀初頭にかけて、通信・運輸手段が飛躍的に進歩した。通信について言えば、モールス信号やマルコーニによる無線電信の発明が挙げられる。運輸について言えば、1869年のスエズ運河開通は従来の喜望峰回りに比べて汽船のアジア向け航路を大幅に短縮するもので、イギリスの3C政策を支えるものであった。また1899年にドイツが敷設権を取得したバグダード鉄道は、ベルリン・ビザンティウム・バグダードを結びペルシャ湾につながるもので、3B政策を後押しした。このように本国と植民地のアクセスが改善されたことは、ヨーロッパ諸国によるアジア・アフリカの植民地統治強化を招き、一方でアジアに於ける民族意識の高揚を招いた。例えば、1900年に中国で発生した義和団事件、1905～11年のイラン立憲革命、1919年以降のガンディーによる無抵抗主義に基づく反英運動は、何れも反帝国主義の立場から行われたものであった。また1904年の日露戦争も白人に対する有色人種の勝利としてもてはやされた側面もあった。</expression>
          </expression_set>
        </answer>
      </answer_set>
    </locale>
  </answer_section>
  <answer_section label="D792W10_[2]_(A)_Question (5)" id="D792W10-10">
    <locale id="en">
      <grand_question_set>
        <grand_question id="q 02"> Human beings have ingested and inherited the diverse cultures that existed in the long history from the early stage to the present age, created a new culture, and conveyed it to the next generation. Answer the following questions (1) - (10) related to this. Answer uses the answer column (b), revise the line for each question and write it with the numbers (1) - (10) at the beginning. </grand_question>
        <grand_question id="q03"> Europeans regarded the culture of ancient Greek and Roman as one of the origins of European culture and called it classical ancient. Answer the following questions related to the later European acceptance of Greek and Roman thought and culture. </grand_question>
      </grand_question_set>
      <instruction>
        <p> The Italian war was crushed for more than half a century in the Renaissance period. Record the politics situation of Italy which triggered this war within 60 letters. </p>
      </instruction>
      <reference_set/>
      <answer_set number="1" type="singleton">
        <answer length_limit="no more than 30 English words" format_string="" choices="" order="- 1" match_type="broad">
          <expression_set>
            <expression writer="writer1" is_gold_standard="true">At that time Italy divided into urban republics, papal territories and countries, and received intervention by France and the Holy Roman Empire aiming for supremacy in Italy.</expression>
          </expression_set>
        </answer>
      </answer_set>
    </locale>
    <locale id="ja">
      <grand_question_set>
        <grand_question id="q02"> 人類は，その初期から現代にいたるまでの長い歴史において，先行して存在した多様な文化を摂取，継承したうえで，新たな文化を創造し，次の世代へと伝えてきた。このことに関連する以下の設問(1)～(10)に答えよ。回答は回答欄(ロ)を用い，設問ごとに行を改め，冒頭に(1)～(10)の番号を付して記せ。 </grand_question>
        <grand_question id="q03"> ヨーロッパ人は，古代ギリシア・ローマの文化をヨーロッパ文化の源流のひとつとみなし，それを古典古代と呼んだ。ギリシアとローマの思想，文化を後のヨーロッパが受容していったことに関連する以下の問いに答えよ。 </grand_question>
      </grand_question_set>
      <instruction>
        <p> イタリア戦争はルネサンス期に半世紀以上にわたってくりひろげられた。この戦争の誘因となったイタリアの政治状況について60字以内で記せ。 </p>
      </instruction>
      <reference_set/>
      <answer_set number="1" type="singleton">
        <answer length_limit="60字以内" format_string="" choices="" order="-1" match_type="broad">
          <expression_set>
            <expression writer="writer1" is_gold_standard="true">当時のイタリアは都市共和国・教皇領・諸侯国に分裂し、イタリアでの覇権を狙うフランスと神聖ローマ帝国の介入を受けた。</expression>
          </expression_set>
        </answer>
      </answer_set>
    </locale>
  </answer_section>
  <answer_section label="D792W10_[2]_(B)_Question (7)_(b)" id="D792W10-14">
    <locale id="en">
      <grand_question_set>
        <grand_question id="q 02"> Human beings have ingested and inherited the diverse cultures that existed in the long history from the early stage to the present age, created a new culture, and conveyed it to the next generation. Answer the following questions (1) - (10) related to this. Answer uses the answer column (b), revise the line for each question and write it with the numbers (1) - (10) at the beginning. </grand_question>
        <grand_question id="q10"> Since ancient times, India and China have mutually influenced and cultivated their own culture, leaving great influence on the surrounding area including Japan. Answer the following questions related to this. </grand_question>
      </grand_question_set>
      <instruction>
        <p>
          Confucianism occurred in ancient China, is a thought that has been widely studied in East Asia. During the Han Dynasty, he established a status as a state religion, and a new systematization was made during Song Dynasty.
          <label_set>
            <label id="a" focus="0">(a)</label>
          </label_set>
          A northern Song Dynasty thinker who made the predecessor to this systematization, give one person who influenced the thinker in South Song Dynasty. Also,
          <label_set>
            <label id="b" focus="1">(b)</label>
          </label_set>
          Please summarize how this new Confucianism was treated afterwards in China, 30 letters or less.
        </p>
      </instruction>
      <reference_set/>
      <answer_set number="1" type="singleton">
        <answer length_limit="no more than 15 English words" format_string="" choices="" order="- 1" match_type="broad">
          <expression_set>
            <expression writer="writer1" is_gold_standard="true">Zhuzhi Zhuzi was established in Song Dynasty was later considered an Orthodox school of Confucianism.</expression>
          </expression_set>
        </answer>
      </answer_set>
    </locale>
    <locale id="ja">
      <grand_question_set>
        <grand_question id="q02"> 人類は，その初期から現代にいたるまでの長い歴史において，先行して存在した多様な文化を摂取，継承したうえで，新たな文化を創造し，次の世代へと伝えてきた。このことに関連する以下の設問(1)～(10)に答えよ。回答は回答欄(ロ)を用い，設問ごとに行を改め，冒頭に(1)～(10)の番号を付して記せ。 </grand_question>
        <grand_question id="q10"> インドと中国は，古代以来相互に影響をあたえつつ独自の文化をはぐくみ，日本を含む周囲の地域に大きな影響を残してきた。このことに関連する以下の問いに答えよ。 </grand_question>
      </grand_question_set>
      <instruction>
        <p>
          儒教は古代中国におこり，東アジアで広く研究されてきた思想である。漢王朝のときに国教としての地位を築き，宋王朝のときに新しい体系化がなされた。
          <label_set>
            <label id="a" focus="0">(a)</label>
          </label_set>
          この体系化のさきがけをなした北宋の思想家で，南宋の思想家に影響を与えた人物を一人あげよ。また，
          <label_set>
            <label id="b" focus="1">(b)</label>
          </label_set>
          この新しい儒教は，その後中国でどのように扱われたか，30字以内でまとめよ。
        </p>
      </instruction>
      <reference_set/>
      <answer_set number="1" type="singleton">
        <answer length_limit="30字以内" format_string="" choices="" order="-1" match_type="broad">
          <expression_set>
            <expression writer="writer1" is_gold_standard="true">宋代に朱熹が大成した朱子学はその後儒教の正統な学派とされた。</expression>
          </expression_set>
        </answer>
      </answer_set>
    </locale>
  </answer_section>
</answer_sheet>