<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TOPIC_SET>
  <TOPIC ID="K792W10-1">
    <PASSAGE_SET/>
  </TOPIC>
  <TOPIC ID="M792W10-1">
    <PASSAGE_SET/>
  </TOPIC>
  <TOPIC ID="M792W10-2">
    <PASSAGE_SET>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.45854086519154375" SCORE="0.8775533333333333" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-S-2-4-2-6" RANK="1"> His travelogue, are such as state of interaction with life and local people of the Muslim in various regions are drawn. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.40533620607928844" SCORE="0.739428" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-12-01-3" RANK="2"> Works of Delacroix of the Statue of Liberty France to lead the people. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.40533620607928844" SCORE="0.739428" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-12-01-3" RANK="3"> Workers who seek a more democratic electoral system is, from the late 30's, male suffrage, was cause under the banner of the People's Charter, which consists of six Article such as members of property qualifications abolished political movement (Chartist movement). </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.39751969798943965" SCORE="0.7206066666666667" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-S-1-1-3-10" RANK="4"> BC '31, Antonius will be suicide by losing to Roman army led by Octavianus, then, Cleopatra is to know that he is taken to Rome as a decoration of victory, he was standing his own life. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.3919045886873155" SCORE="0.7072906666666667" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-01-02-9" RANK="5"> Among them, the Egyptian Alexandria, prospered greatly as a central city of economy and culture. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.3919045886873155" SCORE="0.7072906666666667" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-01-02-9" RANK="6"> In this way, although police weakened political independence by being conquered Macedonia, the city of as the foundation of civilization life in which the police to prototype, and then still went continued to live in the ancient Mediterranean world. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.35573438150857606" SCORE="0.6252599999999999" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-15-03-5" RANK="7"> In Indochina that France dominates, Ho Chi = = the people formed the Vietnam youth revolution comrades meeting in 1925, Indochina Communist Party has been established it in '30 to the mother. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.3536516278901089" SCORE="0.6207186666666666" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-15-02-3" RANK="8"> But in '29, when the foundation of the economy is hit by the Great Depression While not stable, the German economy will be catastrophic situation, people's lives and parliamentary politics was confusion. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.33159536691478864" SCORE="0.573716" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-01-03-7" RANK="9"> The priests and Pharisees who had led the Judaism at that time and deference to keeping the law formally, also because I have cooperated in Rome dominated as the Jewish ruling, did not try to answer the people's voice suffering from heavy taxes. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.32451504976865575" SCORE="0.5590266666666667" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-3-8-2-8" RANK="10"> It was to lead the world economy after the first World War, it was in the United States. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.31545802014155094" SCORE="0.5405" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-12-01-2" RANK="11"> In Europe, and Greece causes a war of independence from 1821 the Ottoman Empire, since the United Kingdom, France and Russia helped it from interests for the Balkans, is independence achieved in 1829, approval of Rekkoku at the London conference of '30 me painting. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.29781851412234317" SCORE="0.5052166666666666" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-4-19-4-6" RANK="12"> In Vietnam, nationalist movement celebrated the uplifting life, nationalist political parties were born in the 1920s. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.29781851412234317" SCORE="0.5052166666666666" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-4-19-4-6" RANK="13"> The '30 Indochina Communist Party is formed under the leadership of Ho Chi = = Min, was uprising in Vietnam Central. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.29781851412234317" SCORE="0.5052166666666666" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-4-19-4-6" RANK="14"> On the other hand, Vietnam Kuomintang also was uprising in the north in '30, both have been put down by the French army. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.29781851412234317" SCORE="0.5052166666666666" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-4-19-4-6" RANK="15"> In Burma, in 1930 to sheath = but Sun is a large peasant movement happened led, and received a large crackdown by the British army. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.29696149413073963" SCORE="0.503528" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-4-19-5-4" RANK="16"> During this time also Depression proceeds, unemployment reached about 600 million people more than 30 percent in 1932. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.2821472843847764" SCORE="0.47469066666666665" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-4-20-3-5" RANK="17"> traditional values ​​of the United States society by the Vietnam anti-war movement growing fluctuation, doubt has been cast on the richness of life, which is determined by the economic efficiency in the first place. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.2821472843847764" SCORE="0.47469066666666665" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-4-20-3-5" RANK="18"> 3 consecutive days 30-400000 young people gathered, Woodstock became the land of the young people of the legend of this era. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.26959658809237347" SCORE="0.4507546666666667" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-S-4-12-5-10" RANK="19"> Because the United States was a country consisting of people who emigrated from various countries, words can even understand the story on the screen without knowing the, good guys and have bad is clear, was always important for simplicity, such as the good guys win It will of. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.26381713234732324" SCORE="0.439876" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-S-3-9-5-5" RANK="20"> The French Revolution previously, to the law in every region was different, because the force of the Royal Government was limited, people's lives was different for each individual region. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.26323049962206485" SCORE="0.43877666666666665" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-S-2-4-2-6" RANK="21"> In the 14th century, Ibn Battuta that was departure on a journey of hajj, to between 30 years, East Africa, Russia plains, India, Southeast Asia, that further traveled to China. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.26323049962206485" SCORE="0.43877666666666665" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-S-2-4-2-6" RANK="22"> He is life, was able to journey of about 12 million km is, at that time, and of inland and sea transportation road safety is secured well, it shows that the free movement of merchants and civilians was possible there. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.26036490143166763" SCORE="0.4334193333333333" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-2-4-2-8" RANK="23"> Under the Ottoman Empire until then, people of non-Muslims can not be forced to convert, I had to retain their religious and social organization. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.26036490143166763" SCORE="0.4334193333333333" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-2-4-2-8" RANK="24"> United Kingdom etc. at the end of the 18th century fight solidified its position in India of Plassey, the holding France aiming to lost territory recovery in the Napoleonic Wars, also, the base for the Dutch East India Company, which had been leading the maritime trade to Asia deprives one after another, began to conquer the sea of ​​literally world. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.25338745513685346" SCORE="0.4204613333333333" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-3-8-3-1" RANK="25"> Market to the expansion of production not keep up, leading the economy had given rise to overheating of speculation. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.25338745513685346" SCORE="0.4204613333333333" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-3-8-3-1" RANK="26"> Once the collapse begins, bankruptcy of the bank after another, people lose a modest savings did not know the number. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.24333182298456116" SCORE="0.40199466666666667" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-16-03-1" RANK="27"> However, this behavior leads to criticism of the international public opinion, because even America and the Soviet Union has warned, the three countries withdrew. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.23834137593961355" SCORE="0.39291733333333334" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-17-03-3" RANK="28"> President Suharto that has been in power for more than 30 years in Indonesia, in '98, was deposed by the economic slump in people's opposition movement with discontent. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.23280862018046286" SCORE="0.3829186666666667" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-4-19-3-1" RANK="29"> Now the United States on behalf of the United Kingdom, it is came to the world's leading economy. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.23280862018046286" SCORE="0.3829186666666667" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-4-19-3-1" RANK="30"> In the celebrated an unprecedented prosperity period the United States, the Republican administration that emphasizes the interests of the business community has continued over three generations in '12, laissez-faire policies and high rate protection tariff policy have been taken. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.23280862018046286" SCORE="0.3829186666666667" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-4-19-3-1" RANK="31"> In the &quot;Golden Twenties&quot;, automobile and home appliances are popular in the United States, popular entertainment such as movies and radio began to take root in life. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.22933615987977543" SCORE="0.3766773333333333" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-01-01-4" RANK="32"> During this time, but about 30 of the dynasty was replaced, partitioning the era which was particularly prosperous in three quarters of the Old Kingdom, Middle Kingdom, New Kingdom. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.2283059867584358" SCORE="0.3748306666666667" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-2-9-1-1" RANK="33"> Keiseito, as well aims to make in the world to Kant, the downfall was the small farmers to focus on management of the manor that peasants equal to the serfs (Tsukudato), to a notable layer to lead the community (scholar-official) It began to grow. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.2283059867584358" SCORE="0.3748306666666667" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-2-9-1-1" RANK="34"> But in terms of spending, and national defense and diplomatic costs, is increased cost to maintain the bureaucracy, public finances were tight. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.22544509966567192" SCORE="0.369714" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-12-01-3" RANK="35"> The king in 1830, in order to divert public discontent, do the expedition to Algeria under the control Ottoman Empire, Shiita a tyranny such as to dissolve the parliament left untreated convocation. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.22544509966567192" SCORE="0.369714" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-12-01-3" RANK="36"> For this reason, July 30, 10 Charles angry revolution in Paris is banished, Orleans home of Louis-Philippe, known as liberals is to welcome the king, monarchy was established in July. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.22544509966567192" SCORE="0.369714" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-12-01-3" RANK="37"> On the other hand, in the United Kingdom, which had been increasingly liberal nature, are abolished examination method in 1828, a result of O'Connell et al Irish of movement in the next '29, Catholics release method is established, attached to public office other than the country Muslim It became way. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.22544509966567192" SCORE="0.369714" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-12-01-3" RANK="38"> Voters plummeted and constituencies had (corruption constituency) becomes obsolete, that amount of seats, conventional emerging commercial and industrial city and that has not been recognized as an independent constituency, it is allocated to states with large populations It was. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.2163989233831219" SCORE="0.35364533333333337" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-01-02-9" RANK="39"> Alexander the Great is a Philip II of the child, in order to hit the ever Persian, which has been often interfere with the struggle of the Greek countries, was starting before 334 years east expedition led the Macedonian and Greek Allied. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.2163989233831219" SCORE="0.35364533333333337" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-01-02-9" RANK="40"> From east expedition of the Great, about 300 years until the longest surviving the Ptolemaic Egypt of destruction (before '30), is referred to as the Hellenistic era. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.2163989233831219" SCORE="0.35364533333333337" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-01-02-9" RANK="41"> 3 kingdom of Alexander the Empire and the Hellenistic era This is the era built in the city are numerous Orient and around the Greek style, the Greek culture was spread around these cities. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.21347932641740228" SCORE="0.34849399999999997" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-3-9-1-12" RANK="42"> Planned economy and it due to the economic efficiency of the poor, a huge bureaucracy, the Soviet Union-type socialism represented by the oppression of freedom, was established in Stalin's domination was 30 years. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.21347932641740228" SCORE="0.34849399999999997" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-3-9-1-12" RANK="43"> How the people of oppression by the state is depicted in such as &quot;The Gulag Archipelago&quot; of dissident writer Solzhenitsyn of the Soviet Union. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.2078615514250595" SCORE="0.338628" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-S-1-1-3-3" RANK="44"> The second half of the second century BC, gracchi it your decline of the defense force, tried to suppress the large land owned by the wealthy people with the aim of revival of the independent farmer, opposition by the reform of influential people failed. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.2078615514250595" SCORE="0.338628" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-S-1-1-3-3" RANK="45"> Caesar (Caesar) performs politics Pompey et al and three (1st Triumvirate), later strengthened dominance in Gaul conquest, became the life of the dictator. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.2078615514250595" SCORE="0.338628" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-S-1-1-3-3" RANK="46"> But his dictatorship leads to rebound, Caesar was assassinated by a Republican. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.2078615514250595" SCORE="0.338628" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-S-1-1-3-3" RANK="47"> Yet 30 years ago, can be conquered Egypt to complete the unification of the Mediterranean world, came to an end the era of confusion. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.20515853109444537" SCORE="0.33390200000000003" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-1-2-1-5" RANK="48"> For ancient people, it is the period of the phases of the moon was easy to understand, annual cycle of the sun was that hard to catch. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.20515853109444537" SCORE="0.33390200000000003" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-1-2-1-5" RANK="49"> In Egypt was originally solar calendar is used, but when it comes to the Hellenistic period, is set to one month 30 days and the extra days the 5th addition to the 360 ​​days of 12 months, the Alexandria system to put a day leap every four years It has been established. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.20515853109444537" SCORE="0.33390200000000003" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-15-02-2" RANK="50"> After the war for a while, international conflicts to rebound to border demarcation and peace conditions are secondary. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.20515853109444537" SCORE="0.33390200000000003" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-15-02-2" RANK="51"> In addition, Washington auxiliary ship that was left at the meeting also limited unity in '30 London Conference, the shareholding ratio between the United States, the United Kingdom, Japan has decided. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.19682378389843275" SCORE="0.3194126666666667" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-03-02-1" RANK="52"> Asia and Zui-dai canals of Sui-Tang era But distress of farmers that have been requisitioned to these repeated expedition to large civil engineering projects and surrounding countries is grossly, occur rebellion in various places on the occasion of the failure of Koguryo expedition, Sui's Horon in a unified 30 years less than. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.19682378389843275" SCORE="0.3194126666666667" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-03-02-1" RANK="53"> Asia and Zui-dai canals of Sui-Tang era Second generation of Taejong (Riyo-min) is allowed to subsumption the mainstay of the East Turkic as well as to unify China, followed Gojong, the East defeated Baekje, Goguryeo, west spread the sphere of influence by possession of the oasis city of the Western Regions. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.19682378389843275" SCORE="0.3194126666666667" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-03-02-1" RANK="54"> Conquered the land put Dohobu, actual governance was allowed to influential people of the land (Jimi system). </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.19289789069803226" SCORE="0.31262999999999996" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-15-03-5" RANK="55"> In the Philippines the United States is to govern, Congress opened in 1907, for the legislative and administrative, delegation of authority to the Philippines people were recommended. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.19158019442353974" SCORE="0.3103593333333333" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-15-02-3" RANK="56"> In the UK, at the 4th election law amendment of 1918, it is expanding suffrage to men and 30 women over the age of 21 years of age or older, in the 5th election law amendment of '28, and election to the men and women over 21 years of age rights were observed. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.19158019442353974" SCORE="0.3103593333333333" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-15-02-3" RANK="57"> By a resolution of the 1926 and '30 of the British Empire conference, '31 Westminster Charter is established, each Dominion as a member of the British Commonwealth, give a home and equal status to the original loyalty to the crown. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.19158019442353974" SCORE="0.3103593333333333" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-15-02-3" RANK="58"> 1929, compresses the total amount, payment period is also extended final payment plan (Young Plan) is determined, total compensation in the Lausanne conference of 1932 was reduced to 30 Oku-kin Marc. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.19084594444492511" SCORE="0.30909533333333333" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-09-04-4" RANK="59"> However, in the 16th century Nakaba also a Roman catholicism countries France can no longer be ignored Protestant force of Calvinist called Huguenot, Huguenot war broke out in the original regent Catherine-de-Medicis of Charles IX and his mother. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.19084594444492511" SCORE="0.30909533333333333" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-09-04-4" RANK="60"> The civil war in that confrontation of old and new sects are associated with partisan strife between the aristocracy, while accompanied by incidents such as the massacre of sambal Barthelemy, it ranged to more than 30 years. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.1868670774360988" SCORE="0.3022613333333333" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-1-6-1-4" RANK="61"> Ancient Southeast Asia and Japan there are many people who are like I thought that there is no relationship. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.17886116927394013" SCORE="0.288588" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-4-19-2-8" RANK="62"> However, naval disarmament is a step forward in the prevalence and the upper limit of the national capital ship is determined by the Washington Naval Treaty of 1922, but in '27 of the Geneva disarmament conference ended in failure, London disarmament of '30 prevalence and the upper limit of the auxiliary ship is determined at the meeting, we saw some progress. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.1778440213512095" SCORE="0.286858" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-01-03-7" RANK="63"> Before long the people of Palestine, was come to expect relief from this situation. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.1778440213512095" SCORE="0.286858" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-01-03-7" RANK="64"> The people Messiah Jesus (Messiah. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.1778440213512095" SCORE="0.286858" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-01-03-7" RANK="65"> Priests and Pharisees complained to the governor Pilate to Jesus as a rebel against Rome, he was executed crucified ('30 rollers). </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.169401802849015" SCORE="0.2725593333333334" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-4-19-3-4" RANK="66"> In the fourth-order election law amendment of 1918, voting rights of suffrage and 30 years of age or older women of men over 21 years of age it was observed, in the fifth-order election law amendment of 1928, to men and women all over 21 years of age suffrage was given. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.16803249958330937" SCORE="0.27025" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-12-01-2" RANK="67"> Did constitute a Latin American residents, in addition to the Kurioryo, Mestizo (Indigenous and whites of mixed race), Indio (indigenous people), mulatto (whites and blacks of mixed race), it was a hierarchy, such as black. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.16780663263722095" SCORE="0.26986933333333335" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-4-19-5-8" RANK="68"> On the other hand, Franco generals revolted in Morocco, civil war spread throughout the country, Germany and Italy helped Franco to send troops. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.16780663263722095" SCORE="0.26986933333333335" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-4-19-5-8" RANK="69"> The Popular Front side the Soviet Union to help, also for intellectuals and workers in each country, such as Hemingway and the United Kingdom of Orwell of the United States participated as international volunteers, the Spanish civil war and the field of international confrontation of the Popular Front and fascism became. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.16535810039799653" SCORE="0.26574733333333334" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-3-10-1-5" RANK="70"> Pro-democracy movement is growing since the late 1980s in Korea, '92, civilian government was born the first time in 30 years. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.1570147598901669" SCORE="0.251764" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-4-19-5-4" RANK="71"> The heart of the people in this way we are away from the Republic, Nazi (National Socialist German Workers' Party) and the Communist Party went stretched the force. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.1570147598901669" SCORE="0.251764" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-4-19-5-4" RANK="72"> Nazis led by Hitler, after it failed to Munich uprising of 1923, it turned to legal route, chanting such as destruction, construction and abolition of anti-Semitism, unearned income of the large German national of the Treaty of Versailles, Ya energetic masses propaganda by action force of the Sturmabteilung (SA), we gathered the support of farmers and intermediate layer was despair in the existing political parties. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.1570147598901669" SCORE="0.251764" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-4-19-5-4" RANK="73"> The Third Reich, the Holy Roman Empire, and second only to the German Empire, was used in the sense of the new empire. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.1570147598901669" SCORE="0.251764" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-4-19-5-4" RANK="74"> The people welcomed and dissemination of vacation travel by ensuring and Nazi work, academic and thought, speech, assembly, etc. were placed under tight rein. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.1570147598901669" SCORE="0.251764" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-4-19-5-4" RANK="75"> Many opponents and Jews, such as the Roma people, are persecuted by the SS (SS) and the secret state police (Gestapo), they were sent to concentration camps. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.1570147598901669" SCORE="0.251764" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-4-19-5-4" RANK="76"> Self-proclaimed exile people, which is said to have originated in India. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.149638338166269" SCORE="0.239478" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-S-1-3-4-1" RANK="77"> Emperor Yang of Sui was killed soon peasant revolt is placed around the country, Sui after unification, was destroyed in just 30 years. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.149638338166269" SCORE="0.239478" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-S-1-3-4-1" RANK="78"> Tang has been ruled a vast area that surpass the Han, except for mainland China performs an indirect rule by influential people of various ethnic groups, the Mongolian Plateau, Central Asia, Northeast China, the Dohobu etc. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.149638338166269" SCORE="0.239478" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-S-1-3-4-1" RANK="79"> End of the 7th century, such as law tenmu after the change the country name and the peripheral on temporary throne, there was a political turmoil, Xuanzong appeared in early 8th century, in the first half of his reign I came to an unprecedented prosperity. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.1412829200457626" SCORE="0.22564333333333333" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-12-03-2" RANK="80"> In contrast, northern industrial revolution was the development of capitalism proceeds claims the protection tariff policy and federalism in order to compete in the United Kingdom, also people who oppose from the standpoint of humanitarian slavery there were many. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.1412829200457626" SCORE="0.22564333333333333" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-12-03-2" RANK="81"> When the free man of the adult male population of a certain region reaches 5 thousand people, the self-government is provided as Territories, when the total free population is 60,000 people were promoted to the province by example the approval of the federal parliament, and joined the Federation. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.1412829200457626" SCORE="0.22564333333333333" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-12-03-2" RANK="82"> In 1820, is tied Missouri agreement in north latitude 36 degrees 30 minutes north was determined to be not made the slave states, this conflict has subsided time. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.1412829200457626" SCORE="0.22564333333333333" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-12-03-2" RANK="83"> In a speech of Lincoln November 19, 1863 to be speech in Gettysburg, Lincoln appealed to &quot;the people, by the people, politics for the people&quot;. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.1412829200457626" SCORE="0.22564333333333333" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-12-03-2" RANK="84"> However, in January 1863, Lincoln issues the Emancipation Proclamation of the southern rebellion region, to collect the support of public opinion inside and outside. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.1412829200457626" SCORE="0.22564333333333333" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-12-03-2" RANK="85"> And from give a victory in the battle of the same year of Gettysburg, the Union led by General Grant became dominant. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.1412829200457626" SCORE="0.22564333333333333" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-12-03-2" RANK="86"> In a speech of Lincoln November 19, 1863 to be speech in Gettysburg, Lincoln appealed to &quot;the people, by the people, politics for the people&quot;. ' </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.14112177424247316" SCORE="0.22537733333333335" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-S-4-12-5-10" RANK="87"> In addition, the western-themed Wild West is where they excel of American movies, it was pleasing to the people around the world. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.13953154713510882" SCORE="0.222754" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-15-03-3" RANK="88"> 1919 Soviet government with respect to China, in the name of Foreign Affairs People's Committee deputy Callahan, declare a waiver of any of the imperial privilege the former Russian government had in China, has been welcomed by the Chinese people. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.13953154713510882" SCORE="0.222754" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-15-03-3" RANK="89"> In '21, with the help of the Comintern, the Chinese Communist Party that leader Chen Xiu Germany was formed. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.13953154713510882" SCORE="0.222754" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-15-03-3" RANK="90"> On the other hand, Sun Yat-sen, which was aiming to strengthen the KMT, to lead an advisor to accept the Soviet aid, as well as promote the modernization of the party organization and reorganized the Kuomintang '24, Communist Party members is it joined the KMT in a personal capacity it was acknowledged that (first-order Kokkyo cooperation). </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.13953154713510882" SCORE="0.222754" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-15-03-3" RANK="91"> Demonstrators to protest the shooting death of the strike the workers by the company side, from the incident that issued the casualties of dozens are crackdown in Shanghai Concession police on May 30, the movement has expanded nationwide. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.13953154713510882" SCORE="0.222754" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-15-03-3" RANK="92"> July 1925, the KMT is to establish a national government in Guangzhou, the following year, Chiang Kai-shek led national government forces began the Northern Expedition aims to China unification. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.13953154713510882" SCORE="0.222754" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-15-03-3" RANK="93"> Been assisted led peasant movement of Communist Party members warlords overthrow proceeds smoothly, in March 27 was occupied Nanjing and Shanghai. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.137822557119671" SCORE="0.219938" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-S-3-9-5-5" RANK="94"> The capital has a role as a political and economic and center of academic and cultural, of one country, and remembering the pride to the people, to visitors from abroad, impress the richness and strength of the country. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.137822557119671" SCORE="0.219938" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-S-3-9-5-5" RANK="95"> Brain and the first modern city in which both of the role was imposed in the face of the nation was Paris. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.137822557119671" SCORE="0.219938" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-S-3-9-5-5" RANK="96"> Furthermore it is and central banks and the stock exchange Napoleon, because the important educational institutions were placed in Paris, came to Paris to dominate the social life of all the French. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.137822557119671" SCORE="0.219938" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-S-3-9-5-5" RANK="97"> Throughout the 19th century, the city's government district and financial, newspapers gather city, the shopping district and entertainment of the city was born in Paris. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.137822557119671" SCORE="0.219938" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-S-3-9-5-5" RANK="98"> About 550,000 was the Paris of the population in 1801 to 720,000 in an increase of about 30% to Napoleon's reign period, to 1.07 million in 1856, in 1872 it became 1.85 million. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.137822557119671" SCORE="0.219938" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-S-3-9-5-5" RANK="99"> Water and sewage and for population has increased rapidly, is required transportation of the development of the city. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.137822557119671" SCORE="0.219938" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-S-3-9-5-5" RANK="100"> Also requires the police of the city in order to protect the safety, uniform policeman was born. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.137822557119671" SCORE="0.219938" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-S-3-9-5-5" RANK="101"> And people and goods, further destroyed the streets since the Middle Ages in order to improve the flow of air, width is wide straight line of tree-lined street was built. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.137822557119671" SCORE="0.219938" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-S-3-9-5-5" RANK="102"> While considering the beauty of the entire city, now also carried out urban planning that attempts to place the road and transportation. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.12627630116037405" SCORE="0.20099733333333333" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-16-03-1" RANK="103"> 1954, gathered in five South Asian countries leaders Colombo such as India, Asian and African countries meeting held, we propose a nuclear test stop, also China's Zhou Enlai prime minister has announced a peace five principles can be met with Nehru Prime Minister of India . </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.12627630116037405" SCORE="0.20099733333333333" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-16-03-1" RANK="104"> Five principles, respect for territorial integrity and sovereignty, non-aggression, non-interference in internal affairs, equality and mutual benefit, and peaceful coexistence. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.12627630116037405" SCORE="0.20099733333333333" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-16-03-1" RANK="105"> Next '55, meeting representatives of the Asia-Africa 29 countries participated in Indonesia of Bandung (Asia = Africa conference &lt;Bandung conference&gt;) is opened ten principles sang the peaceful coexistence and anti-colonialism was adopted. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.12627630116037405" SCORE="0.20099733333333333" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-16-03-1" RANK="106"> The conference, peaceful coexistence, support of national liberation, and to declare a break of colonialism, has vowed to take a joint pace. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.12627630116037405" SCORE="0.20099733333333333" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-16-03-1" RANK="107"> Egypt After this went to the leading position of Arab nationalism. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.12627630116037405" SCORE="0.20099733333333333" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-16-03-1" RANK="108"> Nkrumah to request an immediate independent en car Ghana that speech is, the place where wields spiel before the people. ' </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.12627630116037405" SCORE="0.20099733333333333" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-16-03-1" RANK="109"> 63, 30 countries participated in the Ethiopia of African countries summit held in Addis Ababa, and formed the Organization of African Unity (OAU), African countries of solidarity, aimed at overcoming of colonialism. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.12349667551625272" SCORE="0.19645866666666667" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-17-03-3" RANK="110"> During this period, South Korea to recover the Soviet Union and China and diplomatic relations, in '91 was a member of the United Nations along with the Democratic People's Republic of Korea. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.12349667551625272" SCORE="0.19645866666666667" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-17-03-3" RANK="111"> 1965, unilaterally independent Rhodesia from the United Kingdom, to accept the black majority domination in the face of criticism of the armed struggle and international public opinion of the liberation movement, has become a '80 Country to the State of black principals and Zimbabwe. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.12190996550977651" SCORE="0.19387133333333334" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-3-17-2-11" RANK="112"> Whether or not recognize slavery in the western part of the new state, in the Missouri agreement that was signed in 1820, but seemed to do was not fall for a fixed to be in north latitude 36 degrees 30 minutes north not allow slavery, northern in among the voice of slavery increases, in 1860, Lincoln Republican opposition to slavery expansion was elected president. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.12190996550977651" SCORE="0.19387133333333334" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-3-17-2-11" RANK="113"> Introduction Although the South was the dominant, canopy solidified the support of western farmers by self-employed Agricultural Land Act (Homestead Act), in 1863 it was attached to ally the inside and outside of the public opinion to announce the Emancipation Proclamation. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.12190996550977651" SCORE="0.19387133333333334" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-3-17-2-11" RANK="114"> The settlers were settled in public land for five years, was determined to give a certain land at no charge. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.12190996550977651" SCORE="0.19387133333333334" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-3-17-2-11" RANK="115"> Many were forced to hard life as a share Cropper (sharecropper). </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.12190996550977651" SCORE="0.19387133333333334" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-3-17-2-11" RANK="116"> Mainly in the eastern urbanization also progressed rapidly, it is also quickly introduced new technologies such as electric light and telegraph and telephone, the basis of prosperity in the 20th century has been built here. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.11851187021190941" SCORE="0.18833866666666665" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-01-01-4" RANK="117"> Greek historian words of Herodotus. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.11851187021190941" SCORE="0.18833866666666665" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-01-01-4" RANK="118"> In this basin, early on a number of villages (Nomos), but has been formed, and the joint labor of residents in flood control of the Nile, strong leader to lead them was required. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.11851187021190941" SCORE="0.18833866666666665" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-01-01-4" RANK="119"> The Egyptian character that they have used, and the sacred character of the hieroglyphics that are carved in such inscriptions and tomb room, sarcophagus (hieroglyphs), but the people for the characters that are written on paper (papyrus) of a kind that was made from papyrus grass (Demotic) there were. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.11851187021190941" SCORE="0.18833866666666665" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-01-01-4" RANK="120"> The sacred character in the upper part, people for the character in the middle, it is written in three Greek letters in the lower part. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.11851187021190941" SCORE="0.18833866666666665" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-01-01-4" RANK="121"> The sacred character in the upper part, people for the character in the middle, it is written in three Greek letters in the lower part. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.11369934287874175" SCORE="0.180522" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-16-02-3" RANK="122"> The US economy had continued a steady growth, it as been placed in the shadow of prosperity to this, from among the blacks who had suffered discrimination, spread the movement seeking equal civil rights. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.11153647751768406" SCORE="0.177016" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-15-04-3" RANK="123"> However, existing political parties will lose the people's trust to continue the power struggle, the military claimed to solve the economic crisis in the dominant zone expansion in the continent. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.11153647751768406" SCORE="0.177016" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-15-04-3" RANK="124"> People of the front row center of the glasses Puyi. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.11153647751768406" SCORE="0.177016" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-15-04-3" RANK="125"> Nationalist Government of China is give a force in 30 years of tariff autonomy recovery from 1928, aimed at domestic political and military unification, than the corresponding to the military actions of Japan, such as the Manchurian Incident, the power to fight against the Communist Party put. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.11153647751768406" SCORE="0.177016" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-15-04-3" RANK="126"> Expansion during the day war 37 by the end of the year, Japan has been occupied Nanjing and key area of ​​North China, at the time of the Nanjing occupation by killing a large number of Chinese (Nanjing massacre), it was criticized in the international public opinion. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.11153647751768406" SCORE="0.177016" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-15-04-3" RANK="127"> Although Japan has secured important cities and traffic route connecting it, it was not able to dominate the broad rural areas. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0948394133638469" SCORE="0.15008533333333332" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-3-7-3-8" RANK="128"> The first half of the 20th century, in between the human race only 30 years, experienced a world war over two degrees. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0948394133638469" SCORE="0.15008533333333332" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-3-7-3-8" RANK="129"> The war transformed the fate of countless people, the devastation was left a deep scar in various parts of the world. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0948394133638469" SCORE="0.15008533333333332" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-3-7-3-8" RANK="130"> The result of the two wars, the direction of the subsequent history of the various regions decisive, it is no exaggeration to say has been a big influence factor the history of people, and until today. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0948394133638469" SCORE="0.15008533333333332" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-3-7-3-8" RANK="131"> 20 century early 1901, which opened the curtain, I finished life of British Queen Victoria was over the reign 60 Toshi-yo. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0948394133638469" SCORE="0.15008533333333332" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-3-7-3-8" RANK="132"> Prestige of Queen Victoria, as indicated by the word Pax Britannica, was to symbolize the mighty forces of the British Empire that has reigned on top of the world order in the 19th century. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0948394133638469" SCORE="0.15008533333333332" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-3-7-3-8" RANK="133"> However, conflict of countries to stimulate the national consciousness of the people, xenophobia of ethnocentric has often driven a lot of people in frenzy. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0948394133638469" SCORE="0.15008533333333332" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-3-7-3-8" RANK="134"> Sudan and Mahdi movement that happened at the end of the 19th century, century Boxer Rebellion in China at the turn of the shows the various aspects of the people's resistance. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0948394133638469" SCORE="0.15008533333333332" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-3-7-3-8" RANK="135"> These developments, as well as to shake the established authority of each region, was supposed to be to explored the way of the new order to the people. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0948394133638469" SCORE="0.15008533333333332" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-3-7-3-8" RANK="136"> The end of the 19th century, not only in Europe of industrial technology, movement to Toriireyo thought and institutions, the constitutional system, particularly linking the nation and the people by the Constitution and the Congress, as well as some reformers, young intellectuals of those countries It had come to capture widely, and the like. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0948394133638469" SCORE="0.15008533333333332" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-3-7-3-8" RANK="137"> But, in the Ottoman Empire and the Qing Dynasty and the European countries face a vast area of ​​heterogeneous China, or will of the nations and peoples of the framework is where the demand. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-S-1-1-3-3" RANK="138"> After that, the private army revolt of Hikiita generals of strife and genus citizens is one after another, Rome, etc. happen slave revolt that leaders of the Spartacus was followed by a state of confusion (one century of civil war). </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-S-1-1-3-3" RANK="139"> Among this confusion, politics went entrusted to a small number of influential politicians. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-S-1-1-3-3" RANK="140"> After the death of his adoptive of Octavianus was performed again Triumvirate and Antonius et al. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-S-1-1-3-3" RANK="141"> However, since the Antonius may have entered into with Queen Cleopatra of Ptolemaic Egypt, Octavianus is the Allies, before '31, broke in the naval battle of Actium. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-S-1-1-3-3" RANK="142"> Octavianus returning to Rome, before '27, after receiving the title of Augustus (dignity person) from the Senate, began the Empire on the facts, even while respecting the traditions of the Republic. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-S-3-9-5-5" RANK="143"> However, all by the revolution came to be determined by the central government. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-S-3-9-5-5" RANK="144"> And, the national trunk railway gathered in Paris. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-S-3-9-5-5" RANK="145"> Appearance of the current Paris was built in the era of Napoleon III. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-S-3-9-5-5" RANK="146"> On the other hand the beginning of the 19th century, London in the UK population is close to one million, had a capital of the role and size of as the center of politics and economy. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-S-3-9-5-5" RANK="147"> Capital Berlin of the same time Prussia was only population 170,000. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-S-3-9-5-5" RANK="148"> 830 000 when the German Empire establishment of 1871, more than 2 million when it comes to 1910. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-S-3-9-5-5" RANK="149"> Italy in Rome, was long the capital of Rome Papal States. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-S-3-9-5-5" RANK="150"> 1861 it became the capital of the unified Kingdom of Italy, the population was only 240,000, resulting in 1.1 million in 1931. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-S-3-9-5-5" RANK="151"> And when it came to Tokyo from Edo, the population was close to one million (1880 960 000). </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-S-3-9-5-5" RANK="152"> The population of Tokyo, which became the capital of Japan is rapidly increasing, in 1908 it became to be 2.1 million. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-S-3-9-5-5" RANK="153"> And, urban construction that sample the London and Paris have been recommended. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-S-3-9-5-5" RANK="154"> The 1870s streets of brick was built in Ginza, was born police that model the Paris Metropolitan Police Department. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-S-3-9-5-5" RANK="155"> Tokyo's population in 1962, exceeded 10 million. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-S-3-9-5-5" RANK="156"> The Tokyo was huge in a short period of time, it is a reflection of the fact that Japan has taken a strong centralized system. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-4-19-3-9" RANK="157"> After the Russian Revolution, Muslims of Central Asia, intellectuals began the independence movement from Russia become a center. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-4-19-3-9" RANK="158"> Independent school has been established the Republic and destroy the Bukhara = Khanate and Khiva = Khanate in 1920, and lost to the Soviet Red Army, in 1922 it came under the control of the Soviet regime. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-4-19-3-9" RANK="159"> Then, Kazakh through the 1930s, it has been reorganized into Uzbek, such as the Socialist Republic of each ethnic group. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-4-19-3-9" RANK="160"> Even in the Caucasus region, but the establishment of an independent government was attempted at the time of the Russian Revolution, from the fact that to determine the support of the Red Army in order to counter the Turkish troops that invaded Armenia, and entered into under the influence of the Soviet regime. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-4-19-3-9" RANK="161"> 1922, but this area has become one Republic that make up the Soviet Union as Zakafukasu federal, in '36 I was separated into ethnic another three of the Republic (Georgia, Armenia, Azerbaijan). </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-4-19-3-9" RANK="162"> However, each country was to face a minority inside. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-4-19-3-9" RANK="163"> Each republic in the Soviet Union dismantling of 1991 is independent, in also involved religious issues in the independence movement of ethnic minorities, this region has become the scene of civil war and conflict. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-01-03-7" RANK="164"> Christianity was born from Palestine under the rule of Rome in the first century. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-01-03-7" RANK="165"> Jesus was born in this land criticized the formalism of the priests and Pharisees, and preach the absolute love and neighborly love of God exerted without rich and poor of the distinction, and promised coming and the Last Judgement of the kingdom of God. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-01-03-7" RANK="166"> I began to follow his teachings and believe Christ) in Greek. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-01-03-7" RANK="167"> The Messiah &quot;which was poured the plaster&quot; in Hebrew, that is in the sense of what is special blessing from God, and Christ is in the form of the Greek. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-01-03-7" RANK="168"> But then, resurrected Jesus in between the disciples, death on the cross is born of faith and that was an act of atonement for human sin, Christianity has been established around this. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-01-03-7" RANK="169"> By shortly thereafter Apostle, such as Peter and Paul, missionary work began. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-01-03-7" RANK="170"> Paul, as the God of love also extends to the Gentiles (non-Jewish ethnicity), the missionary to the Roman Empire around, spread the Christianity also in areas other than Palestine. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-01-03-7" RANK="171"> The church is a congregation of the organization also, Asia Minor, Syria, Greece, and was built in the capital Rome. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-01-03-7" RANK="172"> As a result, until around the third century, Christianity, mainly spread around the socially vulnerable, such as slavery, women and lower citizens empire, was soon come to be seen congregation also in the upper citizen. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-01-03-7" RANK="173"> &quot;New Testament&quot; during this time is written in common language Koine Greek, it became the Holy Scripture of Christianity with the &quot;Old Testament&quot;. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-12-01-3" RANK="174"> In France, I was subjected to reactionary policies under the constitutional monarchy government to take severe restrictions election system, 10 Charles is respect for the nobility, clergy. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-12-01-3" RANK="175"> The July revolution spread to various places, Belgium is independent from the Netherlands, it became the kingdom of next '31 constitutional system. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-12-01-3" RANK="176"> Take the subject in 1830 of the French July Revolution, the goddess has to hand the three-color flag and gun. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-12-01-3" RANK="177"> Although rebellion that took place in Poland, Germany and Italy have been put down, Western Europe takes a distance from the Vienna regime, the emphasis of the Vienna regime came to be placed in Central Europe. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-12-01-3" RANK="178"> In addition, since the electoral system did not match the reality of the society after the Industrial Revolution, when the exercise of determining the election law amendment becomes violently, Whig Cabinet was realized the reform in 1832 (first round election law amendment). </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-12-01-3" RANK="179"> This constituency has been re-organized, is election qualification also expanding, including the industrial capitalist, middle class that became rich in the industrial revolution but strengthened the political clout, landed gentry to the then long political leadership also retention was. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-12-01-3" RANK="180"> British this time, advantageous free trade policies to industrial capitalists also have been realized, what is its revolutionary, result Cobden Bright et al. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-12-01-3" RANK="181"> Of the motion by the Anti-Corn Law League who participated, Corn Law is abolished in 1846 the difference was so is that. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-12-01-3" RANK="182"> In order to protect the interests of the landed gentry, the law to maintain grain prices over the high rate of customs duties on imports of foreign grain production. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-12-01-3" RANK="183"> In addition, the '49 was abolished also voyage method. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-12-01-3" RANK="184"> In addition, in 1834 the abolition of the China trade monopoly of the East India Company has been carried out. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-15-03-5" RANK="185"> After the first World War, ethnic movements, also in Southeast Asia was again spread. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-15-03-5" RANK="186"> In Indonesia, the Indonesian Communist Party has advocated independence is founded in 1920. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-15-03-5" RANK="187"> After nearly destroyed by the movement is severe crackdown, students who returned from the Netherlands came to leadership. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-15-03-5" RANK="188"> '27 Kuomintang that the party leader the Sukarno is founded in, and uplifting independent Holding Aloft movement with unity is, the next day in '28 was declared that the aim of the homeland, ethnicity, language that is unified that Indonesia. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-15-03-5" RANK="189"> But 29 leaders were arrested at the end of the year, the exercise was stagnated. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-15-03-5" RANK="190"> Party, was to expand the peasant movement, such as also to establish a rural Soviet regime while receiving a thorough crackdown. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-15-03-5" RANK="191"> In Myanmar begins ethnic movement from the 1920s, the rise of radical nationalists called Enlightenment and Takin party by the monks was seen. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-15-03-5" RANK="192"> However, the economic order has advanced greatly dependent on commodity crop production in the United States, beggar-thy-the farmers was repeated the rebellion. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-15-03-5" RANK="193"> As a result, the Philippines independent law enacted in 1934, independent preparation government was established the following year. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-15-03-5" RANK="194"> Under these circumstances, the Asian region is to rush from the end of 1941 in the Pacific War, many were supposed to greet the invasion of the Japanese army. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-4-19-5-4" RANK="195"> Great Depression, is not limited to the economic crisis in Germany, it caused a serious political crisis. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-4-19-5-4" RANK="196"> In March 1930, when the grand coalition Cabinet collapse in the resistance of the ruling Social Democratic Party against the unemployment allowance reduction, military and conservatives, organized a minority Cabinet in succession by using the presidential emergency decree. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-4-19-5-4" RANK="197"> For this reason, Congress is mere facade, Weimar democracy has been hollowed out. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-4-19-5-4" RANK="198"> In the general election of 1932 was breakthrough in first party Nazis, with the cooperation of feel a sense of crisis conservatives and industry in advance of the Communist Party, was established Hitler Cabinet on January 33. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-4-19-5-4" RANK="199"> The Nazis, in addition to was oppression of the Communist Party by using the Parliament arson incident, in March and passed a Enabling Act of 1933 which gives legislative power to the government and allowed to dissolve the political parties and organizations other than the Nazi, one in just half a year party We have established a dictatorship. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-4-19-5-4" RANK="200"> When the Hindenburg President to his death in 1934, Hitler became the president of the Third Reich and also serves as the president and the prime minister. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-4-19-5-4" RANK="201"> Nazis to overcome unemployment by construction and munitions production of autobahn (motorway) embarked on the economic system building toward war by the &quot;four-year plan&quot; from '36. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-4-19-5-4" RANK="202"> It has been called a Gypsy, because it contains discriminatory nuances, this self-proclaimed are used at present. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-4-19-5-4" RANK="203"> Therefore, there were numerous persons who exile in Einstein and Thomas Mann = such as academics and cultural figures. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-3-10-1-5" RANK="204"> East Asia from the late 1980s through the 1990s the beginning, while maintaining the divided structure that characterizes the post-war of the Cold War period, the economic development are taken policy which gives priority, and the movement that give priority to political reform in the Soviet Union It had been without a marked contrast. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-3-10-1-5" RANK="205"> South Korea called the Asian NIES through the 1970s, Hong Kong, Taiwan, remarkable economic development was seen in Singapore. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-3-10-1-5" RANK="206"> 80s, China, based on actively promoting economic reform and openness policy in Kodaira, worked on four of modernization (modernization) policy, such as science and technology. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-3-10-1-5" RANK="207"> But rapid social change, caused, such as Tiananmen Square incident of June 89. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-3-10-1-5" RANK="208"> When the Cold War to end, China will avoid isolation in the international community while strengthening the leadership in the political by the Communist Party, we have built a new friendly relations with Russia. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-3-10-1-5" RANK="209"> In 2001, the Shanghai Cooperation Organization, was tied with Russia and Kazakhstan, such as six countries. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-3-10-1-5" RANK="210"> Along with the ASEAN + 3 (China, South Korea and Japan), as being oriented towards the stabilization of the regional areas across the north and south, China trends have been noted. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-3-10-1-5" RANK="211"> China is to introduce a socialist market economy in economic, but has made remarkable economic development, are expanding gap between the rich and the poor in the country. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-3-10-1-5" RANK="212"> Also in Hong Kong in 1997 from Britain, in 1999 the return of Macau from Portugal, the one country, two systems that have been applied here, it is proposed as a unified system with Taiwan. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-3-10-1-5" RANK="213"> In Taiwan, under lasted KMT domination after World War II, Lee Teng-hui was appointed President in '88 is embarked on democratization, in the presidential election of 2000 for the first time established the Democratic Progressive Party administration. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-3-10-1-5" RANK="214"> Dae-Jung Kim, who took office in South Korea president in 1998, it was to improve relations with North Korea, in 2000 was realized for the first time of the inter-Korean summit after divided at between the general secretary of North Korea Kim Jong Il. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-3-10-1-5" RANK="215"> North Korea, which are pursuing their own diplomacy to clue the nuclear issue, according to the six-party talks to be an intermediary in China, has also been promoted discussions among the international framework. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-2-9-1-1" RANK="216"> About 50 years after the fall of the Tang, 5 dynasties of Zhou after post Kang Jin after the rear beam and rear tow, is alternated North China (five generations), the local 10 much of the country has been the rise and fall (ten countries). </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-2-9-1-1" RANK="217"> Era of the Five Dynasties and Ten Kingdoms is a major period of change in the society, on behalf of the noble lineage aristocracy since the Six Dynasties era, moderation use or warlords becomes jiedushi, emerging landlord layer that connects and its warrior has extended the force. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-2-9-1-1" RANK="218"> 5 of the dynasty, rear Tang, rear Jin, was built a post-Han, it was a moderate use of Turkic origin. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-2-9-1-1" RANK="219"> Each administration is singing the inheritance of the Tang empire, especially in the Later Shu and rear Tang, civilization of the Tang continued to develop. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-2-9-1-1" RANK="220"> Improvements and of the papermaking process, the development of woodblock printing technology, books of most came to be published. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-2-9-1-1" RANK="221"> In 960 years, per rear periphery of the warlord Chao K'uang-yin (King Taejo) is throne, built the Song Dynasty (Northern Song Dynasty), the opening is a goods distribution center of the hub of the Grand Canal (Henan) Place the capital, nearly reunification nationwide did. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-2-9-1-1" RANK="222"> Taejo is to concentrate power in the emperor and took the helm of moderation used, was politics Bunji principle that values ​​the literati bureaucrats were selected by the imperial examination. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-2-9-1-1" RANK="223"> In emerging landlord layer became a born womb of this literary bureaucracy (tide door), honor and benefit is given to the house that issued the bureaucracy (Kant). </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-2-9-1-1" RANK="224"> The Song Dynasty, the national income due to monopoly, such as tea, salt, sake has increased dramatically, the amount was enough to comparable to the tax revenue by both tax law. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-2-9-1-1" RANK="225"> Sixth Daikamimune is to appoint Wang Anshi, protection of land-own farmer and small merchants, securing financial resources, went reform of wealth and military strength to strengthen the national defense force (the new law). </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-2-9-1-1" RANK="226"> This is finances for the better, in the opposite of Sima glow of conservative, soon the new law is aborted, the political was confused by the faction of the new law Party and the old law party. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-17-03-3" RANK="227"> Many seen development dictatorship and military regime, or long-term administration in developing countries, to reduce the number and the 1980s, it has been a multi-party system and democracy spread. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-17-03-3" RANK="228"> In Asia, it is committed to the development of export industry, South Korean President Park was cracking down anti-government activity has been assassinated in 1979, the foundation of the military who crackdown anti-government pro-democracy movement in Gwangju in '80, and Chun Doo Hwan, Roh Tae-woo and military personnel born president was followed. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-17-03-3" RANK="229"> In the 92 year-end election, the Kim Young Sam became a non-military president for the first time in '32, and then punish the two former President at stake, such as the Kwangju incident, served in the fixing of civilian rule. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-17-03-3" RANK="230"> Dae-Jung Kim becomes president from '98, to promote democracy and the Korean Peninsula of detente, in 2002 Roh Moo-hyun was elected president. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-17-03-3" RANK="231"> Export industry is growing, also wearing a economic strength Taiwan, the domestic has been followed by a one-party rule of the Kuomintang under martial law. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-17-03-3" RANK="232"> However, martial law in 1987 is released, Lee Teng-hui was appointed to the President from '88 was served to democracy promotion. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-17-03-3" RANK="233"> In the 2000 presidential election, Chen Shui-bian was elected that does not belong only to the KMT. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-17-03-3" RANK="234"> In addition, President Marcos of the Philippines, which was in power since 1965, being chased by a popular movement that unauthorized protest of the '86 election, then is followed by a regime by democratic elections. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-17-03-3" RANK="235"> In India, accounting for administration of post-war National Congress faction mainstream, during this time, and repeat the collision On such attribution of Kashmir in between with Pakistan, in 1971 was independent East Pakistan as Bangladesh. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-17-03-3" RANK="236"> However, '84 Prime Minister Indira = Gandhi, the '91 is assassinated Rajiv Gandhi = eldest son who succeeded After, national Congress away from the regime. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-17-03-3" RANK="237"> In 1998, Pakistan also conducted a nuclear test against the Indian nuclear test, became the new nuclear powers. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-17-03-3" RANK="238"> Even in many was Latin America of dictatorship, in 1973, withdrew shortly defeated in referendum the Chilean Allende socialist regime in the Pinochet military regime 88 years was defeated in the coup, challenged the Falklands war in 1982 the United Kingdom Argentina's military regime also been defeated in war, it was shifted to civilian rule. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-17-03-3" RANK="239"> Central America Nicaragua of Somoza long-term dictatorship overthrown in '79 left-wing guerrillas, '90, could centrist government by election. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-17-03-3" RANK="240"> In Africa, Caucasian minority dominated regime has disappeared. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-17-03-3" RANK="241"> South Africa after the Second World War, was introduced the apartheid policy of extremely discriminate against blacks is a majority, was orphaned in response to the economic sanctions of the protest and the United Nations of the African National Congress. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-17-03-3" RANK="242"> In the late 1980s, de Klerk government review the apartheid entirely, abolished the '91 discrimination laws, it was also observed equality suffrage in '94. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-17-03-3" RANK="243"> South African President Mandela (right) in 1994, he was appointed to the results of the presidential election. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-17-03-3" RANK="244"> Caucasian of de Klerk Vice President left had promoted reconciliation with black. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-17-03-3" RANK="245"> Both were both received the previous year Nobel Peace Prize. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-17-03-3" RANK="246"> The results of the election, African National Congress is won the majority was elected president black Mandela, it is then also selected a black president. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-17-03-3" RANK="247"> South African President Mandela (right) in 1994, he was appointed to the results of the presidential election. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-17-03-3" RANK="248"> Caucasian of de Klerk Vice President left had promoted reconciliation with black. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-17-03-3" RANK="249"> Both were both received the previous year Nobel Peace Prize. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-12-01-2" RANK="250"> French Revolution and liberalism and nationalism woke up under the Napoleonic domination (nationalist) caused a variety of rebellious movement against the Vienna regime. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-12-01-2" RANK="251"> Students' Union Bull Shen shaft and Italian anti-government movement of the secret society of the Carbonari Germany, but has occurred, such as a constitutional revolution of Spain, both have been put down. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-12-01-2" RANK="252"> Austria is a multi-ethnic nation, but he was from the standpoint of conservatism in its suppression, the United Kingdom in early 1820 began to show the attitude to leave the Vienna regime. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-12-01-2" RANK="253"> In Latin America, as triggered by the resistance movement by Tusan = Ruvu~eru tulle, it becomes black republic independent French territory Haiti in 1804, in the 1810's fingerprint = Bolivar in the northern part of South America, Saint-Martin is independence movement in the south and teaching, and was achieved independence beginning Mexico also uprising of Hidalgo. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-12-01-2" RANK="254"> Haiti became the end of the 15th century the Spanish, but I was changed in the 17th century the end of French colonial. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-12-01-2" RANK="255"> Independence of Latin America These movements, which was a mainly a Kurioryo layer is a white colonial-born, dominated the squire of Kurioryo was followed in the Republic was born after independence from Spain. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-12-01-2" RANK="256"> On the other hand Brazil, prince of Portugal became an independent empire (in 1889 after the Republic) for the throne. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-12-01-2" RANK="257"> However, the President of the United States Monroe cast Americas and Europe of mutual non-interference in the Monroe State of the Union of 1823, because it was recognized the independence of countries in the United Kingdom Foreign Minister Canning also aimed at the development of the Latin America market, Metternich interference to these independence movement it was not able to. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-12-01-2" RANK="258"> December 1825 In Russia, when Nikolai I's coronation, but young officer of noble has caused a turbulent of Decembrists (December party members) seeking liberal reform, and was immediately put down. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-15-02-3" RANK="259"> Britain and France after the war, but increased the overseas territories, it does not recover from the economic blow received by the war, suffered the economic recession. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-15-02-3" RANK="260"> After the war, per the second party of the status of second only to Labor Party Conservative Party on behalf of the Liberal Party, in 1924 he organized a coalition government with the Labour Party leader McDonald's Liberal Party. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-15-02-3" RANK="261"> This regime was short-lived, the Labour Party in the election of '29 will be the first time first party, McDonald's has once again came to power. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-15-02-3" RANK="262"> Ireland, in 1922, became a self-governing dominion except the northern part of Ulster as the Irish Free State. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-15-02-3" RANK="263"> However, Ireland independent faction abolished the loyalty declaration to the crown in '37, it has established its own constitution, has left virtually federal ale as a country. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-15-02-3" RANK="264"> France Land, became the battlefield was also afraid of the powers of Germany after World War II. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-15-02-3" RANK="265"> Therefore France, obligations of the Treaty of Versailles imposed on Germany, in particular demanding a compensation payment, at the time of the Poincare right-wing Cabinet, was forced to rule occupation because of payment defaults. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-15-02-3" RANK="266"> However, versus the German hard-line diplomacy fails bathed the international criticism, in 1924 left-wing coalition government appeared. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-15-02-3" RANK="267"> Briand became the foreign minister in 25 years to strive to reconciliation with Germany, it has contributed to international cooperation. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-15-02-3" RANK="268"> In Germany, although the Communist Party from revolutionary propulsion force and the Social Democratic Party in Germany has been conflict immediately after the war, the Social Democratic Party by connecting with conservatives such as the military, I held down the Communist Party beginning in 1919. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-15-02-3" RANK="269"> German Communist Party, especially in the Spartacus faction Social Democratic Party the most left-wing was organized under the banner of the anti-war, was formed after the war. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-15-02-3" RANK="270"> Leader Rosa = Luxembourg (1870-1919) and Karl Liebknecht = (1871-1919), was murdered in '19 beginning. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-15-02-3" RANK="271"> In the National Assembly, which was held in Weimar, Ebert of the Social Democratic Party is elected president, democratic Constitution (Weimar Constitution) has been established, made the foundation of the Republic (Weimar Republic). </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-15-02-3" RANK="272"> However, compensation payments, such as by anti-Republic activities by imperial faction and the right wing, economic and political situation was not stable. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-15-02-3" RANK="273"> In particular, the French rules occupation of 1923 and reduced productivity due to the resistance in disobedience movement, progress in severe inflation. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-15-02-3" RANK="274"> Old bill in the currency inflation currency inflation in Germany is almost worthless, you can be in children's toys instead of the usual, were or are used as wallpaper. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-15-02-3" RANK="275"> The same year summer, Stresemann became the prime minister is to overcome the inflation by issuing the rentenmark, with a successful mitigation and capital introduction of compensation payments in cooperation with the United States, and re-built the economy, was to promote international cooperation diplomacy. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-15-02-3" RANK="276"> In response proposal of experts of international business community (the Dawes Plan), the Allies to reduce the time being the compensation payments of Germany, it decided the German economic recovery by the United States capital. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-15-02-3" RANK="277"> However, Nazi Germany = denied the compensation itself. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-15-02-3" RANK="278"> International circulation of capital after the Dawes Plan established Stresemann, who served as foreign minister until 1929 to realize the international Federation, we tried the recovery of the international status of Germany. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-15-02-3" RANK="279"> If during this time Ebert died in 1925, it was the Army Chief of the General Staff of the First World War the late Hindenburg was elected president (in office 1925-34). </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-3-8-2-8" RANK="280"> The United States during the war, had carried out a huge amount of financial assistance to the Allies, even as can be seen in the Dawes Plan of 1924 after the war, was carried out a loan of large amounts of private capital for the German economic recovery. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-3-8-2-8" RANK="281"> German performing economic reconstruction on the basis of the money, which is expected to carry out the payment of compensation. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-3-8-2-8" RANK="282"> And for the UK and France, the reparations from Germany was also the source of funding debt repayment to the United States. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-3-8-2-8" RANK="283"> Post-war European economy even I said that was supported by the United States. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-3-8-2-8" RANK="284"> Also in Latin America, after the war, after the forces such as Britain and France is retracted, the United States strengthened the influence politics, in the economy on both sides, in the 1920s in Central America, the Caribbean became a &quot;sphere of influence&quot; of the United States. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-09-04-4" RANK="285"> France is a result of the hundred years war, and almost wiped out the British national, has been on the road to the centralized state. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-09-04-4" RANK="286"> A number of new Muslims murder in 1572 in the massacre Huguenot war of sambal Barthelemy. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-09-04-4" RANK="287"> because this was also seen foreign forces intervention, in France, such as Bodin, it went Hitobitogafue to try to prioritize national unity than the religious problem. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-09-04-4" RANK="288"> Bourbon Henri IV is to convert and take the throne from Protestantism to Roman catholicism, giving a significant religious freedom in Huguenot in 1598 in Nantes the king decree (edict), it was Owarase the Huguenot war. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-09-04-4" RANK="289"> In this way, the unity of France as the nation is maintained. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-09-04-4" RANK="290"> France has stayed in the Roman catholicism countries, the idea that claims the independence of the French church to papacy has become stronger. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-09-04-4" RANK="291"> Henri 4 world begins Bourbon morning under, France celebrated its heyday of the absolute monarchy. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-09-04-4" RANK="292"> Louis XIII of vizier Richelieu, do not open the three Group Hold the resisting nobility and Huguenot to kingship, in terms of international politics, three decades during the war, lottery the emperor power of the Habsburgs to stand on the side of the Protestant forces It served To this. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-09-04-4" RANK="293"> After the coronation of the childhood of Louis XIV, in 1648, but the High Court and the aristocracy has caused revolt (the Fronde), policy of kingship strengthening by Chancellor Mazarin was continued. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-4-20-3-5" RANK="294"> In 1969 the New York suburb of Woodstock, a concert of rock and folk songs was held under the banner of the Vietnam anti-war. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-S-4-12-5-10" RANK="295"> Since its founding, there is the center of American politics and culture in the eastern part, production of the movie was done in New York and Chicago. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-S-4-12-5-10" RANK="296"> But in 1908, one of the filmmakers I was shooting a movie in Los Angeles suburb of Hollywood facing the west coast. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-S-4-12-5-10" RANK="297"> Eventually most advanced to the Hollywood of the American film company, around 1915, here was a center of filmmaking. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-S-4-12-5-10" RANK="298"> 300 days of the year 1 climatic conditions that the skies had been directed to filmmaking. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-S-4-12-5-10" RANK="299"> The first was in the movie kingdom is France, First World War just before, the movie was screened in the world 90. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-S-4-12-5-10" RANK="300"> % Was made in France. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-S-4-12-5-10" RANK="301"> However, France of the country in the First World War was devastated, the film industry was also hit. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-S-4-12-5-10" RANK="302"> American movie is increased development in the meantime, that 85% of the movie was screened in the world in 1919 was made in America. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-S-4-12-5-10" RANK="303"> 1920s mid, American movies that are produced in Hollywood, it becomes to account for 90 percent of the world's film market, it has become the automobile, iron and steel, petroleum, to one of America's five largest industry with canned. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-S-4-12-5-10" RANK="304"> The movie to be made in the United States, there were some of the features. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-S-4-12-5-10" RANK="305"> One is the speed of movement and the magnitude of the Among the screen. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-S-4-12-5-10" RANK="306"> Depiction of a person riding a horse among the broad earth goes missing ran had utilizing well the American natural environment. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-S-4-12-5-10" RANK="307"> In addition, American movie was simple and Wakariyasuka~tsu. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-S-4-12-5-10" RANK="308"> And American movies provided a abandon luxurious spectacle by large funds. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-S-4-12-5-10" RANK="309"> The audience to look at the American movie, was able to experience the luxury, such as temporarily dream. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-S-4-12-5-10" RANK="310"> In the movie, because it was possible impossible trick shooting on the stage of the theater, initially's slapstick comedy it is gaining in popularity. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-S-4-12-5-10" RANK="311"> Over the 1930s from the 1920s, when the movie with a voice to spread, dance movies and musical movie he was born. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-S-4-12-5-10" RANK="312"> Of color film technology is established in the 1930s, Hollywood movies more enjoyable, it became a luxury. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-S-4-12-5-10" RANK="313"> The 1950s, the influence of Hollywood became small, American film was never of abating. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-S-4-12-5-10" RANK="314"> Time of the Cold War, American film that depicts the socialist countries as bad has been made many. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-S-4-12-5-10" RANK="315"> A movie with such a political trend, fun as entertaining movie, and collected a lot of fans all over the world. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-1-2-1-5" RANK="316"> Therefore, the original of the calendar were often lunar calendar due to the periodic phases of the moon. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-1-2-1-5" RANK="317"> In Rome, had lunisolar calendar is used for a long time, there is also negligence of priests group that controls the calendar, large deviation occurs over the years. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-1-2-1-5" RANK="318"> In order to rectify this absurd, Caesar '45 ago, we embarked on a reform to correct the deviation of the season and calendar, adopted the solar calendar by the Alexandria system. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-1-2-1-5" RANK="319"> By law, normal year was 365 days, in one leap year in four years, it was 366 days by adding a day in February. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-1-2-1-5" RANK="320"> The leap day at the end of February is placed, in the Roman calendar, because now of March falls Martius of the month (English name March) was the beginning of the year. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-1-2-1-5" RANK="321"> Calendar named after the clan name of Julius Caesar this is, while being subjected to some modifications by the Gregorian calendar in the 16th century, which extends to today. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-3-8-3-1" RANK="322"> 1929, stock prices was a big crash in the stock exchanges of New York. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-3-8-3-1" RANK="323"> Since the war, the United States, which had become the center of the world of finance, Europe of gold had been flown by the wartime debt and interest payments. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-3-8-3-1" RANK="324"> However, a large imbalance has been created in the world economy. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-3-8-3-1" RANK="325"> The flow of capital procurement stagnant, Depression spread to the world, in the early 1930s production and trade has decreased in countries, was brought serious recession to increase unemployment. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-16-02-3" RANK="326"> After the war, in the United States, against the background of the self-confidence of the military and economic power of the country, has increased claimed to be that we should be teaching the international community against the Soviet Union. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-16-02-3" RANK="327"> In 1947 in Japan, Taft-Hartley Act to restrict the trade union activities on behalf of the Wagner Act was enacted, and frustration is intensified by prolonged atomic bomb possession and the Korean War of the Soviet Union, pursue leftist movement and communist ideology movement to (&quot;Red Scare&quot;) appeared. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-16-02-3" RANK="328"> Republican Senator McCarthy (1909-57) is, because stood at the beginning of the idea pursue activities of intellectuals and civil servants, this trend was also called McCarthyism. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-16-02-3" RANK="329"> Eisenhower Republican was elected in the 1952 presidential election, while maintaining the framework of the Cold War, and to terminate the Korean War, tried to Susumeyo a dialogue with the Soviet Union. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-16-02-3" RANK="330"> Marshall = Western European countries of the economic recovery that has received the assistance of the plan is remarkable, was followed by a high economic growth rate 1950-70 20 years years. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-16-02-3" RANK="331"> The average economic growth rate of developed countries (%) economic growth rate of the 1950-70's, it found to be those who stand out among the 20 century. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-16-02-3" RANK="332"> In Western Europe sandwiched between the US and the Soviet Union, in order to revive the economy and standing in the reflection of the two world wars, to manage jointly the energy resources and industrial resources, appeared initiative to try to prevent a conflict of mutual . </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-16-02-3" RANK="333"> 1952, at the suggestion of the French Foreign Minister Schuman (Schuman = plan), France and West Germany, the Benelux countries and Italy was inaugurated European Coal and Steel Community body (ECSC). </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-16-02-3" RANK="334"> This movement, is prompted to conflict with the Soviet Union socialist bloc, the European Economic Community in '58 (EEC), and developed it into the establishment of the European Atomic Energy Community (EURATOM), mutual reduction of tariffs, joint commercial and agricultural policy, the liberalization of capital and labor movement was implemented. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-16-02-3" RANK="335"> In '67, three communities merged European Community (EC) next, the foundation of Western European integration was made. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-16-02-3" RANK="336"> 1958 In France, the fourth Republic falls down without being able to resolve the Algerian independence problem, was changed to the fifth Republic. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-16-02-3" RANK="337"> De-goal became the President recognized the independence of Algeria, was the fourth nuclear power in France. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-16-02-3" RANK="338"> Further approved a 64 year country, in '66, such as refuse military cooperation to NATO, insisted its own position in between the United States and the Soviet Union. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-16-02-3" RANK="339"> West Germany has achieved economic growth that has been called under the Adenauer &quot;miracle&quot;. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-16-02-3" RANK="340"> '66 Of the results of the election, a large coalition government is established by adding the Social Democratic Party to such as the Christian Democratic Union. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-16-02-3" RANK="341"> Britain does not participate in the EEC, it was against it have formed the Free Trade Association (EFTA) 1960 年 Europe. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-16-02-3" RANK="342"> When the Wilson Cabinet is satisfied with victory Labor Party in the '64 election, and decided to withdrawal from the Suez Ito, also running the pound devaluation from the economic crisis. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-16-02-3" RANK="343"> Japan after the outbreak of the Korean War, received pull the goods supply to the United Nations Army (Korea special demand), was dramatically develop the industrial production. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-16-02-3" RANK="344"> 1955 to be satisfied Liberal Democratic Party, we were able regime taking power over the subsequent long-term. ' </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-16-02-3" RANK="345"> 56, Restored diplomatic relations with the Soviet Union, also in the same year by a member to the United Nations, was a return to the international community. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-16-02-3" RANK="346"> 1960 (1960) is revised US Treaty of Mutual Cooperation and Security day a year, but the US between the ties of the day has been strengthened, violent confrontation occurred Concerning revision in Japan. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-16-02-3" RANK="347"> In fart the high economic growth period of the 1960s, Japan became a member of the industrialized countries. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-16-02-3" RANK="348"> The average economic growth rate of developed countries (%) economic growth rate of the 1950-70's, it found to be those who stand out among the 20 century. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-16-02-3" RANK="349"> It should be noted that, in 1965, Japan signed a Korea and NichiKan basic treaty, was realized the normalization of diplomatic relations. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-16-02-3" RANK="350"> At the end of the 1960s, in France, such as Western Europe and developed countries West Germany Japan, and the post-war political and social system, the student movement and the labor movement that has criticized the deviation between the Social Transformation by economic growth spread. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-16-02-3" RANK="351"> The '69 French-de-Gaulle is deposed, and government is satisfied that the prime minister blunt after the war the first time the Social Democrats in West Germany, began a review of post-war politics. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-15-02-2" RANK="352"> Ottoman Empire to recover the part of the territory is under Mustafa Kemal =, a Greek fighting, signed a renewed Lausanne Treaty the Sevres treaty. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-15-02-2" RANK="353"> Poland was invaded in 1920 Russia (Poland = Soviet war), give a part of Belarus and Ukraine, Italy also cause Yugoslavia and the border dispute, won the Fiume. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-15-02-2" RANK="354"> Above all, confrontation of France and Germany over the compensation payments, France in 1923 and Belgium has deteriorated enough to occupy the Ruhr area of ​​Germany. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-15-02-2" RANK="355"> However, spreads the momentum after the 1924 international cooperation, in the Locarno Treaty of '25 determines the status quo and the mutual security of the border with Germany and Western European countries, Germany has joined the League of Nations the following year. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-15-02-2" RANK="356"> In general term for a series of treaty group that has been agreed at a meeting in Switzerland of Locarno, in addition to maintaining the status quo of the German western border, Rhineland demilitarization, are the main contents of resolution by arbitration of international disputes. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-15-02-2" RANK="357"> 1928, at the proposal of France Briand Foreign Minister and the United States of Kellogg Secretary of State, signed by the bye Treaty (Briand-Kellogg Treaty) of 15 countries (later 63 countries), is that it does not resort to war as a means of settling international disputes It is sworn. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-15-02-2" RANK="358"> Owned tonnage ratio, in the United States, the United Kingdom, Japan, was approximately 10, 10 and 7. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-15-04-3" RANK="359"> Although Japan has developed the industry in the wartime economy of the first World War, 1923 will upset trade from (Taisho 12) years time, financial crisis occurs in the 27 (1927) year, further the Great Depression It was multiplied by the internal and placed. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-15-04-3" RANK="360"> Economy frequently labor dispute confused, social unrest also spread. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-15-04-3" RANK="361"> September 1931, the Japanese Kwantung Army Tohoku region (in Japan at the time had &quot;Manchuria&quot; toyon) China to blow up the railway in Yanagijo lake, which is causing the military action as a pretext, in the Tohoku region It occupied the majority. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-15-04-3" RANK="362"> This is the Manchurian Incident, the military in order to divert the attention of the international community, to 32 (1932) year caused the Shanghai Incident. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-15-04-3" RANK="363"> Military action of Japan is internationally criticism, the International Federation also decided to dispatch of Lytton investigation team in the appeal of China. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-15-04-3" RANK="364"> Since Kwantung Army to create a fait accompli, March 32, the Qing Dynasty last emperor Pu Yi is laid to consul (later Emperor), it was founded the Manchuria country. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-15-04-3" RANK="365"> Establishment of Manchukuo in September 1932, Japan-Manchukuo Protocol signed commemorative photo after expression. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-15-04-3" RANK="366"> Leadership of the are backward Kwantung Army. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-15-04-3" RANK="367"> Investigation team rejected the claims of Japan that military action is the activation of the right of self-defense, because the Federation was also support it, Japan 33 (1933) in March, was notified of the League of Nations withdrawal. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-15-04-3" RANK="368"> Invasion of Japan spans the then heat the river district, the temporary is approaching in Beijing beyond the Great Wall, began to aim the dominant North China. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-15-04-3" RANK="369"> The Japanese army in 1935, and invaded the Inner Mongolia, North China in the name of Anti-Comintern, was established the East Hebei Autonomous Council, which was separated from the national government in Hebei east (1935-38). </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-15-04-3" RANK="370"> Some of the military personnel in parallel with this cause terrorism and coup incident, tried to Tsuyomeyo influence in the country. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-15-04-3" RANK="371"> 1932 of May 15th Incident, and the like. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-15-04-3" RANK="372"> 36 (1936) year of 2.26 incident. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-15-04-3" RANK="373"> 1934, Communist forces of Ruijin, in response to the national government forces attack, ran the Long March, which aims to Shaanxi-Gansu Province hinterland around the Yan'an. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-15-04-3" RANK="374"> In this process, it increased the leadership of Mao Zedong in the Communist Party. ' </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-15-04-3" RANK="375"> 35, The national government was unified currency in the assistance of the United Kingdom, United States. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-15-04-3" RANK="376"> Until the currency of China is basically a silver, bill because that was issued by each bank, currency value and Spoken range was unstable. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-15-04-3" RANK="377"> National government prohibits the silver, the banknotes issued by the four major banks that were linked to the £ defined as legal tender (Honusa), was to promote the financial unity. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-15-04-3" RANK="378"> This weakened the warlords of the power of the region, the direction of domestic unity was further progress. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-15-04-3" RANK="379"> Anti-Japanese movement in China to machine the Manchurian Incident is spread throughout the country, in August 1935, Chinese Communist Party issues an eight-one declaration, called for a civil war stop and ethnic united front formed. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-15-04-3" RANK="380"> The Zhang Xueliang who was in Xian to see this situation, it captures the Chiang Kai-shek who came to encourage the Communist Party of Thailand attack, it was persuaded anti-Japanese and civil war stop (Xi'an Incident). </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-15-04-3" RANK="381"> Chiang Kai-shek to accept this, then, Kokkyo approached again. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-15-04-3" RANK="382"> Japan's military in the wake of the Marco Polo Bridge Incident of July 1937, an enlarged view of the military action. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-15-04-3" RANK="383"> Second Kokkyo Cooperation same year in September is established in China, Japan and China has entered the overall state of war (day during the war). </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-15-04-3" RANK="384"> China is subject to the United States, England and Soviet aid, Wuhan government from Nanjing, further continued to die resistance transferred to Chongqing outback. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-15-04-3" RANK="385"> 1940, Japan set a Toa new order construction, against the Chongqing government, but was allowed to establish a pro-Japanese regime of Hiroshicho inscription in Nanjing, prospects and are not situation resolved give a popular support China did not appear It was. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-2-4-2-8" RANK="386"> In the Balkans, the influence of the French Revolution and the Napoleonic Wars, also domestic developments also observed, increased ethnic awareness of various ethnic groups. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-2-4-2-8" RANK="387"> Especially Greeks, engaged in commercial activity has its own privileges, had keep the force. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-2-4-2-8" RANK="388"> It became the foundation of the movement to independence. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-2-4-2-8" RANK="389"> Resistance to the Ottoman Empire of the various ethnic groups, has evolved to gradually independence movement. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-2-4-2-8" RANK="390"> 1804, rebellion of Serbs began first. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-2-4-2-8" RANK="391"> Eventually in 1821, it was Kira is cover for gun barrel of the independence war in Greece. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-2-4-2-8" RANK="392"> This war initially, involving also the Wallachia and Moldova. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-2-4-2-8" RANK="393"> for the suppression of the war prolonged, but Egyptian forces of Muhammad Ali has troops, whereas Russia, the United Kingdom, France intervened, Greek independence was officially recognized in 1830. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-2-4-2-8" RANK="394"> In the same year, Serbia also complete autonomy was observed. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-2-4-2-8" RANK="395"> On the other hand Wallachia and Moldova, unification was observed in 1861 after the Crimean War, it became the Romanian principality. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-2-4-2-8" RANK="396"> European war has also spread to various regions ranging from the Indian Ocean to Japanese waters. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-S-1-1-3-10" RANK="397"> Cleopatra, Ptolemy the Greek system morning was born as Egyptian royal family of second daughter. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-S-1-1-3-10" RANK="398"> At the time, other Hellenistic countries has already been conquered by Rome, it was while slipped to last Moments Egypt also gradually Rome of the dependent countries. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-S-1-1-3-10" RANK="399"> Married with his brother according to the old habits of Egypt at the age of 17 after the death of his father, was attached to the throne jointly. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-S-1-1-3-10" RANK="400"> However, servants of Ototo-o was revolted for fear the ambition of her alone reign. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-S-1-1-3-10" RANK="401"> Cleopatra fled from Egypt, but sake of comeback in Syria, this time, the Rome of the influential person Caesar I arrived in Alexandria owed the political opponents. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-S-1-1-3-10" RANK="402"> Cleopatra secretly met with Caesar, was restored to the throne and won his aid and love at the same time. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-S-1-1-3-10" RANK="403"> In addition after the death of Caesar, and captured the hearts of Antonius became the influential person of east world in its military commander, was married to him. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-3-9-1-12" RANK="404"> Under the Communist Party of the dictatorship, the means of production are nationalized, thought control has been carried out thoroughly. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-3-9-1-12" RANK="405"> Education, publishing and cultural activities is also subject to control, freedom of speech was restricted. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-3-9-1-12" RANK="406"> It is impossible to openly criticize the state, resisting person in control of the Communist Party was persecuted. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-3-9-1-12" RANK="407"> On the other hand, education and health care are free of, social welfare, which was enriched by the State has been carried out. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-3-9-1-12" RANK="408"> Communist Party of Eastern Europe before the war, eradication of economic exploitation, set a elimination of social equality of realization and ethnic discrimination, to some extent attract the farmers and workers, in the war to become the center of the resistance movement, its own We were aiming to reform. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-3-9-1-12" RANK="409"> However, after the war, when the East-West confrontation deepens uniqueness of the countries deprived, it was supposed to be socialism of the Soviet Union type is gradually introduced. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-3-17-2-11" RANK="410"> In the United States, the southern and northern part of the interest is at odds with the development of the vast western development. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-3-17-2-11" RANK="411"> In the south it is mainly cultivated cotton in large plantations of slavery, because the system to export to the United Kingdom was the development of the cotton industry had been taken, southern states to determine the survival of free trade and slavery. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-3-17-2-11" RANK="412"> On the other hand, the northern advanced industrialized on the opposition of the United Kingdom, seeking the unification of trade protection and domestic market, the western farmers also seeking mutual market of the northern part of the industry, began to conflict with the South. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-3-17-2-11" RANK="413"> 1854, Kansas, in the Nebraska both quasi-state, it will be left as to whether or not a slave state in the selection of residents, Missouri agreement was denied. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-3-17-2-11" RANK="414"> In addition, this time Mrs. Stowe (1811-96) is represents the &quot;Uncle = Tom's Cabin&quot;, was opposed to slavery. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-3-17-2-11" RANK="415"> The rebound was southern states is disengaged from the United States and formed the next '61 Confederate States of America, the Civil War began here. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-3-17-2-11" RANK="416"> Northern Army in '65, won by occupying the southern part of the capital of Richmond. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-3-17-2-11" RANK="417"> Although slaves were freed in the southern reconstruction by the northern-led state that discrimination in the legal and social African Americans as blacks, were still alive. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-3-17-2-11" RANK="418"> Remaining strong sense of discrimination around the southern secret society Ku Klux = = clan which claims the superiority of whites (KKK) was organized. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-3-17-2-11" RANK="419"> Industrial development with a focus on the north is remarkable, also breakthrough agriculture by western development, the first transcontinental railroad was completed in 1869, it was strengthened ties of the domestic market. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-3-17-2-11" RANK="420"> 19th century in the second half also involved immigrants from new Eastern Europe and Southern Europe, mass immigration from Europe has supported the United States economy. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-3-17-2-11" RANK="421"> The 1890s disappearance of the frontier is said, rapid economic growth and gave birth to social trend called &quot;Bling era&quot;. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-3-17-2-11" RANK="422"> However, the movement of such limitation of prejudice and Asian immigrants to the new immigrants from Eastern Europe occurs, labor movement and peasant movement for social conflict, such as the gap between the rich and the poor was also intensified was uplifting. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-3-17-2-11" RANK="423"> The 1886 American Federation of Labor (AFL) is, the 1905 alliance world industrial workers (IWW) was formed. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-3-17-2-11" RANK="424"> The end of the 19th century is enacted Sherman (antitrust) law, but in the early 20th century was taken policy called &quot;progressive&quot;, it was not possible to suppress the formation of a giant. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-3-17-2-11" RANK="425"> By hosting the Pan-American Conference in 1889, the United States, which strengthened the influence of the Latin America, changed the policy from traditional isolationism, in the 1990s strengthened overseas. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-3-17-2-11" RANK="426"> McKinley Presidential Republican, launch a war in Spain in 1998 (USA-Spain war), it laid the Caribbean and scaffolding foray into the Pacific Ocean, followed by Theodore = Roosevelt president of the Republican Party as well, an aggressive Caribbean policy deployment was. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-16-03-1" RANK="427"> In between the Asian and African countries, confrontation of East and West both sides are brought to Asia and Africa, to see a situation where the Korean War and the Indochina war is resolved in the United States and the Soviet Union-led, to strengthen the independence, to try to form a third force tide that it is assumed that was born. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-16-03-1" RANK="428"> In addition, without involving Asia, Africa and Latin American countries in the US-Soviet confrontation, to put together in a position of active neutrality as third world, such as the 1961 Yugoslavia interrogation first Kaihi the participating 25 countries in Belgrade allies summit meeting was held. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-16-03-1" RANK="429"> In Egypt, in 1952, Naguib-Nasser et al., Led officer delegation defeat the monarchy, was established well in '53 Republic (Egypt revolution). </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-16-03-1" RANK="430"> Shortly When Nasser becomes president, and cast a positive policy of neutrality, to take a direction to approach the socialist countries, it was aimed at the construction of the Aswan = High Dam in order to promote the domestic modernization. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-16-03-1" RANK="431"> UK, the United States in opposition to diplomatic posture of the nacelle, has stopped economic aid to Egypt. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-16-03-1" RANK="432"> Nasser in 1956, declared the nationalization of the Suez Canal in order to obtain the dam construction funds. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-16-03-1" RANK="433"> On the other hand the United Kingdom, France, Israel, caused the military action in Egypt (Suez war, the second Middle East War). </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-16-03-1" RANK="434"> In North Africa under French domination, Tunisia, Morocco, in 1956 became independent. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-16-03-1" RANK="435"> In Algeria, and resisting the French settlers and local military independently, but was followed by armed conflict in between the National Liberation Front (FLN), independence was achieved in '62. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-16-03-1" RANK="436"> Other 1957 in colonial Africa, including Ghana and Nkrumah to the leaders became the first of their own independent black republic, in '60 born 17 things newly independent countries in one fell swoop, this year is &quot;Africa I was called the year, &quot;he said. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-16-03-1" RANK="437"> However, the colony is still the rest of Portugal, some of the economic interests do not want to let go of the old home country after independence as Belgium also interfere, was also example that caused the Congo Crisis. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-16-03-1" RANK="438"> Newly independent countries of the economy, because that have been developed along the economic interests of the colonial weapons states, the foundation of self-reliance was weak. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-16-03-1" RANK="439"> Moreover, in many areas, social infrastructure (basic livelihood), such as transportation networks and electricity, water, social institutions such as education and medical care had not been almost maintenance. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-16-03-1" RANK="440"> Therefore, political and economic after independence also unstable, is repeated civil wars and coup by conflict of tribalism, the military dictatorship has often appeared. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-16-03-1" RANK="441"> The initial momentum of the newly independent nation is lost, the direction aimed at modernization by the assistance of Western countries became dominant. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-4-19-3-4" RANK="442"> In the United Kingdom after the first World War, the economy is stagnant, the labor movement has been uplifting. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-4-19-3-4" RANK="443"> Government, but survived the offensive of workers by attaching the cooperation of moderate union leadership, workers got a new right to vote in the fourth-order election law amendment in war, put the expectation in Labour Party It became way. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-4-19-3-4" RANK="444"> In the general election of 1923 the Labour Party, which became the second party, per the first time government in coalition with the Liberal Party the following year, the first-order McDonald's Cabinet is satisfied. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-4-19-3-4" RANK="445"> The Labour Party Cabinet, it has been recommended a social policy to accept the Soviet Union, was short-lived. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-4-19-3-4" RANK="446"> However, this after Liberals continue to decline, politics came to an two-party era of the Conservative Party and the Labour Party. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-4-19-3-4" RANK="447"> United Kingdom in the face of exaltation of ethnic movement after the war, while suppress the independence movement of India and Egypt, and recognized the autonomy to Ireland with the exception of northern Ulster, in 1922 the Irish Free State was established. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-4-19-3-4" RANK="448"> Although Ireland Autonomy Law was established in 1914, when the First World War begins, implementation has been postponed. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-4-19-3-4" RANK="449"> The country was declared the full independence in 1937, is referred to as Yale, it was renamed the ale (Ireland) Republic in '49. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-4-19-3-4" RANK="450"> In addition, the Dominion, which cooperated in the home country at war, and recognize the relationship between the home country and equal in the British Empire Conference of 1926, was organized the British Commonwealth. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-4-19-3-4" RANK="451"> Then this system has been legislated by '31 Westminster Charter. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-4-19-3-4" RANK="452"> On the other hand France, sometimes you have lost huge claims against Imperial Russia in the Russian Revolution, it joined the Soviet Union interference war, demanded excessive compensation in Germany. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-4-19-3-4" RANK="453"> However, it fails to rule the occupation of 1923, left-wing coalition government has been established. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-4-19-3-4" RANK="454"> Briand Foreign Minister aim to cooperation with Germany, is withdrawal from the rule in 1925, it signed a Locarno treaty. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-4-19-3-4" RANK="455"> Then, in '28 it was passed a no-war treaty in cooperation with the Secretary of State Kellogg of the United States. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-01-01-4" RANK="456"> In happened oldest civilization with Mesopotamia, Egypt, Kotoba-dori called &quot;Nile of gift&quot;, a rich agriculture by using increase or decrease water of the Nile it was done. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-01-01-4" RANK="457"> Nile river is swollen, flooding every year from July to October, since carried the fertile soil from upstream, fruitful agriculture has been Itonama as compared to other regions. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-01-01-4" RANK="458"> Therefore Egypt Ayumihajime the road to shortly integration, was also gradually Totonoe political organization for national governance. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-01-01-4" RANK="459"> In the previous 3000 years around Egypt, faster than Mesopotamia, a unified nation by the king (Pharaoh) it was made. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-01-01-4" RANK="460"> Thereafter, temporarily had also receive the invasion and foreign domination of peripheral ethnic, age to keep the domestic unity lasted long. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-01-01-4" RANK="461"> It was subjected to despotic theocracy as God the king living in Egypt. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-01-01-4" RANK="462"> Such as the small number of priests, officials, but was given the land from the king is the owner of the land, the majority of residents are handicapped status of farmers, the tax and unpaid work to the product was imposed. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-01-01-4" RANK="463"> In the Old Kingdom, which flourished in the heart of the Memphis of the Nile under the basin, Khufu et al probably as his tomb, it was built a huge pyramid. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-01-01-4" RANK="464"> This shows the enormous power of the king is God. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-01-01-4" RANK="465"> The Middle Kingdom, the center has been moved to Thebes of Upper Egypt, nomadic Hyksos invaded from Syria in the last stage, the country was temporarily confused. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-01-01-4" RANK="466"> However, it banished the Hyksos angry New Kingdom before the 16th century, was further advanced to Syria. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-01-01-4" RANK="467"> The before the 14th century, established the capital Akhenaten (Ikunaton) is Tel = El-Amarna, was subjected to one of God (Aton) only the faith to reform prohibits the worship of traditional Kamigami. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-01-01-4" RANK="468"> This reform was over by the king of death, but not bound to the old tradition under the influence of faith reform realistic art (Amarna art) has been created. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-01-01-4" RANK="469"> Egyptian religion in polytheism around the sun god Ra, Amon = error of faith has become popular is combined with faith guardian deity Amon, the capital of Thebes in the New Kingdom era. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-01-01-4" RANK="470"> Egyptians to make a mummy to believe the world of immortal and after death of the soul, leaving the &quot;Book of the Dead.&quot; </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-01-01-4" RANK="471"> Picture documents written Egyptian dead were buried along with the mummy praying the happiness of the dead went to the afterlife. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-01-01-4" RANK="472"> Dead received the Last Judgement before the king of the underworld Osiris (third from right), they are drawn and how the defense of the act of living. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-01-01-4" RANK="473"> New Kingdom era. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-01-01-4" RANK="474"> In Egypt expedition of Rosetta Stone = Napoleon, it was discovered in Alexandria east of Rosetta (Rashid). </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-01-01-4" RANK="475"> French Champollion (1790-1832) is, to clue the Greek character, has succeeded in deciphering the sacred character. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-01-01-4" RANK="476"> In Egypt expedition of Rosetta Stone = Napoleon, it was discovered in Alexandria east of Rosetta (Rashid). </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-01-01-4" RANK="477"> French Champollion (1790-1832) is, to clue the Greek character, has succeeded in deciphering the sacred character. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-01-01-4" RANK="478"> In addition, geodetic surgery was developed in Egypt, is the original geometry of the Greeks, the solar calendar that was used along with the lunar calendar, became the Julian calendar and is later adopted by Rome. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-12-03-2" RANK="479"> With the development of the United States of the West, conflict in the south and the north has intensified. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-12-03-2" RANK="480"> Originally in the southern region it had developed a large plantation (plantation) to use the black slaves, Whitney in the late 18th century and invented the cotton gin, strengthened ties with the United Kingdom as a cotton-growing region. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-12-03-2" RANK="481"> Therefore southern continuation of slavery and free trade, has strongly demanded the state of autonomy. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-12-03-2" RANK="482"> The northern part of the free states and the southern slave states, the results when a new state is born of the Wild West, and fought vigorously in whether to allow slavery in the province. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-12-03-2" RANK="483"> However, more for both Territories of Kansas-Nebraska in the north, and become either a free state and to become or slave state if the law to be determined by the will of the residents is established in 1854, confrontation between North and South was rekindled. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-12-03-2" RANK="484"> Around this time, Women Writers Stowe (1811-96) is authored the &quot;Uncle = Tom's Cabin&quot;, was opposed to slavery. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-12-03-2" RANK="485"> This Republicans to cast slavery opposite is formed in the wake, conflict of North-South over slavery became decisive. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-12-03-2" RANK="486"> 1860, Lincoln Republican was elected president. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-12-03-2" RANK="487"> Although he was a moderate slavery expansion cons who prioritize the federal unified maintenance, southern states were separated from the federal, select the Jefferson = Devis to the President to make a well-'61 beginning Confederate States of America, here the Civil War began. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-12-03-2" RANK="488"> North had surpasses overwhelming in population and economic power, initially I struggled to Confederate under Lee command. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-12-03-2" RANK="489"> In addition, in the Homestead Act of 1862, settlers are lending the state-owned land of 160 acres (about 65 hectares), if settled five years, because it was supposed to be given the land, progress in the western development. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-12-03-2" RANK="490"> 65, Confederate and fall is the southern part of the capital Richmond surrendered, the United States was re-unified. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-3-7-3-8" RANK="491"> Changes in the early 19th century to 20 century society. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-3-7-3-8" RANK="492"> The funeral has attended from most of the royal family of Europe, yet by many of relatives or in-laws relationship, it had been connected to the queen. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-3-7-3-8" RANK="493"> Then within just a '20 less than, fighting countries is divided down the middle of the camp, yet As a result, it is to become a thing to turn off the beginning Austria, figure major dynasty, such as Russia and Germany, who was expected I wonder. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-3-7-3-8" RANK="494"> However, the beginning of the 20th century, mainly in Europe, while the various regions of the world Yuku are linked by a close relationship, deep cracks that occur there was also the era has come to reveal. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-3-7-3-8" RANK="495"> Unified completion of the German Empire, which was against the background of the Prussian forces, coupled with the remarkable development of the industry, was intended to shake the British position, which stood on the balance of power of the European powers. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-3-7-3-8" RANK="496"> Powers, while exploring each other of new alliances, and compete with and enhance the military, with the aim of ensuring the exclusive market for infrastructure enhancements and economic expansion of the country's industry, went embarked on colonial acquisition. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-3-7-3-8" RANK="497"> As seen in the previous chapter, in Europe, it was while born two camps to conflict that Tripartite Pact and the Triple Entente. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-3-7-3-8" RANK="498"> Such movement criticized by imperialism a four, also movement of socialism complaining of international solidarity and anti-war workers of countries had been organized. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-3-7-3-8" RANK="499"> For Socialists, the interests of the industry by the development of capitalism what, was something that produces conflict of national or ethnic. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-3-7-3-8" RANK="500"> Mainly in Germany, 19th century nationalism, the direction of national formation as a community of ethnic groups that share a language and culture, has become a thing of strengthening. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-3-7-3-8" RANK="501"> The Austro-Hungarian Empire and the Ottoman Empire, as a legacy of the great powers that troubled the inner diverse ethnic groups, was shaken to the movement of the various ethnic groups for ejecting. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-3-7-3-8" RANK="502"> Especially in the Balkans, by interventions such as various ethnic independence and Russia multiplied in it, it showed a very unstable aspects. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-3-7-3-8" RANK="503"> Among the colonial competition of European powers becomes violently, in various places resistance to expansion of powers has occurred in a variety. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-3-7-3-8" RANK="504"> Until where the system such as the dynasty domination had been established in its own way, the first in many cases strengthening of the framework or restructuring was required. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-3-7-3-8" RANK="505"> However, in many cases, the old regime is brittle against the advance of the European forces, and collapsed to remain not be shown sufficient resistance, or deprived of their rights and interests in the activities of the active industrial and capital of Europe, Kumiko in the world I went rare. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-3-7-3-8" RANK="506"> Youth in the Ottoman Empire Turkey, Sun Yat-sen these activities in China, was intended to be representative of such new generation. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-3-7-3-8" RANK="507"> After the Young Turk revolution, strengthened gradually Turkish nationalism in the Ottoman Empire, Empire went fraught with crisis of dismantling. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-3-7-3-8" RANK="508"> China's Sun Yat-sen, also by warlords defending local authority after the Xinhai Revolution, had to experience the long civil war. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-3-7-3-8" RANK="509"> National, ethnic formation, in the non-European world, was not in any way be self-evident. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-3-7-3-8" RANK="510"> This early 20th century, Japan had already realized the imperial constitutional framework, are troops in Beijing along with the Western countries in the Boxer Rebellion, it was beginning to enter the corner of powers. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-3-7-3-8" RANK="511"> 1902 of the Anglo-Japanese Alliance was so to speak a clear ranks of the imperialist countries. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-3-7-3-8" RANK="512"> Soon, Japan by fart the Russo-Japanese War, Yuku proceed to the annexation of Korea. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-4-19-4-6" RANK="513"> In the Netherlands East Indies, from the 1920s, the independence movement that aims to integrate as Indonesia beyond the framework of regional and religion began to be deployed. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-4-19-4-6" RANK="514"> Indonesia Communist Party, which was formed in 1920, rapidly expanded its influence, was the uprising in Sumatra and Java in 26-27 years, was devastated by Dutch troops. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-4-19-4-6" RANK="515"> However, in 1927 Indonesia Nationalist Party has been formed under the leadership of Sukarno, proposed a Merdeka (patriotic) movement. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-4-19-4-6" RANK="516"> Entering the 1930s, repression of the Netherlands side is arrested most of the leaders have been strengthened, in 1942 during the Second World War received the invasion of the Japanese army. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-4-19-4-6" RANK="517"> When the Popular Front government is established in France in 1936, the united front of the Communist Party and the nationalist political party was formed in Vietnam, it was advanced to the regional parliament. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-4-19-4-6" RANK="518"> However, it becomes catastrophic situation is again received a crackdown in the late 1930s, in 1940 the Japanese troops have been stationed. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-4-19-4-6" RANK="519"> The same year, mainly students of Rangoon University is Takin (husband) party is formed, it was eventually expand the anti-British independence movement under the leadership of Aung San =. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-4-19-4-6" RANK="520"> On the other hand, in Thailand, takes place a constitutional revolution in 1932, Congress was promulgated the Constitution was established. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-4-19-4-6" RANK="521"> In the Philippines, the United States recognized the autonomy in 1934, promised an independent after 10 years. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-4-19-2-8" RANK="522"> Versailles system was extremely unstable initially also, we are stable against the background of the recovery and the policy shift of the Soviet Union of Western Europe economy since 1923, it was born momentum of international cooperation among them. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-4-19-2-8" RANK="523"> Already in 1922, the two countries diplomatic relations are resumed tied the Rapallo Treaty between Germany and the Soviet Union, had fluctuating is Germany and Soviet containment system, the powers except for the United States over the next year from '24 approved one after another Soviet Union . </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-4-19-2-8" RANK="524"> In addition, seven countries including the UK, Germany and France in 1925, to open a meeting in Switzerland of Locarno, Germany western border of the status quo and the inviolability, Rhineland demilitarized, France and Czechoslovakia, respectively Poland such as mutual assistance treaty, it signed a group of the Convention. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-4-19-2-8" RANK="525"> Driving force behind the Convention established, Stresemann Foreign Minister of Germany, French Foreign Minister Briand, the Nobel Peace Prize of 1925 in the United Kingdom in Austin = Chamberlain Foreign Minister was awarded. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-4-19-2-8" RANK="526"> This Locarno treaty European collective security system is established, Germany is next in '26, accession to the League of Nations was observed. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-4-19-2-8" RANK="527"> Also, no-war treaty vowed to renunciation of war as a means of national policy implementation in 1928 (Kellogg = Briand agreement) is also tied, international cooperation has reached the apex. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-4-19-2-8" RANK="528"> From reflection of the war, reduction of armaments but had been an important issue of the International Federation, national interests did not expedite at odds. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-4-19-2-8" RANK="529"> In Washington Naval Treaty, Ying capital ship owned tonnage ratio, rice, day, Buddha, Lee 5: 5: 3: 1.67: was 1.67. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-4-19-2-8" RANK="530"> The London Conference on Disarmament, the auxiliary ship owned tonnage ratio Britain, the US, day 10: 10: 7. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-S-1-3-4-1" RANK="531"> 589 years after it was fart the era of long division, was able to Emperor Wen of Han Sui generated from the North (Emperor Wen of Sui) is again unify the country. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-S-1-3-4-1" RANK="532"> Emperor Wen of Han has established a Ritsuryō and inherited the policy of North Korea, in the land system equal-field system, and such as performing a fubing system that soldiers farmers in the military system, was working to strengthen its domination. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-S-1-3-4-1" RANK="533"> Also, stop taking Kyu-hin Chiang Kai-shek, it was adopted the bureaucracy in the newly written test. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-S-1-3-4-1" RANK="534"> This system is called the imperial examination been handed down subsequent to each dynasty, and was carried out until the 20th century began. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-S-1-3-4-1" RANK="535"> Imperial examination is with supporting a mechanism emperor to dominate the whole country with the bureaucracy, it had a major impact on the way of China's academic and cultural. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-S-1-3-4-1" RANK="536"> In addition, Emperor Yang of Sui of Sui, and the North China is a political and military center, as the aorta of economy that connects the rich Gangnam of goods, was to complete the Grand Canal. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-S-1-3-4-1" RANK="537"> The Grand Canal is also, each dynasty piled up renovation of After that, I was used as a transport of the mains. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-S-1-3-4-1" RANK="538"> However, the expedition over three times to these large civil engineering projects and Goguryeo was plagued farmers. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-S-1-3-4-1" RANK="539"> Among this confusion, 618 years, Emperor Gaozu of Tang was a military commander of the Sui (Koso) is per throne, it was built the Tang as capital Chang'an. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-S-1-3-4-1" RANK="540"> The basis of this dynasty, was built in the era of him and his son Taejong (Riyo-min). </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-S-1-3-4-1" RANK="541"> Vietnam north by installing was control the various ethnic groups. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-S-1-3-4-1" RANK="542"> Nomadic tribe was also recognized the authority of the Emperor of Tang. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-S-1-3-4-1" RANK="543"> Tang, tailored the Code, such as law or decree, provided with a control tower of the three provinces and six parts of the center. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-S-1-3-4-1" RANK="544"> Initially the force of noble lineage aristocracy was strong, I began to adopt the bureaucracy by the imperial examination, which was gradually enrich the system of Sui. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-S-1-3-4-1" RANK="545"> Also, assign the land to farmers by performing Tasei average, mining lease, Yong, tone, and impose a tax and labor consisting Zatsu徭 (Soyocho system), and financed the finances. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-S-1-3-4-1" RANK="546"> From farmers who were given land by the average Tasei, fubing system to issue a soldier by the principle of Heino match it has also been developed. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-1-6-1-4" RANK="547"> However, most parts of Southeast Asia, belongs to the East Asian tribute area, there was also mutual exchange. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-1-6-1-4" RANK="548"> Song at the famous Abe no Nakamaro of &quot;month might could appear in heaven of the original pretend salmon Kasuga become Mikasa mountain If you look&quot; (Tomei morning equilibrium) is 鎮南 MiyakoMamoru (name of safety Nanto protection after the An Lushan Rebellion) that government was the Secretary of is not well known. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-1-6-1-4" RANK="549"> Abe no Nakamaro's Kaiyuan 5 (717) years of Japanese students of the tender 16-year-old was accompanied to the envoys, but I want to rush the ranks of the Tang court in no time at all. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-1-6-1-4" RANK="550"> It becomes a staff of Prince in the mid-30s, emperor immediate secretary audit by the time more than 50 years of age, had become a mandarin of the sub three goods. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-1-6-1-4" RANK="551"> In addition, also famous in poetry, create a Li Bai and Wang Wei, such as first-class poets and salon, leaving its name to Toshi statement. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-1-6-1-4" RANK="552"> 760 years turbulent is headed to the convergence Yasushi, Nakamaro is Ninze is to 鎮南 MiyakoMamoru, and went to the current Hanoi, after established the Yunnan communication path, is return to duty 767 years. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-1-6-1-4" RANK="553"> Center of Nanhai trade, the safety Nanto protection in jobs that benefit, when there was usually make the goods until the quinine, Nakamaro is seemed integrity of officials, which died in Chang'an in 770 years, Tang that has been Zoi the Shu-dai Metropolitan supervision, without any property, the family was in poverty. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-1-6-1-4" RANK="554"> Imperial Court of Japan heard this I have sent to the bereaved family commissioned the silk and cotton to Tang used. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-1-6-1-4" RANK="555"> In Abe no Nakamaro Japan, it has not been evaluated only as a poet but, at that time, it was also the finest of international civil servants shining in the history of during the day - - Vietnam three countries. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-01-02-9" RANK="556"> The Great and destroyed the Persian after the conquest of Egypt, or stay until India Northwest further recommended the army, built a large empire that spans from east to west. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-01-02-9" RANK="557"> 3 kingdom of Alexander the Empire and the Hellenistic era After he died suddenly, the territory is contested by warlords of subordinates called Diadokoi (successor), was eventually split into countries such as Antigonus morning Macedonia and Seleucid Empire Syria Ptolemaic Egypt. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-4-19-5-8" RANK="558"> After the war, in Eastern Europe that many of the independent country was born, after countries that had the complex ethnic problem, the impact of the global agricultural recession, the political was also economically unstable. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-4-19-5-8" RANK="559"> For this reason, in most of the country, from the previously 1920s, conservative dictatorship was made by landowners and military. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-4-19-5-8" RANK="560"> In Hungary, also dictatorship 25 years since 1919 Horuti continued, Pilsudski has started the military dictatorship from '26 in Poland. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-4-19-5-8" RANK="561"> Yugoslavia is shifted to the king dictatorship in 1929, Bulgaria, Romania king also, in the 1930s was declared one after another the dictatorship government. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-4-19-5-8" RANK="562"> Comintern, which could not be prevented from fascism and militaristic dictatorship regime, at the 7th Congress of 1935, it was converted policies to hostile social democratic parties of up to it, all the forces opposed to cooperate to fascism We have proposed the formation of the Popular Front (antifascist united front). </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-4-19-5-8" RANK="563"> In France, it established the Popular Front cabinet that Prime Minister Blum of the Socialist Party in 1936, was enacted and paid leave law that triggers of today's Vacances. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-4-19-5-8" RANK="564"> In Spain, second Republic is established in 1931, separation of church and state and land reform has been grave. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-4-19-5-8" RANK="565"> Landowners and with a sense of crisis in this, capitalist, is support to the church forces, and right-wing political parties to rise, such as the Socialist Party and the Communist Party in 1936 was born the Popular Front government in cooperation. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-4-19-5-8" RANK="566"> However, in addition to the non-interference policy of Britain and France, there is also opposition inside the Popular Front, civil war by fall Madrid in 1939, and the end to the Franco side of victory, Franco's dictatorship was followed thereafter. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-4-19-5-8" RANK="567"> In Portugal, Salazar of dictatorship it has been carried out since 1933. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-03-02-1" RANK="568"> Emperor Wen of Han Sui exiting from the north periphery of the North (Emperor Wen of Sui) is to defeat the Chen Dynasty, and unified China, which has been split into north and south, was established the capital in Daikyo-jo (Changan). </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-03-02-1" RANK="569"> Asia and Zui-dai canals of Sui-Tang era Sui is incorporating a system that has been tried in various dynasties of the Northern and Southern Dynasties era, I tried to Katameyo the basis of fiscal and military by the equal-field system, Soyocho system-fu military system. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-03-02-1" RANK="570"> It also abolished the Kyu-hin Chiang Kai-shek, and tried to centralization by creating a system of imperial examination to determine the widely human resources by the test of Confucianism. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-03-02-1" RANK="571"> Grand Canal, which was completed when the child Emperor Yang of Sui of Emperor Wen of Han is, linking the Gangnam that more developed north and south morning era and North China, was China the first time in the history of north-south traffic trunk. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-03-02-1" RANK="572"> Warlords of Emperor Gaozu of Tang was raising an army among the Sui end of the rebellion (Koso of Tang), the vertical Tang to defeat Sui in 618 years, it was the capital of Chang'an. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-03-02-1" RANK="573"> Asia and Zui-dai canals of Sui-Tang era </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-4-19-3-1" RANK="574"> First World War caused a large fluctuation in the world economy. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-4-19-3-1" RANK="575"> United States consists of debtor countries and creditor nations, the other was overwhelmed in industrial power, Wall Street in New York has emerged as the new center of world finance. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-4-19-3-1" RANK="576"> Industrial production of the United States, accounted for 42% of the entire world in 1929, the 1923 year-end had held a half of the world's gold. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-4-19-3-1" RANK="577"> Harding, Coolidge (tenure 1923-29), three generations of Hoover. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-4-19-3-1" RANK="578"> Also externally to takes a isolationism, the League of Nations but did not participate, and to prevent the spread of socialism, expand the aggressive foreign policy in order to expand the market, the German economic recovery and China We supported the ethnic movement. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-4-19-3-1" RANK="579"> A new industry is developing, and industrialization progresses in the north, blacks seeking work has been moved in large quantities in the north from the south. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-4-19-3-1" RANK="580"> However, a motion seeking a return to the &quot;good old days&quot; of the large pre-war also strongly, establishment of Prohibition was intended to tell one side of conservative and strong American society of religious. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-4-19-3-1" RANK="581"> Also, the stronger criticism against immigrants, in the immigration law that was enacted in 1924, Asian immigrants, such as the Japanese have been virtually prohibited. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-4-19-3-1" RANK="582"> The center of American society is a Caucasian called Wasp (WASP), blacks and, Eastern Europe-based, Italian system, and is of Asian immigrants has been the subject of discrimination and racial prejudice. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-4-19-3-1" RANK="583"> The WASP, and as it is an acronym for WhiteAnglo-SaxonProtestant, refers to the Protestant British-based whites. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-4-19-3-1" RANK="584"> Activities of KKK was activated. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-4-19-3-1" RANK="585"> In addition, the persecution of socialist movement has occurred. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-4-19-3-1" RANK="586"> Sacco = Vu~anzetti incident, known for false accusation also happened at this time. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-15-03-3" RANK="587"> He also set a &quot;continuous Seo Yokyo-aid Engineering agriculture&quot;, it was out out the routes of overthrow warlords, overthrow imperialism. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-15-03-3" RANK="588"> Sun Yat-sen was died in '25, but the five-thirty movement that the labor dispute was spread as a trigger in the spinning factory in Shanghai of Japanese management in the same year, was intended to show the exaltation of the anti-imperialist movement in China . </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-15-03-3" RANK="589"> However, in the national government inside, and the Communist Party colleagues leftist aimed at expansion of the mass movement, and the right to be wary of this has deepened the conflict. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-15-03-3" RANK="590"> Chiang Kai-shek the same year in April, the oppression of the Communist Party is causing the Shanghai coup, he became the president to make a national government in Nanjing. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-15-03-3" RANK="591"> 1928, Northern Expedition is resumed, and forthcoming shortly in Beijing. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-15-03-3" RANK="592"> Japan repeated Shandong troops to interfere with the national unity of the national government, also Japanese Army (Kwantung Army) in the middle Zhang Saku霖 traditional Japanese Mukden had sponsored warlords pulls up to the northeast from Beijing and losing to Northern Expedition Army, by blow up the train were killed Zhang, it tried to control of the northeast. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-15-03-3" RANK="593"> ZHANG ZUOLIN with a foundation in the Northeast, the Anhui clique of Duan Qirui (1865-1936), beating the Zhili clique such as the influential warlords Wu Peifu (1874-1939), had advanced to Beijing at that time. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-15-03-3" RANK="594"> This plot will fail, since Kohari ManabuRyo of ZHANG ZUOLIN admitted the northeast dominate the national government to counter Japan, the national unity of the national government has been tentatively achieved. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-15-03-3" RANK="595"> Chiang Kai-shek, by connecting with the Shanghai center in Zhejiang chaebol that had dominated the Chinese business community through the bank capital, was aiming a unified administration by the KMT one-party system on the basis of the United States, the United Kingdom of support. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-15-03-3" RANK="596"> On the other hand, the Chinese Communist Party, after Kokkyo division of 1927, was to have tried a few times of the uprising failed, was converted to a policy to make the Soviet regime in rural areas. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-15-03-3" RANK="597"> base ground that Mao pull are Red Army (Communist Party Army) was built in Jinggangshan gradually spread, Chinese Soviet Republic Provisional Government to the chief Mao Zedong in Jiangxi Ruijin in '31 has been established. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.0" SCORE="0.0" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-15-03-3" RANK="598"> National government has repeated the siege against the Soviet regime, but was not able to extinguish it. </PASSAGE>
    </PASSAGE_SET>
  </TOPIC>
</TOPIC_SET>