<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TOPIC_SET>
  <TOPIC ID="D792W10-1">
    <PASSAGE_SET/>
  </TOPIC>
  <TOPIC ID="D792W10-10">
    <PASSAGE_SET>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.9200341356137146" SCORE="7.91923" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-S-3-7-1-9" RANK="1"> That Zheng He was a eunuch of Muslims. Fleet is too much 60 vessels, 20 000 those massive thousands of people, the voyage has ranged from the Indian Ocean to the east coast of Africa. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.9161475843722604" SCORE="7.54819" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-4-20-2-7" RANK="2"> Kashmir British colonial era, Han-o are Hindus, about 60 percent of the residents were Muslims. 1947 of India, upon Pakistan separatist, from the fact that Han-o's decision to join India, began two countries attribution dispute. The current border is a cease-fire line of the first Tsugishirushi pa war. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.9145345287805652" SCORE="7.40405" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-2-5-2-17" RANK="3"> 1825 of the Decembrists of turbulent since, Russian emperors of the 19th century was cracking down revolutionary idea. Among the first half of the 19th century that tyranny is strengthened, people who have a consciousness that dedication to society as a whole of happiness, have emerged in between the nobles. They are intellectuals with a radical and left-wing ideology, it was called intelligentsia Zia. In between them, it was caused controversy On historic mission of Russia from the 1840s through the 1960s. People of Slavic faction think what individualism community spirit unlike of Western Europe is the center of the Russian ethnicity was emphasized that to go to Peter the Great previous tradition. On the other hand Western Europe faction, the reverse specific Russia insisted that he should imitate the Western Europe learn from Western Europe. Once in the '60s, clergy, junior officials and merchants, such as various class-born intellectuals appeared, it began to play an active role through the publishing activities and secret society. As the 70's, from among such a chaotic situation, revolutionary idea of ​​such narodniks was born. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.9139955989411213" SCORE="7.35709" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-3-9-3-8" RANK="4"> Minority among the early society blacks, who had been placed in the position of underdog is, also was allowed to expand the movement to challenge for the role of such society, it is a major feature of this period. Motion seeking black Elimination of All Forms of Discrimination against, it showed the exaltation as the civil rights movement in the 60s in the center of the Martin Luther King, the new Civil Rights Act was established in '64. It was an important step to improve their status. However, the black people of the reality that many impoverished severe, Martin Luther King was assassinated in '68. On the other hand, in between the black people it was also increased movement that tries to reattempt look at their own values ​​and culture possessed by themselves as African-American. Homogenized culture, rather than assimilation to the dominant value, tendency to try to respect their own culture, appeared also to movement of the minority, such as indigenous peoples. The August 70, for the sake of American women's suffrage won 50 anniversary, women of rallies and demonstrations took place in various places. It was indicative of the growing movement of women's rights claims gave birth to words of Woman ribs in the 60s. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.9073187492223203" SCORE="6.82032" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-4-20-1-8" RANK="5"> 1951 of the Convention under the Cold War, for the sake of Japan and peace and security in the Far East, the United States forces stationed in Japan, was to be construed as an admission that you want to use the base. In '60, it is revised to a more strengthened the bilateral of &quot;US-Japan Treaty of Mutual Cooperation and Security&quot;, the violent opposition movement, which in Japan is called the security struggle happened. '70 After it is automatically extended. After the Cold War, The Governments of Japan and the United States is newly redefine the Japan-US security arrangements, for cooperation in the case of &quot;peripheral situation&quot; of Japan's new guidelines were created. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.9041019830814981" SCORE="6.58822" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-3-9-1-15" RANK="6"> Western European countries progress in post-war economic recovery, hailed the high-growth period through the 1960s from the 1950s. Began showing signs is that independence from the United States in political, in the French and core cooperative relationship of West Germany, and began to walk the road of Western European integration. European Economic Community, which was established in 年 1958 (EEC) is, France, West Germany, Italy, the Netherlands, Belgium, is composed of six countries of Luxembourg, standardization of abolition and export customs tariffs in the region have been pursued. The 1967 European Community (EC) next, integrated has been further promoted. United Kingdom, on the other hand, initially as impair the interests of the British Commonwealth does not join the EEC, the formation of the Nordic countries and the neutral country and the European Free Trade Association (EFTA) in 1960. But the UK economy is stagnant compared to the economic growth of the EC countries, in 1973, Britain joined the EC. France, among which is deepening upset by the Algerian War of Independence, which began in 1954, 1958, De Gaulle who appeared the military revolt in the wake has launched the fifth Republic by amending the Constitution. By referendum and is elected president, the de Gaulle with enhanced authority in between the United States and the Soviet Union two major powers, the expansion of foreign policy to assert the unique position of France. But &quot;May Revolution&quot; that occurred around the students in 1968, including the nature of society Yuku is highly management of, was supposed to reveal the contradictions of De Gaulle regime. On the other hand, West Germany, which has made significant economic growth after World War II, Prime Minister Brandt from the late 1960s to advance press the east diplomacy, the Soviet Union and Poland, efforts to improve relations with Eastern European countries such as East Germany. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.8972421174079747" SCORE="6.14144" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-3-9-1-10" RANK="7"> Progress of the Cold War also affect the domestic United States, in the 1950s the suppression of speech and thought called McCarthyism, it was promoted the control of public opinion. On the other hand, after the war of the United States enjoy the economic prosperity until the 1960s, it had been supporting the it was a technological innovation. Innovation that began in the United States would allow the large-scale mass production, it was one after another created the new products such as large change nylon and plastic consumption life of industrialized society. Economic prosperity will prompt the middle class of the American people, the spread of higher education and popular culture was impressed the American society as the &quot;rich society.&quot; Mass production and the American way of life, which is representative for mass consumption, so that after the war, begin to penetrate the beginning around the world Western Europe and Japan. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.8910499821496447" SCORE="5.78607" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-3-9-3-6" RANK="8"> Kashmir British colonial era, Han-o are Hindus, about 60 percent of the residents were Muslims. 1947 of India, upon Pakistan separatist, from the fact that Han-o's decision to join India, began two countries attribution dispute. The current border is a cease-fire line of the first Tsugishirushi pa war. Pakistan, but wants the intervention of such referendum the international community to determine the attribution on the basis of the UN resolutions, India has refused to third-party intervention. Long lasted Vietnam war, also in the United States, also brought great changes in the world. America in 1963 there was a deepening intervention in Vietnam, President Kennedy was assassinated. In this case to the border, then the United States is fully intervened in Vietnam, as the war expands, myth that the Second World War strongly led to the after world rich America, went collapse greatly. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.8891325027553759" SCORE="5.684" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-S-4-13-2-2" RANK="9"> Eastern Europe in the wake of Stalin criticism of Khrushchev countries were upset. When the anti-Soviet riots occur in 1956 Hungary, the Soviet Union was put down this by force. In '68, starting a political and economic reform by the Communist Party leadership in Czechoslovakia (the &quot;Prague Spring&quot;), the Soviet Union this was also oppression. However, the motion to the liberalization and democratization in Eastern Europe intensified, influence of the Soviet Union was gradually reduced. On the other hand, preach capitalism overthrow China rebounded to the movement against the US approach of the Soviet Union, it was in conflict with the Soviet Union. China from 1958, had recommended its own socialist construction by the people's communes, sometimes the Soviet Union was discontinued economic aid in '60, radical economic construction was bankrupt. When Liu Shaoqi et al became Jintao changes to Mao Zedong to restore the economy by adjusting policy, hair causes the Cultural Revolution, which listed the transformation of education, academic and thought, confusion lasted over 10 years. Among the Sino-Soviet split deepens, China has succeeded in nuclear test, also in '69 happened Sino-Soviet border conflict. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.8884939424020752" SCORE="5.65078" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-2-11-3-5" RANK="10"> 1514 of the summer, in the current Republic of Turkey of the eastern part of the chalcoalumite Diller down of the earth, there was a tournament game between the morning and the Safavid Ottoman. Safavid military mainstay, is a cavalry corps, which has been called Kijirubashi, Ottoman military mainstay of opposition to it, was the Janissaries infantry corps equipped with a gun. The result of the fight, gun Corps overwhelmed the cavalry, became the Ottoman military victory. In Japan, Nobunaga gun Corps of Oda in the battle of Nagashino in 1575 it is well known that broke the cavalry of Takeda, battle of chalcoalumite Diller down is that of ago in '60 than it. Ottoman army, already during this battle earlier Constantinople conquest (1453), have overwhelmed the enemy with artillery and gun. Janissaries corps, military band, Corps of Engineers, artillery corps, in the emperor immediate standing army equipped and gun Corps, later was a modern army in the previous cliff to develop in Europe. In this effect, it will be making the infantry gun troops also Safavids, also followed it also Mughal Empire of India. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.8861582119513265" SCORE="5.53241" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-13-03-2" RANK="11"> Qing, was losing streak to the Royal Navy with excellent weapons, signed the Treaty of Nanking in 1842, ceded Hong Kong Island, Shanghai, Ningbo, Fuzhou, Xiamen, Guangzhou of 5 the harbor of open ports, the abolition of the public line, reparations We showed such payments. Even better in '43, consular jurisdiction (extraterritoriality), agreement tariff (loss of tariff autonomy), it signed the unequal treaties to admit such as most-favored-nation treatment. After the A countries signed a B countries and treaty provisions that if you signed a separate treaty and C countries, also provides a privilege that was given to country C in country B. If the B countries do not have the same obligation to the country A, becomes unfavorable conditions towards country A, this is called unilateral most-favored-nation treatment. Gominato (five-neck) refer to trade Shotei - Treaty of the Bogue. The UK is provided first of Concession (the area where foreign has administrative rights) in Shanghai in 1845, foreign Concession went flute in the subsequent opening of the airport field. The United States and the treaty of wanghia in '44, signed a France and Huangpu treaty, I admitted the same rights and the United Kingdom. But it does not rise profit of about expected even Western countries in the post-war trade, the United Kingdom, which was disgruntled had interviewed machine of treaty revision. In Guangzhou in 1856, the Chinese crew of the ship that claims the United Kingdom Flag has happened Arrow No. incident of being arrested on suspicion of piracy. United Kingdom This was the pretext, to perform joint troops is calling on France, was caused Arrow War (Second Opium War). British and French troops occupied Guangzhou, by sea north is approaching in Tianjin, it tied the Tianjin Treaty in '58. But the following year, to the machine that the entering the capital of the instruments of ratification exchange envoy Qing troops were blocked by armed, the Anglo-French troops occupied Beijing by troops again, tied the Beijing Convention in '60. At this time, British and French troops looted in the palace of Yuanmingyuan, was carried out the destruction, the garden became the ruins. Qing, foreign minister Beijing Representative, Tianjin, such as 11 of the harbor opened, freedom of travel in China inland foreigners, acknowledged such as freedom of the Christian missionary, was ceded Kyuryu peninsula south to the United Kingdom. Around the same time opium trade it has also been certified. 19th century in the mid, Russia also strengthen the pressure of the original Eastern Siberia Governor-General Muravyov to China, in 1858 was the territorial Heilongjiang north by connecting the Qing and the treaty of aigun. Russia Eastern foray Then in '60 won the Primorye by connecting the Beijing treaty, was the Vladimir Voss to open the talk harbor Pacific Ocean foray base ground. Russia Eastern foray In addition to troops in the Ili region to machine the revolt of Muslims (Ili incident), it was decided taken up in favor the border with Qing in the Ili treaty of '81. Russia Eastern foray Also in Central Asia direction, indicating the momentum of the south, in the middle of the nineteenth century, it was placed under the control of a three-Khanate of Bukhara, Khiva, Kokand of Uzbeks. Russia Eastern foray </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.8842415842825411" SCORE="5.43881" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-4-20-2-9" RANK="12"> Sub-Saharan Africa, Ghana in 1957 under the guidance of Nkuruma (Nkrumah) is, Guinea 58 years, even 60 years, independently of 17 countries, in 1960 the &quot;Year of Africa It was called. &quot; These independent countries formed the Organization of African Unity (OAU) in '63. Since then the former colonial independently one after another, most of the region of Africa in the first half of the 1960s was independent. However, in many countries, for economic structure that was subordinate to the former colonial powers remained, self-reliance of the economy did not proceed. In addition, conflict and regime inside of the power struggle between ethnic groups at the national internal, further civil war continued for unlimited arms exports of foreign countries, often military dictatorship was established. In the former Belgian Congo, after independence in 1960, revolt happened to disputes over the copper resources Western countries also interfere with the (Congo Crisis). In addition, in South Africa, apartheid policy against blacks (apartheid) have been taken. Independent in 1965 of Southern Rhodesia (now Zimbabwe) be those white minority regime went, again participation in the black politics is rejected, racial discrimination has continued. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.8785177138652746" SCORE="5.17667" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-S-4-13-2-3" RANK="13"> Western European countries, international status was reduced by the loss of appearance and colonial post-war US-Soviet superpower. However, when the economy comes to reconstruction in the United States of assistance, we were aiming for economic integration to compete with the United States and the Soviet Union. France to join the European Coal and Steel Community (ECSC), Italy, six countries such as West Germany formed the European Economic Community in 1958 (EEC), the '67 has evolved into the European Community (EC). To achieve the free movement in the region of tariff reduction and capital and labor, in '73 UK, etc also a member, economic zone comparable to the United States and the Soviet Union was born. France, which became the core of economic integration, to develop nuclear weapons under the De Gaulle president, for example, by leave of the NATO military organization, walked their own way away from the United States. In addition, West Germany, was achieved economic growth of the miracle while accept the migrant workers under Adenauer prime minister. Japan, which has returned to the international community in UN member is observed in '56 enters in the process of rapid economic growth since the late 1950s, continued economic growth of up to 10% annual rate. As a result, in the late '60s to become the &quot;economic superpower&quot; of the capitalist bloc the second place, by the end of the 1970s it became the world's best in automobile production. On the other hand, fluctuation by huge spending advantage in the Vietnam War in the US economy, even capitalism camp's progress in the direction of multipolarity. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.874290484728798" SCORE="4.99822" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-S-4-13-5-1" RANK="14"> In between from the end of World War II of about '60, the world's population exceeded 60 million people of about 3 times, the United Nations Member States four times at the time of establishment, has reached 192 countries. By expansion and the development of transportation telegraph technology, movement of people and goods and information has increased both the mass, to expand on a global scale beyond the border, there is an increasing interdependence (globalization). Since the 1990s, there is no wall of the east and west of the political and economic system, regulation of the nation by investment and exports and imports are eased or abolished, the world of trade and financial and multilateral deployed, but market economy has progressed. In 1995 established the World Trade Organization (WTO) in order to proceed smoothly the economic liberalization, the Association of Southeast Asian Nations (ASEAN), Asia Pacific Ocean Economic Cooperation (APEC), EU expanded its member countries. Huge companies, and create a manufacturing and sales of network on a global scale, also sequence the same products in the shop also in developing countries in developed countries, standardization of life culture has advanced. Depending on the TV and the spread of the Internet, information, including voice and image is transmitted around the world in an instant, it has a major impact on politics and economy. In other hand the integration of the world progresses, in developing countries, expanding economic disparity between the industrialized countries, and suffer the excessive debt for development, population explosion of destruction and cities, including the forest ecosystem serious It has become a problem. Environmental issues such as global warming, as well as issues of political, economic and social has been asked to resolve on a global scale. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.8728179859173615" SCORE="4.93881" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-16-04-1" RANK="15"> 1961 in the United States, Kennedy of the Democratic Party was appointed to the President, and began to beat the positive attitude over the inside and outside under the banner of the New Frontier policy. While avoiding the entire surface of confrontation with the Soviet Union, externally to takes a policy to prevent the influence of the national liberation movement of the Cuban Revolution and the Indochinese Peninsula, although the country was seeking a response to the civil rights movement of blacks, November 63 It was assassinated in the southern campaign. The civil rights movement led King pastor Martin Luther King organized a civil rights movement to protest against the black discrimination, in August 1963, was noted by leaders to &quot;March on Washington&quot; by the tens of thousands of supporters. Johnson President took over after 1964, passed a Civil Rights Act aimed at the Elimination of All Forms of Discrimination against blacks, it was to promote social policies aimed at discrimination and poverty of eliminating the original &quot;great society&quot; plan. But Externally, we expanded the military intervention in Vietnam. From the late 60s, by the increase of quagmire and the damage of the Vietnam War, anti-war movement centered on the students in the country has intensified. In addition, such as leader Martin Luther King, Jr. in the civil rights movement is assassinated in '68, conflict over the black movement also becomes serious, social crack became uncovered. The civil rights movement led King pastor Martin Luther King organized a civil rights movement to protest against the black discrimination, in August 1963, was noted by leaders to &quot;March on Washington&quot; by the tens of thousands of supporters. '69 To Republican Nixon was appointed president, but was allowed to withdraw American troops from Vietnam, resigned in '74 in the Watergate scandal. Incident Nixon camp Republican aimed at the President re-election, was trying to eavesdrop on the Democratic Party headquarters in Washington's Watergate = building in 1972. Although Nixon himself was involved, because it was denied it, and resigned before the impeachment resolution adoption of the House of Representatives plenary session. By turmoil in the second half of the 1960s, rich and stable society, the United States of the image of a democratic state management, was greatly impaired. In the Soviet Union is dismissal is Khrushchev in 1964, was handed to the regime of Prime Minister Kosygin, Brezhnev first secretary. There was no fundamental change in and out of the policy, the voice of progress and Stalin criticism of liberalization was suppressed. Among the socialist countries to support Albania in China, and also began to expand its own diplomacy Romania also take the Soviet Union and the distance with the oil resources. '68, Takes place national movement seeking democratization in Czechoslovakia, Dubcek reformers became Communist Party General Secretary was trying to promote the liberalization. Attempts to Czechoslovakia national liberalization that has surfaced in Prague citizen in June 1968 to protest the Soviet Union's military intervention, the same year in August, has been put down in the invasion of the Soviet army. Although this movement was called &quot;Prague Spring&quot;, the Soviet Union, which feared the spread of liberalization, is military intervention in Czechoslovakia with four armed forces of the Warsaw Pact, was sealed the movement of reform. Attempts to Czechoslovakia national liberalization that has surfaced in Prague citizen in June 1968 to protest the Soviet Union's military intervention, the same year in August, has been put down in the invasion of the Soviet army. The Soviet Union by this action is internationally condemned, and lowered the prestige as a leader of the Eastern socialist bloc. In addition, the movement of the reform of the socialist bloc also because it was inhibited, thereafter, the Soviet Union and East European socialist countries of politics and economy was stagnant. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.8707059947184177" SCORE="4.85593" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-3-9-3-3" RANK="16"> After Stalin's criticism, the Soviet Union and hammer out a peaceful coexistence line, China is criticized and this is the stifle of world domination and the revolution by the US-Soviet, Sino-Soviet dispute began. 1960, the Soviet Union to stop aid to China, increasing your technician, confrontation becomes a decisive, armed conflict took place at the border in '69. In addition, China is promoting the development of nuclear weapons in the 1960s, atomic bomb experiment in '64, was successful hydrogen bomb test in '67. In China, after the failure of the Great Leap Forward, Liu Shaoqi was loosen the radical socialization. On the other hand, Mao Zedong is to undergo a large-scale social and political movement called culture by the Red Guards in 1966 Revolution, it began to deprive rights struggle. Confusion has covered the whole country, but it was converged by four duo of arrest of the leadership of the '76. For this exercise, the party and government cadres, attacked the intellectuals, but cultural heritage is also evaluation that was a social disaster that spans 10 years, such as being destroyed, the international Vietnam anti-war movement and international along with the social movements, it was also called &quot;rebellion&quot; of the global youth. China settled with the United States in 71-72 years, it has returned to the international community to give the right to represent the United Nations. This movement along with the progress of the strategic arms limitation negotiations of the United States and the Soviet Union, showed the direction (detente) of East-West tension is weakened. In addition, Japan normalized diplomatic relations in '72 and, economic relations were rapidly expanding. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.8673399966705483" SCORE="4.72922" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-12-02-5" RANK="17"> The division was followed by Italy, after the February 1848 revolution, also participated Mazzini, which has been leading the &quot;Young Italy&quot; but the Roman Republic was built, it brought down the French army, also, is an obstacle to the unification of Italy Kingdom of Sardinia fought with Austria was also was defeated. &quot;Young Italy&quot; is formed in 1831. '34 Once collapsed, but had been re-formed in 1843. Soon under Vittorio = Emanuele II went to Sardinia throne, liberals of Cavour ringing the Prime Minister to promote industrialization, and was war with Austria in 1859 and signed a Napoleon III and the secret alliance. Sardinia you win in this battle painting Lombardy, next in '60, central Italy was also annexed by cede Savoy and Nice in France. In addition, this year, &quot;Young Italy&quot; born of Garibaldi has occupied the Kingdom of the Two Sicilies, it gave it to the King of Sardinia. By organizing a militia called the Expedition of the Thousand in Garibaldi in 1860, it was greatly contributed to the Italian unification. '61 Of the Kingdom of Italy after the establishment was activity seeking admission to the kingdom of Rome Papal States. As a result, the Kingdom of Italy is established in March 1861, Vittorio = Emanuele II was attached to the throne. Then merged Venice was Austrian territory in 1866, the 1870 national unity was realized by occupation and Roman Papal States. Such as Trieste and South Tyrol stay in Austria territory (&quot;Italian irredentism&quot;), also, the papacy that stuck inside the Vatican Holy See continued to conflict with the Italian government. However, north and poor south of the disparity that was the development of the industry, was not then also be eliminated. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.8664996906974467" SCORE="4.69857" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-S-1-1-1-1" RANK="18"> In Mesopotamia, Sumerians from before around 3500 years have made Ur, the city-state, such as Uruk in the lower reaches of the Tigris river, the Euphrates. City surrounded by walls, agricultural production, became the center of trade and defense. Was built temple worship the guardian deity at its center, the king is the highest of the priests ruled the people as a representative of the guardian. The politics that uses the authority of these God's theocracy. Sumerians, and increments the cuneiform that has developed an emoticon to the clay plate, using a Bronze, developed a astronomy and calendar for farming and festivals, 60 hexadecimal, began thinking like one seven days a week basis. By the time before around 2400, west it looks like the tribes of Semitic to many settled from, and dominated the Mesopotamia on behalf of the Sumerians, and built many of the city-state to inherit the culture. It is an old Babylonian kingdom centered on the Babylon is most prosperous among them. Hammurabi the king of this country was unified Mesopotamia before the 18th century. He is for the kingdom of maintaining order, enacted the Code of Hammurabi are collectively up to that law. In particular criminal law can stand on the principle of the same harm revenge of &quot;An eye for an eye&quot;, there was a difference in punishment by the Identification. Besides that, there was agriculture and land, commercial, provisions of a number of fields, such as marriage. This era, traffic routes, such as canals and roads have been developed, commercial connecting cities flourished. In addition, silver is used as money, it is also known that the usurers industry had begun. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.86628970235488" SCORE="4.69097" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-4-20-1-9" RANK="19"> In Western countries strive to economic recovery, France, West Germany, the Benelux countries, Italy has launched the European Coal and Steel Community to co-manage the coal and steel industry in 1952 (ECSC). On the basis of the Treaty of Rome (1957) to extend this to all economic sectors, in '58 was organized European Economic Community and (EEC) European Atomic Energy Community body (EURATOM). This was an attempt to try to create a third economic bloc against the United States and the Soviet Union. Looking at the movement of the country, in the United Kingdom, established the Attlee Labour cabinet in 1945, was committed to the realization of the welfare state by the completion of the nationalization and social security systems of the important industry. In '56 fails to Eden Conservative Cabinet troops in Suez, further, such as by pound devaluation and withdrawal from the Suez east of when Wilson Labour Party of the Cabinet of the 1960s, the British influence in the world has been greatly reduced . In France, the fourth Republic was established in 1947, the Communist Party, Socialist Party, in opposition is political parties such as the People's Republican political situation is not stable, '58, and de Gaulle in the wake of the rebellion of Algeria troops but it came to power. De-goal, approved China in 1964, '66 to NATO military withdrawal mechanism (to return in '96), and the like, and developed its own diplomacy. He passed a fifth Republic constitution to strengthen the authority of the President, the acknowledged Algeria independence in '62. In West Germany, economic recovery, which is said to be under the Adenauer prime minister of the Christian Democratic Union &quot;miracle&quot; was accomplished. In 1955 and a member of the NATO, while proceeding with the re-armament, it was to restore the diplomatic relations with the Soviet Union. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.8654499246942964" SCORE="4.66081" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-16-01-0" RANK="20"> In this chapter, from after World War II until the early 1970s, is to target the world between the nearly quarter of a century. After the Second World War, but the realization of international peace order by the United Nations was expected, the world was split into East and West both sides centered on the United States and the Soviet Union both powers. East and West in Europe separation, after the armed conflict in Asia, confrontation of both sides will avoid a US-Soviet direct confrontation on the basis of the threat of nuclear, became a Cold War to each other direction is formed a global military block. From the newly independent countries of Asia and Africa, in order to protect the entrained not autonomous position in East-West confrontation, convocation of peace five principles of the proposed and Asia = Africa conference, attempts such as bringing together of non-alliance forces have been made. Many of colonial Africa, most independent in the 1960s. Third world of breakthrough, became an important feature of the post-war world. By assistance of the United States, in Japan and Western capitalist world, rapid economic recovery is realized from the 1950s, among the high-growth period over the subsequent 20 years, was shifted to the modern society of the American type. The Soviet Union after Stalin criticism, but turned to liberalization and peaceful coexistence route, the movement of the reform of the Eastern bloc I was sealed by force. Once in the '60s, the Soviet Union and the confrontation of China is intensifying, unity of socialist bloc is lost, also appeared signs of economic stagnation of the socialist bloc. On the other hand, the United States also been criticized from inside and outside intervention in the Vietnam War, we were faced with economic challenges and the EC. The early 1970s, initially Cold War loosened, by upset and the oil crisis of the United States, the world economy is headed into multipolarity, gap between industrialized and developing countries was serious as a North-South problem. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.8606308655406751" SCORE="4.49466" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-4-20-3-6" RANK="21"> Japan, which became a member of the Western capitalist camp, signed a new security treaty with the United States in 1960, was striving to economic development under the banner of the income doubling plan. Japan, the continued high economic growth in excess of 10% per annum from around '60, gross national product in around '68 became incidentally capitalist bloc second largest in the United States. As economic power increases, the relationship between the United States enters a new stage, Okinawa was returned to Japan in '72. Japan also signed a Southeast Asian countries and South Korea and the diplomatic relations were given the damage in pre-war and war do the compensation and economic assistance, Japanese companies began to play a foray into these countries. In South Korea, but was resigned Rhee growing pro-democracy movement centered on the students in 1960, Park Sei熙 has seized power in the following year of the military coup. Park administration, while taking the authoritarian political system, and then entered into a Japan-South Korea Basic Treaty in 1965 to strengthen the relationship between Japan, efforts to foster export industry by large-scale foreign investment. Southeast Asian countries also made the foundation for economic development in special demand of compensation and Vietnam war from Japan. In 1965, Suharto is annihilated Communist Party happening military coup (nine-thirty incidents), which led in Indonesia, Sukarno is ousted, Suharto embarked on economic development of the state-led. In the Philippines, Marcos becomes President in '65, the development was advanced under his dictatorship. In '67, it was formed Indonesia, Malaysia, Singapore, Philippines, five countries is the Association of Southeast Asian Nations of Thailand (ASEAN). This is the beginning, but the color of the anti-communist military alliance was darker, when it comes to the '70s, it began to migrate to the cooperation mechanism of the economic front. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.8591674264227052" SCORE="4.44642" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-3-10-0-0" RANK="22"> Early 1960s, young people foursome of music band was formed in Liverpool, England. Band name Beatles. Anger, affection of hunger, their rock music to express in a novel melody was captivated the hearts of 10-20 generations of young people of the world. Their hairstyle (long hair), even wacky fashion shown in clothes (G bread), had an impact on young people. Hairstyle, clothes, by items such as watches, shoes, bag, oriented to try to express the self of individuality, thereafter, became a feature of young people leading up to the modern times. 20 century since the late, there has been a remarkable thing in the development of communication technology. 60s the beginning, the universe relay is performed by the communication satellite, people began to be able to know the situation of other countries in real time. Underlying reason for the angry political transformation in Eastern European countries in 1989, goods are rich, for the Western countries that were thought to be free atmosphere, was a longing for Eastern Europe of the people. Such image of Western countries, and which was made by such as video by satellite broadcasting, even the communist government, it was not able to prevent up to radio waves. Century, PCs spread significantly, by using the Internet, financial, product became possible to get well video, music, a global scale culture information such literature. Highly developed capitalist society, under the consumer society, it was decided that food culture also globalization. Hamburger shop that are deployed on a global scale, at the coffee shop, people are now the same material, the food was made with the same recipe, the drink became so consumed by each city of the world. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.8585406615243948" SCORE="4.42606" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-4-20-4-6" RANK="23"> The oil crisis and the world recession of the 1970s was missing cut by streamlining of innovation and management Japan, continued stable growth of the economy. Since the 1960s South Korea and Taiwan, following the commodity and capital exports to Southeast Asia, economic relations with China deepened rapidly by mid normalization day in '72. 1978, Peace and Friendship Treaty was signed during the day. Japan became a member of the Summit in the 1970s, in '87 became the world's largest creditor nation. However, if exports to the United States, such as automobiles and electronic products is rapidly increasing, intensifying trade friction with the United States, demanding Japan bashing in the United States Congress and the mass media (Japan = bashing) it has been deployed. The United States government not only expanded imports of American products to Japan, it requested the transformation of economic structure. Rapid economic growth of Japan, had a major impact on the surrounding Asian countries. But it was followed by a military government in Korea, by industrialization that has linked the low wages and the introduction of foreign capital, was followed by economic growth that more than 10% per annum. 1980 to but happened Gwangju incident that armed crackdown democratization request movement of students and workers, in '87 declared the government is democracy, to enhance the international status to open the Olympic Games in Seoul in '88 It was. 1979, President Park was assassinated, then, Chun Doo Hwan of military origin, Roh Tae Woo became president. Thus South Korea by the end of the 1980s, Taiwan has undergone a similar economic growth, Singapore, has grown to be called Asia with Hong Kong NIES (newly industrialized economies). Southeast Asian ASEAN countries is subject to special demand of the Vietnam War, in conjunction with the capital investment and market expansion of Japan, it has developed a capitalist economy. However, expansion and environmental destruction of the gap between rich and poor on the back of economic development, of society, such as the collapse of traditional culture strain was also expanding. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.8585406615243948" SCORE="4.42606" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-4-20-3-1" RANK="24"> Between the late 1950s 60s, but &quot;peaceful coexistence&quot; to ease Cold War among the US-Soviet countries has been realized, in various parts of the world local wars and political change continued, also the economic gap between the north and south is also expanding, he went moving lily the international order of the post-war centered on the United States and the Soviet Union. When the authoritarian leader Stalin of the Soviet Union to death in 1953, the Soviet Union converted the foreign policy, in '55, against the Asia-Africa conference held Geneva 4 giant talks with the US, UK, France, and the West It showed a cooperative attitude. And, Khrushchev first secretary et al performs a Stalin criticism in 20th Congress of the Communist Party of the Soviet Union 56 years, launched a peaceful coexistence line with the West camp, Cominform was also disbanded. Thus, it appeared momentum of East-West detente, in '59 Khrushchev visited the United States, meeting with President Eisenhower and the camp = David was have. This detente has been called &quot;thaw&quot;. But in 1962, when the Soviet Union to build a missile base in Cuba, President Kennedy of the United States to seek its removal, it was sealed off Cuba from the sea. The Cuba crisis was fraught with danger of nuclear war broke out by the United States and the Soviet Union, crisis concessions Soviet Union has left. In addition, the '63 tied the US, UK, Soviet trilateral a partial nuclear test stop Treaty (PTBT), but detente has progressed greatly. The 1968 Nuclear Non-Proliferation Treaty (NPT) was signed. The possession of nuclear weapons, the United States, Soviet Union, United Kingdom, France, limited to China, the non-weapon states and prohibited the production and acquisition. Then the Soviet Union, Khrushchev in 1964 ousted in such failure of agricultural policy, Brezhnev became the first secretary (General Secretary of the later). Brezhnev regime, while taking the peaceful coexistence policy against the west, to strengthen the control of the domestic and Eastern European countries, has recommended the extension of the arms. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.855828042156911" SCORE="4.33995" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-3-17-2-4" RANK="25"> After the failure of the 1848 revolution, became the base of the forces that aim to the unification of Italy from above by political maneuvering, it was Sardinia kingdom with a center Piedmont of the Industrial Revolution. The Prime Minister Cavour is close to the British and French during the Crimean War, he defeated the Austrian army in 1859 signed a secret agreement with Napoleon III (Italy unification war). Sardinia kingdom is annexed Lombardy, in the next '60, instead of cede Savoy and Nice in France, was merged also central Italy. On the other hand, Garibaldi of radical faction in the youth from Italy, led Expedition of the Thousand (red shirt Corps) landed in Sicily, from the south occupied Naples (both Sicily) kingdom, deploy a unified movement that also involve the people did. Cavour who fear that momentum is to merge the hurry kingdom of Naples, a large part of Italy came under the control of the Sardinia Kingdom. Thus in 1861, the Kingdom of Italy that the king Vittorio = Emanuele II is satisfied. Italy, when Prussia and Austria is war (Prussian-Austrian war), in favor of Prussia were combined Venice, but occupied the Papal States by multiplying the war of Prussia and France, still under Austrian domination Trieste and South Tyrol and is called a &quot;non-recovery of Italy,&quot; and continued to request the recovery. In the unified nation that has been realized from the top, because the politics of northern center that developed industrial have been performed, in the southern Italian peasant revolt over five years continued, with the subsequent southern society in deep scar is left, inside Italy and north-south problem of economic disparity in have been included. The externally balance the forces established in the surrounding Mediterranean, after the end of the 19th century that was colonized the Red Sea coast of Eritrea, it is further failed by aiming at the colonization of Ethiopia, with the Ottoman Empire and the 20th century Tripoli and Cyrenaica in the war took the (now Libya) as a colony (Italy-Turkey war). </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.8481367235744773" SCORE="4.11224" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-4-20-3-8" RANK="26"> After the Second World War, following the United States of America to prosperity, Western Europe and Japan went steadily to restore the economy. These Western countries had against the Soviet sphere of economy, appeared on whether you are on track to development on the basis of the planned economy. In contrast, many of the post-war independent Asian and African countries, because it was subject to colonial rule over the years, economic development and lack of capital and technology does not proceed, it was called developing countries. In addition, even in Latin American countries, such as by industry dominated by bias and foreign capital of land ownership, instability of farmers of poverty and politics was followed. and advanced countries mainly located on the north side of the earth, to expand the gap between developing countries, which is located on the south side through the '60s, a state in which the north is economically to subordinate the south was called the North-South problem. 1964, the United Nations Conference on Trade and Development (UNCTAD) was established at the initiative of developing countries. Many of the North-South problem in facing the southern countries, in order to counter the North's economic domination, the Soviet Union and by political cooperation, was adopted socialist economic policies. However, economic aid from the Soviet Union is limited, economic development of these countries does not proceed, against the rich northern countries, it was followed by a composition that poor southern countries. Among them, the United States and from Japan was made a foothold of development by introducing a capital and technology, South Korea, Taiwan, Thailand, Malaysia, was such as Singapore. These countries when it comes to the 1970s succeeded in economic development, came to be known as NIES (newly industrialized economies). The oil-producing countries such as Iran and Saudi Arabia, it becomes to manage the oil resources in the country, it has accumulated an enormous amount of foreign currency. 1960, major oil-producing countries was formed the Organization of the Petroleum Exporting Countries (OPEC) in order to compete with international oil capital. And countries that have succeeded in these oil-producing countries and economic development, a large economic disparities between the take remaining country has occurred, which was called South-South problem. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.8481367235744773" SCORE="4.11224" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-2-9-1-6" RANK="27"> Ben Kyoto Kaifeng Prefecture is located at the node of the Grand Canal which extends to the Yellow River from the north and south. This economic advantage, after that ruined the Tang empire, was chosen as the capital from the Five Dynasties to the Northern Song Dynasty is neither in Luoyang in Changan, was this opening. The Song Dynasty, Ouchi consisting Miyagi and Grand Noble (government district), its outer Uchijiro (Old Castle), and around 26km or so of outside Castle (New City), and growth in the walled city which is surrounded by triple walls of did. The population was 60-70 million people in the only castle. On the periphery of each city walls, moat of the canal also serves is Megurasa, these, and some of Ogawa drawn into Ben river (Tsusumikawa) and the castle across the castle, had been functionally linked. Thus capital opening, the size of the ship full of large amounts of goods to buy go to the canal, was thriving as a metropolis of commerce and consumption. Speaking of Tang long Anjo, downtown and is only two of Bow that Higashi-shi and West City, it also, and Bomon is closed and facing a sunset, I had to hurry to going out of business. The opening to this, immediately highway Koji on the outside has become a variety of shopping street, also downtown, such as restaurants, liquor store, Giro and inns is join the eaves of Ouchi is, all over the Uchijiro it was in. Moreover, according to the &quot;Tokyo Yumehana-roku&quot; Meng Senate, even the &quot;Night Market&quot; in the late-night it is, was proudly opened in various places. Even in a private road of the emperor leading South Gate of Ouchi from (Sentoku-mon) to Uchijiro (Suzakumon), on its both sides, stalls were lined. And it proceeds down this road further south, when passing through the Suzakumon past the state bridge according to Ben river, leading to the dragon of Tojo Tsubashi. The streets of this north-south, fried or boiled meat, fish, tofu and vegetables, restaurant that sells like candy Toka ice water has a row, in the center of the &quot;State Bridge Night Market&quot;, and the hustle and bustle until midnight It was not interrupted. Moved instead of the times of &quot;the toe to Song&quot; may means inquires from such a surface. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.8454448007472699" SCORE="4.0378" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-01-03-3" RANK="28"> Great was gracchi is a sense of crisis to military power reduction due to the downfall of the farmers, and is chosen to protect the people and government in succession (brother before 133 years, brother before 123 - 122 years), and confiscated a large land owner of the land We tried to distribute in Musan citizen. But reform will fail love the opposite of large landowners, brother killed brother committed suicide. Thereafter influential politicians, suffers many as under the private patronage people, each other using them and now compete in the violence, Rome was plunged into &quot;a century of civil war.&quot; When you enter a century ago, the army becomes a private army of influential people is make attracting Musan citizen, Sula Marius and clan faction of commoner faction was fighting led each other private army. The alliance Italian cities peninsula was revolted in search of Roman citizenship (before 91 to before '88). Furthermore sword guy that was used in spectacle to cause large rebellion headed to Spartacus (before 73 to the previous 71) years, such as civil war has reached the apex. The Kenyakkokenyakko, slaves presentations and showing or fighting with each other duel or beast. Figure Lion and cattle, such as the fight Kenyakko. The people asked for entertainment in this way bloody spectacle. From the 4th century mosaic. Of this confusion submerged by armed was the influential person Pompey Caesar, Crassus. They previous 60 years, against the Senate and the clan faction signed a private political alliance, came to power (1st Triumvirate). Then Caesar won the leadership by the success of Gaul (France of today) expedition, unified the world before '46 to defeat political opponents Pompey. He served in the stabilization of society is appointed dictator in succession, give a great deal of popularity in people. But because it showed a momentum that ignoring the Senate become dictator, was assassinated in Buruto~usu et al before '44 Senate Republican, politics was confused again. The following year, men of Caesar Antonius and Lepidus, adoptive Octavian Caesar was holding the clan faction again signed a political alliance (2nd Triumvirate). Eventually Octavian is defeated Battle of Actium in '31 before the Antonius that connects the Egyptian queen Cleopatra, Ptolemy morning became destroyed is in province of Rome. Here in the Mediterranean is pacified, civil war told the end. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.8425520941219542" SCORE="3.96059" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-4-20-1-3" RANK="29"> When World War II ended, the United States has the world's strongest military force as the only atomic bomb weapons states, had become a country that has an overwhelming economic power to dramatically develop the industrial power during the war . The United States and owns nearly 70 percent of the total world gold, accounting for nearly 60 percent of the industrial production. Reconstruction initiative of the United States of the international economy, was achieved by the establishment of one International Bank for Reconstruction and Development and the International Monetary Fund (IMF) is a specialized agency of the United Nations (IBRD, World Bank). In the post-war framework of international economy has been discussed in the 1944 Bretton Woods conference =, the United States played a major role. The international economic system centered on the dollar of the United States that the Bretton Woods system =. Thus, the exchange ratio of the national currency (exchange rate) is fixed, the United States currency dollar that has been guaranteed the exchange of gold becomes an international reserve currency, and the mechanism of assistance to the new development and the post-war economic reconstruction but it has been developed. In '48, launched General Agreement on Tariffs and Trade (GATT) is, trade order, which stood on the principle of liberalism has been aimed. Also in '47, when the United States announced the Marshall Plan = (European Economic Recovery Assistance Program), Western countries to accept this, formed the European Economic Cooperation (OEEC) in '48. 1961, it was reorganized in Organization for Economic Cooperation and Development (OECD). Thus, the framework of a new international economy centered on the United States were being made, different Soviet of the economic system is, refused to participate in this system. The plethora of food, wide housing, the image of the rich civic life surrounded by electrical appliances and automobiles tied and prosperity of the United States, it was advertised to the world through movies and newspaper and magazine cartoons. The United States, by exclusively providing information through the mass media, tried to attract the world of the people in the United States. In addition, a number of excellent scholars and intellectuals from large pre-war is, had moved to the United States from Europe, after the war this trend continues, the University of the United States has become a center of academic and science and technology development, is the word of the United States English There it was to be a common word in the world. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.8302317725778724" SCORE="3.66062" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-4-20-3-4" RANK="30"> In Vietnam, it forced the authoritarian the original to the anti-communist policy of support in the south of the regime is the United States, has increased anti-American and anti-government movement against this. In 1960, it was formed south Vietnam release National Front, was to expand the guerrilla war with the support of the north of Vietnam Democratic Republic (North Vietnam). In the United States, Kennedy was appointed president in 1961, took the aggressive policy over the inside and outside. Takes the attitude of the whole area confrontation with the Soviet Union during the Cuban Missile Crisis, it began to intervene in the Vietnam War. Kennedy is assassinated in 63 end of the year, the President Johnson took over a trail, it is believed to communism as adjacent countries also domino if Ochire in the hands of South Vietnam is communist side, to set a &quot;free world of defense&quot;, It was full-scale military intervention. Although Gulf of Tonkin incident of 1964 became the catalyst for full-fledged intervention, it was found that later it was hoax. '65 Or later, while adding a large-scale bombing (Kita爆) to the north Vietnam, it was charged the army of the maximum time of 500 000 to the south Vietnam. On the other hand, the Soviet Union and China have carried out massive military and economic aid to the Liberation Front and North Vietnam. Therefore, Vietnam war was prolonged, it becomes the largest of the war after the Second World War, lives of several million is lost. The late Vietnam 1960s has bogged down the war, the anti-war movement against the United States military intervention in Vietnam is spread all over the world, the United States government has been exposed to harsh criticism. In addition, it challenges the governments and the existing system, which has been supporting the United States, &quot;protest of young people&quot;, which centered on the students was uplifting in European countries and Japan. In France, in 1968, students, workers, and developed a large-scale movement of citizens is called &quot;May Crisis&quot;. Many of the young people participated in the anti-war movement in the United States, spread also the movement of the draft rejected. The civil rights movement to request the right of as opposed to citizens in black discrimination also becomes actively, but the Civil Rights Act was established in '64, Martin Luther King is assassinated in '68, confusion was intensified. In this way, American society of the 1960s ran shaking big. In the United States who received a serious blow to economical vast war, in 1968, President Johnson gave up the re-election, President Nixon of the next Republican to reduce the military intervention in Vietnam in '69, in '73 established the Paris peace agreement, US forces withdrew. '75, Liberation Front and the North Vietnamese army is allowed to fall to Saigon (now Ho Chi Minh City), was conquered South Vietnam throughout. Vietnam Republic collapsed, the next day in '76, Vietnam Socialist Republic was established to implement the North-South unification. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.822292113813869" SCORE="3.48886" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-3-13-3-1" RANK="31"> Qing Dynasty, reached the golden age in the era of Kan熙-Yongzheng-dry Ryuzo Emperor. Kangxi (Kiyoshiso), the Han became the Han-o of Yunnan by subsumption in Qing warlords, such as Wu Sangui has quelled the revolt that caused Canaan (three clan of the run). In that time Taiwan, the Dutch built a citadel, and had tried to occupation of the land, was the base of HanKiyoshi forces Tay success of Ming surviving retainer is to destroyer this. Zheng Chenggong is, from the royal family that has been fielded in the light of the surviving retainer (To-o), allowed to ride name a bright country surname &quot;Zhu&quot;, got the nickname of Kuniseiji. 18 of the century chikamatsu monzaemon which was announced at the beginning Joruri &quot;Kunisei (sex) old man battle&quot; is one that was dramatized this vestige. Therefore Qing, took countermeasures, such as forcibly relocate residents of coastal areas to the hinterland (1661 遷界 old). This Mr. Zheng Taiwan three generations '22 and lasted but down to the Kangxi (1683), Taiwan was added to the Qing Dynasty of the territory here. In Central Asia, it is Junggar had stretched a incidentally force received a Oirato of the Ming Dynasty, Kangxi is pacified This led his own army, housed in the territory of the empire the Mongolian Plateau, Tibet, Qinghai provinces, following Yongzheng Emperor but we have established a dominance that. This expansion policy, the Qing this means you are each other direction as Russia, which measure the south, era in Nerchinsk Treaty of Kangxi, then Kyakhta treaty is tied to the era of the Yongzheng Emperor, ambit of sphere of influence has been set. Continued Qianlong is conquered by dispatching army Tianshan Mountains north of Junggar and it south of Islamization was Uighur land of (times part), was this area &quot;new area&quot; and (Xinjiang), also Taiwan - like to me was troops also Vietnam, Burma (now Myanmar). Thus, the second half of the 18th century, the Qing will be to win the Chinese Empire in history, the largest of a hunt, Qianlong was enjoying the reign of up to reign in '60. The vast territory of the Qing Empire, was ruled separately in the clan section and the headquarters (under the direct control point). Headquarters and is made up from a straight 隷省 and ministries of local metropolitan area, the clan section is a region, such as has been conquered or consolidation one after another Junggar-times part Tibet, Lifan Yuan to manage the clan section It was established. The three northeastern provinces and Xinjiang (now Xinjiang) were added and 21 Ministry of the 1882 installation. &quot;Saving&quot; is derived from it was the original local government system &quot;row Chu-sho Ministry&quot;. In Tibet, by Je Tsongkhapa in the 14th century it is performed reform of Buddhism, was born newly Guelph faction (yellow hat sect). Then, his lineage of Sheikh (Dalai Lama =) came to church and state both rights. Large area of ​​the Qing Dynasty, which consists of headquarters and clan part, overlap with the local name of &quot;China&quot; of today, also the Qing Dynasty of customs and culture, it became the source of the image of &quot;Chinese&quot;. From this large territory, Primorye of Ussuri east and (Russian territory) is the region excluding the Mongolian plateau north zone (Mongolia), overlaps in nearly current of the People's Republic of China and Taiwan range. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.7980248296481709" SCORE="3.0455" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-16-03-1" RANK="32"> In between the Asian and African countries, confrontation of East and West both sides are brought to Asia and Africa, to see a situation where the Korean War and the Indochina war is resolved in the United States and the Soviet Union-led, to strengthen the independence, to try to form a third force tide that it is assumed that was born. 1954, gathered in five South Asian countries leaders Colombo such as India, Asian and African countries meeting held, we propose a nuclear test stop, also China's Zhou Enlai prime minister has announced a peace five principles can be met with Nehru Prime Minister of India . Five principles, respect for territorial integrity and sovereignty, non-aggression, non-interference in internal affairs, equality and mutual benefit, and peaceful coexistence. Next '55, meeting representatives of the Asia-Africa 29 countries participated in Indonesia of Bandung (Asia = Africa conference &lt;Bandung conference&gt;) is opened ten principles sang the peaceful coexistence and anti-colonialism was adopted. In addition, without involving Asia, Africa and Latin American countries in the US-Soviet confrontation, to put together in a position of active neutrality as third world, such as the 1961 Yugoslavia interrogation first Kaihi the participating 25 countries in Belgrade allies summit meeting was held. The conference, peaceful coexistence, support of national liberation, and to declare a break of colonialism, has vowed to take a joint pace. In Egypt, in 1952, Naguib-Nasser et al., Led officer delegation defeat the monarchy, was established well in '53 Republic (Egypt revolution). Shortly When Nasser becomes president, and cast a positive policy of neutrality, to take a direction to approach the socialist countries, it was aimed at the construction of the Aswan = High Dam in order to promote the domestic modernization. UK, the United States in opposition to diplomatic posture of the nacelle, has stopped economic aid to Egypt. Nasser in 1956, declared the nationalization of the Suez Canal in order to obtain the dam construction funds. On the other hand the United Kingdom, France, Israel, caused the military action in Egypt (Suez war, the second Middle East War). However, this behavior leads to criticism of the international public opinion, because even America and the Soviet Union has warned, the three countries withdrew. Egypt After this went to the leading position of Arab nationalism. In North Africa under French domination, Tunisia, Morocco, in 1956 became independent. In Algeria, and resisting the French settlers and local military independently, but was followed by armed conflict in between the National Liberation Front (FLN), independence was achieved in '62. Other 1957 in colonial Africa, including Ghana and Nkrumah to the leaders became the first of their own independent black republic, in '60 born 17 things newly independent countries in one fell swoop, this year is &quot;Africa I was called the year, &quot;he said. Nkrumah to request an immediate independent en car Ghana that speech is, the place where wields spiel before the people. '63, 30 countries participated in the Ethiopia of African countries summit held in Addis Ababa, and formed the Organization of African Unity (OAU), African countries of solidarity, aimed at overcoming of colonialism. However, the colony is still the rest of Portugal, some of the economic interests do not want to let go of the old home country after independence as Belgium also interfere, was also example that caused the Congo Crisis. Newly independent countries of the economy, because that have been developed along the economic interests of the colonial weapons states, the foundation of self-reliance was weak. Moreover, in many areas, social infrastructure (basic livelihood), such as transportation networks and electricity, water, social institutions such as education and medical care had not been almost maintenance. Therefore, political and economic after independence also unstable, is repeated civil wars and coup by conflict of tribalism, the military dictatorship has often appeared. The initial momentum of the newly independent nation is lost, the direction aimed at modernization by the assistance of Western countries became dominant. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.7768643560509949" SCORE="2.73526" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-16-02-3" RANK="33"> After the war, in the United States, against the background of the self-confidence of the military and economic power of the country, has increased claimed to be that we should be teaching the international community against the Soviet Union. In 1947 in Japan, Taft-Hartley Act to restrict the trade union activities on behalf of the Wagner Act was enacted, and frustration is intensified by prolonged atomic bomb possession and the Korean War of the Soviet Union, pursue leftist movement and communist ideology movement to (&quot;Red Scare&quot;) appeared. Republican Senator McCarthy (1909-57) is, because stood at the beginning of the idea pursue activities of intellectuals and civil servants, this trend was also called McCarthyism. Eisenhower Republican was elected in the 1952 presidential election, while maintaining the framework of the Cold War, and to terminate the Korean War, tried to Susumeyo a dialogue with the Soviet Union. The US economy had continued a steady growth, it as been placed in the shadow of prosperity to this, from among the blacks who had suffered discrimination, spread the movement seeking equal civil rights. Marshall = Western European countries of the economic recovery that has received the assistance of the plan is remarkable, was followed by a high economic growth rate 1950-70 20 years years. The average economic growth rate of developed countries (%) economic growth rate of the 1950-70's, it found to be those who stand out among the 20 century. In Western Europe sandwiched between the US and the Soviet Union, in order to revive the economy and standing in the reflection of the two world wars, to manage jointly the energy resources and industrial resources, appeared initiative to try to prevent a conflict of mutual . 1952, at the suggestion of the French Foreign Minister Schuman (Schuman = plan), France and West Germany, the Benelux countries and Italy was inaugurated European Coal and Steel Community body (ECSC). This movement, is prompted to conflict with the Soviet Union socialist bloc, the European Economic Community in '58 (EEC), and developed it into the establishment of the European Atomic Energy Community (EURATOM), mutual reduction of tariffs, joint commercial and agricultural policy, the liberalization of capital and labor movement was implemented. In '67, three communities merged European Community (EC) next, the foundation of Western European integration was made. 1958 In France, the fourth Republic falls down without being able to resolve the Algerian independence problem, was changed to the fifth Republic. De-goal became the President recognized the independence of Algeria, was the fourth nuclear power in France. Further approved a 64 year country, in '66, such as refuse military cooperation to NATO, insisted its own position in between the United States and the Soviet Union. West Germany has achieved economic growth that has been called under the Adenauer &quot;miracle&quot;. '66 Of the results of the election, a large coalition government is established by adding the Social Democratic Party to such as the Christian Democratic Union. Britain does not participate in the EEC, it was against it have formed the Free Trade Association (EFTA) 1960 年 Europe. When the Wilson Cabinet is satisfied with victory Labor Party in the '64 election, and decided to withdrawal from the Suez Ito, also running the pound devaluation from the economic crisis. Japan after the outbreak of the Korean War, received pull the goods supply to the United Nations Army (Korea special demand), was dramatically develop the industrial production. 1955 to be satisfied Liberal Democratic Party, we were able regime taking power over the subsequent long-term. '56, Restored diplomatic relations with the Soviet Union, also in the same year by a member to the United Nations, was a return to the international community. 1960 (1960) is revised US Treaty of Mutual Cooperation and Security day a year, but the US between the ties of the day has been strengthened, violent confrontation occurred Concerning revision in Japan. In fart the high economic growth period of the 1960s, Japan became a member of the industrialized countries. The average economic growth rate of developed countries (%) economic growth rate of the 1950-70's, it found to be those who stand out among the 20 century. It should be noted that, in 1965, Japan signed a Korea and NichiKan basic treaty, was realized the normalization of diplomatic relations. At the end of the 1960s, in France, such as Western Europe and developed countries West Germany Japan, and the post-war political and social system, the student movement and the labor movement that has criticized the deviation between the Social Transformation by economic growth spread. The '69 French-de-Gaulle is deposed, and government is satisfied that the prime minister blunt after the war the first time the Social Democrats in West Germany, began a review of post-war politics. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.7362573706541804" SCORE="2.27409" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-3-7-3-8" RANK="34"> Changes in the early 19th century to 20 century society. The first half of the 20th century, in between the human race only 30 years, experienced a world war over two degrees. The war transformed the fate of countless people, the devastation was left a deep scar in various parts of the world. The result of the two wars, the direction of the subsequent history of the various regions decisive, it is no exaggeration to say has been a big influence factor the history of people, and until today. 20 century early 1901, which opened the curtain, I finished life of British Queen Victoria was over the reign 60 Toshi-yo. The funeral has attended from most of the royal family of Europe, yet by many of relatives or in-laws relationship, it had been connected to the queen. Prestige of Queen Victoria, as indicated by the word Pax Britannica, was to symbolize the mighty forces of the British Empire that has reigned on top of the world order in the 19th century. Then within just a '20 less than, fighting countries is divided down the middle of the camp, yet As a result, it is to become a thing to turn off the beginning Austria, figure major dynasty, such as Russia and Germany, who was expected I wonder. However, the beginning of the 20th century, mainly in Europe, while the various regions of the world Yuku are linked by a close relationship, deep cracks that occur there was also the era has come to reveal. Unified completion of the German Empire, which was against the background of the Prussian forces, coupled with the remarkable development of the industry, was intended to shake the British position, which stood on the balance of power of the European powers. Powers, while exploring each other of new alliances, and compete with and enhance the military, with the aim of ensuring the exclusive market for infrastructure enhancements and economic expansion of the country's industry, went embarked on colonial acquisition. As seen in the previous chapter, in Europe, it was while born two camps to conflict that Tripartite Pact and the Triple Entente. Such movement criticized by imperialism a four, also movement of socialism complaining of international solidarity and anti-war workers of countries had been organized. For Socialists, the interests of the industry by the development of capitalism what, was something that produces conflict of national or ethnic. However, conflict of countries to stimulate the national consciousness of the people, xenophobia of ethnocentric has often driven a lot of people in frenzy. Mainly in Germany, 19th century nationalism, the direction of national formation as a community of ethnic groups that share a language and culture, has become a thing of strengthening. The Austro-Hungarian Empire and the Ottoman Empire, as a legacy of the great powers that troubled the inner diverse ethnic groups, was shaken to the movement of the various ethnic groups for ejecting. Especially in the Balkans, by interventions such as various ethnic independence and Russia multiplied in it, it showed a very unstable aspects. Among the colonial competition of European powers becomes violently, in various places resistance to expansion of powers has occurred in a variety. Sudan and Mahdi movement that happened at the end of the 19th century, century Boxer Rebellion in China at the turn of the shows the various aspects of the people's resistance. These developments, as well as to shake the established authority of each region, was supposed to be to explored the way of the new order to the people. Until where the system such as the dynasty domination had been established in its own way, the first in many cases strengthening of the framework or restructuring was required. However, in many cases, the old regime is brittle against the advance of the European forces, and collapsed to remain not be shown sufficient resistance, or deprived of their rights and interests in the activities of the active industrial and capital of Europe, Kumiko in the world I went rare. The end of the 19th century, not only in Europe of industrial technology, movement to Toriireyo thought and institutions, the constitutional system, particularly linking the nation and the people by the Constitution and the Congress, as well as some reformers, young intellectuals of those countries It had come to capture widely, and the like. Youth in the Ottoman Empire Turkey, Sun Yat-sen these activities in China, was intended to be representative of such new generation. But, in the Ottoman Empire and the Qing Dynasty and the European countries face a vast area of ​​heterogeneous China, or will of the nations and peoples of the framework is where the demand. After the Young Turk revolution, strengthened gradually Turkish nationalism in the Ottoman Empire, Empire went fraught with crisis of dismantling. China's Sun Yat-sen, also by warlords defending local authority after the Xinhai Revolution, had to experience the long civil war. National, ethnic formation, in the non-European world, was not in any way be self-evident. This early 20th century, Japan had already realized the imperial constitutional framework, are troops in Beijing along with the Western countries in the Boxer Rebellion, it was beginning to enter the corner of powers. 1902 of the Anglo-Japanese Alliance was so to speak a clear ranks of the imperialist countries. Soon, Japan by fart the Russo-Japanese War, Yuku proceed to the annexation of Korea. </PASSAGE>
    </PASSAGE_SET>
  </TOPIC>
  <TOPIC ID="D792W10-14">
    <PASSAGE_SET>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.9805603849667258" SCORE="32.7384" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-4-20-3-5" RANK="1"> traditional values ​​of the United States society by the Vietnam anti-war movement growing fluctuation, doubt has been cast on the richness of life, which is determined by the economic efficiency in the first place. In 1969 the New York suburb of Woodstock, a concert of rock and folk songs was held under the banner of the Vietnam anti-war. 3 consecutive days 30-400000 young people gathered, Woodstock became the land of the young people of the legend of this era. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.9700557690406584" SCORE="21.2445" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-3-9-3-7" RANK="2"> Vietnam war while is called the movement of the anti-war around the world, it gave towards the eyes of many of the people in the third world. The movement in the United States violently, happened military service refused. On the other hand, young people's behavior and life style called hippie has spread to Western Europe and Japan. Traditional values ​​of American society is fluctuation, it was cast doubt on the &quot;richness&quot; of the life you are prompted for economic efficiency and convenience in the first. In August 1969, in the New York suburb of Woodstock, a concert of rock and folk song it has been opened under the banner of the Vietnam anti-war. This concert is over three days, most of the gathered men and women from the early 20s 10 Dai-matsu which is said to daily 300 000 to 400 000, Woodstock has become a place of legend for the young people of the era of the Vietnam War. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.9598934329885201" SCORE="15.8522" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-14-02-2" RANK="3"> In the Pacific Ocean region, then to Spain, Portugal, the Netherlands, when it comes to the 18th century entered the United Kingdom, France, Germany and the United States has advanced to the 19th century. Powers of the sphere of influence in the Pacific Ocean (early 20th century) Australia becomes the British in the late 18th century, the beginning has been a penal colony, then freedom immigration also joined, after the gold mine discovery of the mid-19th century, it was rapidly developing. Powers of the sphere of influence in the Pacific Ocean (early 20th century) UK, was territorial also part of the New Zealand and North Borneo New Guinea. Powers of the sphere of influence in the Pacific Ocean (early 20th century) In this process, in Australia Aboriginal indigenous people are busy hinterland, the resistance of the Maori have been held down by force in New Zealand. Germany also, since the 1880s, Bismarck Islands (part of Melanesia), won the Caroline Mariana Marshall Palau Islands (Micronesia). Powers of the sphere of influence in the Pacific Ocean (early 20th century) The United States in 1898 the United States = Spain of war result, won the Philippines, Guam from Spain, also Hawaii was also annexed the same year. Hawaii last queen Lili Walsh Kalani Hawaii kingdom 1840 years, but was a constitutional monarchy, Queen Liliuokalani in the pressure of the United States in 1893 are deposed, it was annexed in 1998. Islands scattered in the South Pacific (Melanesia, Polynesia) also, has been divided into the United Kingdom, France, the United States until the early 20th century. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.9562235843589234" SCORE="14.5196" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-S-3-10-4-10" RANK="4"> The region in which the combined islands and Australia's top indigenous Pacific Ocean called Oceania. Australian and indigenous (Aboriginal), Papua New Guinea of ​​human's ancestors, emigrated from Southeast Asia before about 30,000 years, there seems to be related to the Dravidian people of India. Ancestor of Polynesia and Micronesia of people, 6000 - was moved from Southeast Asia to 3000 years ago. Oceania of people without knowing the metal until the 19th century, we had to use stone tools and pottery, fish bones and shellfish. In addition to fishing in many of the island, but agriculture such as the cultivation of potatoes has been performed, Aboriginal had done the only hunting and collecting. Full-fledged foray of Europeans began in the 18th century. After the Cook expedition, British Australia from the late 18th century, including the colonists in New Zealand, later France, also, such as the United States has advanced. They may be provided a fishing base, in addition to was the collection of wood and seafood and groundwater resources, is at good climate he engaged in agriculture and depriving the indigenous people of the land. Europeans and Americans or abuse the indigenous people as the labor force, was causative in other island as slaves. A large number of indigenous people had also died in the pathogen. Tasmania indigenous people were wiped out, lore is lost population is reduced to extreme in the Easter Island, the character of this island has not been deciphered yet. In the late 19th century with the independent colony, also the wave of colonial competition is surging in the region, it was the independent country Hawaii became a US territory. Japan also won the part of Micronesia after the First World War. In the Second World War Japan fought with Allied in a wide range of Oceania, many who were killed in local residents. Since the 1960s, independent of colonial was followed by Oceania throughout. In New Zealand and Australia, the British were also increased momentum to attempt to return the land and rights that took from the indigenous people. However, as compared to Euro residents indigenous people are difficult to become equal in education and employment, on the other hand, in the case such as Hawaii indigenous people has become comparable to other residents, and to maintain the indigenous traditions and pride it has become difficult. Newly independent islands, with a population of 100,000 or less small country a lot, suffer from political, economic many problems. But, currently, a small nation in the region, has become to have a big say against destruction of nuclear testing and the natural environment in the South Pacific of major powers, it has become the presence that can not be ignored by the international community. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.9549350097039162" SCORE="14.1031" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-2-4-3-11" RANK="5"> Also in this period, Australia and Canada began to form as a new immigration colony. Australia, east coast part has been found by the late 18th century Cook of exploration voyage. After the United States 13 states of independence, is a British penal colony to replace it, in 1788, the basis of colonial was built in Sydney today. In Canada, after the United States similarly independent, such as the colonists to support the King of England has moved much from 13 states. They went separately, open a new colony it until the settlement of French residents who had moved into the center of Quebec. These land, eventually ties with the home country of industrial development, was expanded to attract a lot of immigrants. But, it is, Australia indigenous people (called Aboriginal), and was supposed to destroy the society of Canada's indigenous people (Indians and Inuit people) are exposed to change. In addition, Australia's development, coupled with the expansion of the European force in the Asia-Pacific Ocean region, was supposed to encourage the division as a colony of the South Pacific Islands. The movement, starting with the New Zealand sovereignty by 1840 of the United Kingdom, advancing rapidly from the 19th century Nakaba. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.9504924053384793" SCORE="12.8331" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-S-1-3-2-1" RANK="6"> Qin was in the frontier of the west to the Warring States period, the government has destroyed the other countries at the time of the king, the first time achieved a unified before 221 years. He created a nickname that the emperor more than the king (Qin Shi Huang), put the capital in Xianyang (near Xian current). Is divided into several counties across the country, place the province under that, it was the county Prefecture regulations that govern directly by sending the bureaucracy from the center. This system, as a mechanism of basic domination whose vertices the emperor, survived until the early 20th century. Qin Shi Huang in order to dominate the whole country, and established a national road, aimed weights and measures and currency, the unification of such character. In addition, we will respect the spirit of the Hoka, was severely punished. The discarded burn a book inconsistent with his politics, was buried alive and Confucian that conflict with Hoka (burning of books and burying of scholars). Externally, it rejected the Xiongnu is a nomadic equestrian people of the north, and prevented the invasion put in place the Great Wall. In the south and placed the county stretched out power to the northern part of Vietnam. Thus finished almost region of mainland China of today, dione Qin became under the English &quot;China&quot;. But Shi Huangdi of large civil works and successive wars that went, it tormented the farmers, the severe political and rapid reform, led the rebound of local influential people since the Warring States. Then, when Qin Shi Huang die, farmers and local influential people have revolted, Qin perished before 206 years. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.9482599746688143" SCORE="12.2771" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-02-03-9" RANK="7"> In fart the era of upheaval of the Spring and Autumn - Warring States, Qin, Han in the timing of, the huge scale of the state that was the apex of the emperor was crafted in China. Bureaucracy and this emperor governance, supported by Confucianism is, then the 20th century during the two thousand years or so is up to the Qing Dynasty of the destruction of the beginning, it became the basis of the national system of China. The presence of China is also known to the west such as through this time India, currently, China China in Europe and the United States (English), you are reading and the like Shi~in (French) is, if traced the etymology of the dynasty name &quot;Qin&quot; It derived to. In addition to that, such as &quot;Han&quot;, &quot;Kanji&quot; in East Asian cultural sphere of today, dynasty name &quot;Han&quot; is that used as a word to represent the Chinese culture today. This time to spread knowledge to the world on the side of China. Transmitted to the west of the situation in China by the Western Han Dynasty of Zhang Qian and rear Han Han than that was sent to Central Asia, now also the presence of the major powers of the Roman Empire (Daqin) is known. The middle of the second century, (in China historical materials &quot;Daqin King AnAtsushi&quot;) Roman emperor that is the envoy was dispatched to China led to Nichinan County by sea (now Central Vietnam). It is a thing of the Roman emperor Marcus Aurelius = = Antoninus. Also exchanges with East Asian interior of the surrounding area became popular, came to be carried out be positioned among the order of the emperor center by giving a title, such as a king in the Emirates. That the messenger of Wajin (Japanese) have received a gold seal of the &quot;Han committee guy King&quot; from Emperor Guangwu is its one example. This gold seal that was discovered in Shikanoshima of gold mark Fukuoka Prefecture, character of &quot;Han committee guy king&quot; has been engraved. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.9463794784566986" SCORE="11.8446" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-3-18-2-11" RANK="8"> Australia continent, several tens of thousand years ago, still indigenous Aborigines who emigrated to time, which has been connected with the Asian continent and the land is, for a long time, had retained its own culture. The late 18th century, by the Cook voyage, become New South Wales is the colony of the United Kingdom, the United Kingdom was fed a large amount of convicts to this land. Immigrants went recommend the development of inland while rid the Aboriginal. When you enter the 19th century, the discovery of the success and the gold mine of the sheep industry, immigration is increasing rapidly, development has proceeded at once. 1901, the Commonwealth of Australia is formed, but his Dominions, long HakuTsuyoshi principle is adherence, as Europe among Asia, played a British agency functions. Caucasian centricity that lasted until the 1970s in Australia. To prevent the entry of Asian immigrants in such language test, it was carried out blatant discrimination policy in the country. New Zealand became a British colony in the 1840s, but Maori indigenous has resisted fierce armed struggle, it has been put down. 19th century in the second half of the sheep industry development, the beginning of the 20th century it became a dominion. South Pacific region, north Hawaiian Islands, southwest New Guinea island, southeast in the broad waters leading to Easter Island, the first people to emigrate to 30,000 years ago, through around the 10th century from around 6000 years ago, Austronesian word system of people emigrated to manipulate the canoe, it had been established. Is a Cook's voyage after the its details are known to the Europeans. The same time, a major islands unified kingship had while established. However, from the early 19th century, the United Kingdom Fiji, Papua, France is sovereignty over Tahiti, New Caledonia, the United States annexed Hawaii. The end of the 19th century, Spain ceded Guam to the United States, also other Mariana was sold to Germany, colonization of the Pacific Ocean Islands whole area has been established. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.942382059300263" SCORE="11.0188" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-4-20-1-7" RANK="9"> 1947, the United States, in order to prevent the penetration of communist force in the Americas, and signed a Latin American countries and the Inter-American joint defense treaty (Rio de Janeiro Convention), the following year was launched the Organization of American States (OAS). People's Republic of China is established in 1949, when the Korean War takes place in '50, the United States was to expand the &quot;containment policy&quot; is also in the Asia-Pacific Ocean region. The United States, the Philippines and the US ratio mutual defense treaty in '51, Australia, signed a New Zealand and the Pacific Ocean Security Treaty (ANZUS). In addition, it signed a US-Japan security treaty between Japan regained independence in '51, was stationed continue the US military in Japan. UN forces to achieve a cease-fire of the Korean War in July 1953 but withdrew from the Korean Peninsula, the United States signed a BeiKan mutual defense treaty, were allowed to continue stationed in South Korea to the US military. The next '54 passed a Southeast Asia Treaty Organization (SEATO), and entered into a Sino-American Mutual Defense Treaty also between the Taiwan. In '55, Turkey, Iraq, United Kingdom, Pakistan, the Middle East to join the five countries of Iran (Baghdad) is allowed to establish a Treaty Organization (METO), and Iraq to leave by the '58 revolution, the United States is it a central treaty It was re-organized into a mechanism (CENTO). The United States in this way, in the 1950s, Tsukuriageta also a military regime that surrounds the socialist countries around the Sino-Soviet in the Asia-Pacific Ocean region. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.9384815178326601" SCORE="10.3162" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-14-01-2" RANK="10"> United Kingdom that has been referred to as the &quot;world factory&quot; in the 19th century Nakaba is, against the background of the superiority of the overwhelming naval power, was forced to free trade around the world. Therefore, in Japan, has advocated even colonial unnecessary theory, British colony was also expanded this later. The United Kingdom, in order to maintain a colonial empire, the dominant direct in non-White colonial, many colony of white settlers, as in Canada, was subjected to indirect domination in the Dominion. 1870s and later, in the face of competition with the global recession and other industrialized countries, Disraeli Prime Minister of the Conservative Party is the acquisition of shares of the Suez Canal Company (1875) grip the canal of management rights, Russia = Turkey ( Russo) to interfere in the war, it was to secure the road to India. Britain, which was placed under the control of Egypt in the 1880s, under Joseph = Chamberlain became a 1895 colonial phase, we aim to strengthen collaboration with the colonial, the result Commonwealth of Australia (1901) and New Zealand (1907) - Union of South Africa (1910) has become the Dominion. Chamberlain is considered necessary colony to solve domestic social issues, South Africa in support of Cecil = Rose (South Africa, Boolean) caused the war. In Japan, Fabian Society and labor unions seeking their own political party workers, the labor representative committee was formed in 1900, '06, which became the Labour Party. Fabian Society is a socialist organization centered on the intellectuals, Bernard = Show (1856-1950) and Webb and his wife (husband 1859-1947, wife 1858-1943) is active, that socialism and Fabian socialism It caught me. Labour, but socialism has set a goal, it took a gradual reform through policies aimed at the realization. Liberal Cabinet was established in 1905, run the social reform by example the cooperation of the Labour Party, we have enacted national insurance law in '11. In addition, in order to obtain a naval expansion costs to compete with Germany, Lloyd George finance ministers have increased the tax burden on the social layer. When the Senate Conservative Party is strong to resist this, the government passed a Act of Parliament in '11, House bill decision has been determined that the priority in the Senate. Liberal Party Cabinet, also Ireland Autonomy Law in 1914 was established. However, the British a lot of Northern Ireland in opposition to this, the conflict with the Shin = Fein claims the Irish independence, the government has postponed the implementation of the autonomy law because of the outbreak of the First World War. Shin = such as Fein repel, some independence hardliners were put down, but caused the armed uprising in 1916. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.9361524366972793" SCORE="9.93748" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-03-02-1" RANK="11"> Emperor Wen of Han Sui exiting from the north periphery of the North (Emperor Wen of Sui) is to defeat the Chen Dynasty, and unified China, which has been split into north and south, was established the capital in Daikyo-jo (Changan). Asia and Zui-dai canals of Sui-Tang era Sui is incorporating a system that has been tried in various dynasties of the Northern and Southern Dynasties era, I tried to Katameyo the basis of fiscal and military by the equal-field system, Soyocho system-fu military system. It also abolished the Kyu-hin Chiang Kai-shek, and tried to centralization by creating a system of imperial examination to determine the widely human resources by the test of Confucianism. Grand Canal, which was completed when the child Emperor Yang of Sui of Emperor Wen of Han is, linking the Gangnam that more developed north and south morning era and North China, was China the first time in the history of north-south traffic trunk. Asia and Zui-dai canals of Sui-Tang era But distress of farmers that have been requisitioned to these repeated expedition to large civil engineering projects and surrounding countries is grossly, occur rebellion in various places on the occasion of the failure of Koguryo expedition, Sui's Horon in a unified 30 years less than. Warlords of Emperor Gaozu of Tang was raising an army among the Sui end of the rebellion (Koso of Tang), the vertical Tang to defeat Sui in 618 years, it was the capital of Chang'an. Asia and Zui-dai canals of Sui-Tang era Second generation of Taejong (Riyo-min) is allowed to subsumption the mainstay of the East Turkic as well as to unify China, followed Gojong, the East defeated Baekje, Goguryeo, west spread the sphere of influence by possession of the oasis city of the Western Regions. Conquered the land put Dohobu, actual governance was allowed to influential people of the land (Jimi system). Asia and Zui-dai canals of Sui-Tang era </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.9332534236073956" SCORE="9.50289" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-3-8-0-0" RANK="12"> As a result of various revolution that begins in American Revolution and the French Revolution, but modern human rights has been formed in the West, it is the men's rights, women's rights has continued to be limited long. The French Revolution, Guju and that women's rights was requested the principles of freedom and equality as should also apply to women, the United Kingdom of Mary Wollstonecraft and colleagues was a pioneer of women's liberation. When you enter the 19th century politics, economy, to release the women from subordination to men in society and at home, he insisted that aims to free-standing human of men and equality has advocated from various positions. Higher education requirements and improve working conditions of women, movement seeking economic independence, women's suffrage movement with such waste 娼 activities have also been expanded. Women's liberation movement the 19th century European labor movement, evolve among the relationship with such socialist movement and American abolitionist movement. Although the association appeared to obtain the suffrage of women in Europe it is the second half of the 19th century, begins women's suffrage movement in 1848 in the United States, in 1869 was realized in the state of Wyoming. Countries where women first World War had the equivalent of suffrage and men in New Zealand, Australia, Finland, but only four countries of Norway, as a reward to the woman's contribution in the large post-war war, many suffrage was given in the country. In addition, when the women's social advancement progresses, life form of women also changed greatly. This is the time Raicho Hiratsuka in Japan, but is centered on the women's suffrage movement Fusae Ichikawa has been deployed, it is after the Second World War from being realized. In China and Korea, women's liberation was also discussed among the five - four movements and three-one independence movement is uplifting. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.9271826240742005" SCORE="8.70453" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-3-17-2-8" RANK="13"> Britain in the era of Queen Victoria, was celebrated the golden age appropriate for the name of the British Empire. Liberal Party and the Conservative Party is also parliamentary government in charge of the regime established alternately, reforms have been promoted. The 1867 workers of the city by a second-order election law revision, agricultural workers in the third-order election law amendment in '84 got the right to vote. In 1870 enacted Education Act to establish a primary education, along with the legalization of trade unions by the trade union law, the incorporation of workers into the system has been recommended. United Kingdom, which had been preceded by industrialization, but fell behind in the conversion of rather technological innovation and economic structure in order that, by overwhelming superiority in capital exports and shipping, position as a center of the world economy had been held. The National Integration stood to liberalism function effectively, the colonial empire with the strongest navy had been formed. Even Conservatives also Liberal Party, in the policy of development of the empire by expanding and strengthening of colonial rule we had in common. Disraeli Prime Minister of the Conservatives, and the acquisition of shares of the Suez Canal Company in 1875, in '77 was passed a India empire. Then the Liberal Party of Gladstone Prime Minister is the de facto protection country Egypt in 1882, colonial goldenrod Joseph = Chamberlain turned to the Conservative Party from the Liberal Party, also in South Africa was to expand the colony. Further, in order to solidify the unity of the empire, the colonial dominated by immigrants from the country was also adopted policies that give autonomy. 1867 Canadian Federal becomes the first Dominion to, in the early 20th century Australia, New Zealand, South Africa Federation, became a self-governing dominion in succession. From the trade union movement and the socialist movement that became prosperous from the end of the 19th century, the labor representative committee that has been formed in the center and Fabian Society is renamed the Labour Party in 1906, and have increased the seats in cooperation with the Liberal Party. In socialist organizations listed a reformist, Webbs, Bernard Shaw = such, I was at the center of the intellectuals. The move, the House of Commons by the Act of Parliament of 1911 (House of Representatives) with predominance of establishment, so that it has a great significance in the UK politics of the 20th century. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.9264715629833972" SCORE="8.61961" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-4-21-1-5" RANK="14"> The Cold War, Asian countries were various protection policy for domestic economic development. Taiwan, South Korea, the ASEAN countries, while the dictatorship to take a pro-US policy get the United States and massive aid and investment from, such as Japan, giving maximum protection to a specific domestic industry, and in the manner raise the export industry, We have seen tremendous economic development. This was called the development dictatorship. However, among the globalization of politics and economy by the end of the Cold War, dictatorship began to collapse one after another. 1986 to the collapse of the Philippines of Marcos dictatorship, and continued to democratic government was born, since 1992 in Thailand, where the military coup had frequent, civilian government continued, in Korea in 1993 to 32 years Kim Young-sam administration has been established is a civilian regime. Continued KimuDejun administration, in 2000, was realized the inter-Korean summit between the Democratic People's Republic of Korea, which long had hostile relations. In Indonesia, Suharto regime, which had continued to dictatorship over 33 years collapsed in 1998, civilian government by democratic elections appeared. In Taiwan the dictatorship of the Kuomintang was followed, the democratization on the basis of established the Lee Teng-hui Kuomintang regime in 1988 proceeded, the Democratic Progressive Party administration of the opposition is satisfied with the election of 2000. End the era of development dictatorship in Southeast Asian countries, some of the confusion of political also, social development based on democratic rule is made slowly progress. Socialist countries Vietnam, which decided to open economy in 1987, and won a large amount of foreign investment, in the 1990s continued high economic growth second only to China. The ASEAN, Vietnam will participate in '95, in '97 Myanmar, Laos, Cambodia also in '99 I decided to join the ASEAN, all of the time in Southeast Asia 10 countries teamed a single coalition. ASEAN countries and have formed the ASEAN Free Trade Area (AFTA) in 1993, it has recommended their own economic bloc formed. China in 1992, to resume the reform and opening routes, Hong Kong in '97, in '99 recovers Macau, was aimed at actively introduction of foreign capital. China, Hong Kong, the application of the system of one country, two systems in Macau. Taiwan capital that continued conflict in the political was also advanced in large quantities in China. China's economy, continued to double-digit annual economic growth close, it has laid a strong foundation Some of the world economy. South Korea continued economic development, China, and Japan, along with ASEAN countries, is aimed at construction of the economic zone called the &quot;ASEAN + 3&quot;. Also in 1989, Australia, New Zealand, the former ASEAN6 countries, Japan, South Korea, the United States, Canada, 12 countries surrounding the Pacific Ocean was formed the Asia Pacific Ocean Economic Cooperation (APEC). APEC is, depending on the progress of the NAFTA formation and EU integration, in this region, is the official consultation body between the government to strengthen the economic cooperation. In '91 China, Taiwan, Hong Kong, in 1998 Russia, Vietnam, Peru of three countries joined the APEC. On the other hand, it is also progressing free trade agreement between the two countries. So far was also reluctant Japan to regional economic agreement, in 2002, signed a free trade agreement with Singapore, thereafter, it is rushing the conclusion of the countries. Amid the integration of the world economy progresses, we are also progressing the development of local economies. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.9164763834746044" SCORE="7.57825" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-4-19-4-6" RANK="15"> In the Netherlands East Indies, from the 1920s, the independence movement that aims to integrate as Indonesia beyond the framework of regional and religion began to be deployed. Indonesia Communist Party, which was formed in 1920, rapidly expanded its influence, was the uprising in Sumatra and Java in 26-27 years, was devastated by Dutch troops. However, in 1927 Indonesia Nationalist Party has been formed under the leadership of Sukarno, proposed a Merdeka (patriotic) movement. Entering the 1930s, repression of the Netherlands side is arrested most of the leaders have been strengthened, in 1942 during the Second World War received the invasion of the Japanese army. In Vietnam, nationalist movement celebrated the uplifting life, nationalist political parties were born in the 1920s. The '30 Indochina Communist Party is formed under the leadership of Ho Chi = = Min, was uprising in Vietnam Central. On the other hand, Vietnam Kuomintang also was uprising in the north in '30, both have been put down by the French army. When the Popular Front government is established in France in 1936, the united front of the Communist Party and the nationalist political party was formed in Vietnam, it was advanced to the regional parliament. However, it becomes catastrophic situation is again received a crackdown in the late 1930s, in 1940 the Japanese troops have been stationed. In Burma, in 1930 to sheath = but Sun is a large peasant movement happened led, and received a large crackdown by the British army. The same year, mainly students of Rangoon University is Takin (husband) party is formed, it was eventually expand the anti-British independence movement under the leadership of Aung San =. On the other hand, in Thailand, takes place a constitutional revolution in 1932, Congress was promulgated the Constitution was established. In the Philippines, the United States recognized the autonomy in 1934, promised an independent after 10 years. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.9058458271476597" SCORE="6.71209" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-16-02-1" RANK="16"> In June 1950, the Democratic People's Republic of Korea (North Korea) troops invaded beyond the boundary line with the aim of unification, was approaching the Busan district of the Korean Peninsula southern tip. United Nations Security Council is recognized as aggression behavior of Republican Army, was dispatched UN forces consisting mainly of the United States Army for the Korean assistance. At this time, the Soviet Union because that had boycotted the Council, we did not exercise a veto. UN troops to counterattack to Republican Army, when you chase to near the Chinese border, China has dispatched a People's Volunteers in support of the Republic side. Thereafter, the offense and defense was followed across the 38-degree line, hold the '53 armistice, North and South Korea of ​​decoupling has been immobilized in the cease-fire lines that sandwich the 38-degree line. To machine the Korean War, the East-West conflict spread to Asia and the Pacific Ocean region, the United States will set a &quot;rewinding policy&quot; from 1953, stretched around the alliance network. Korean War After the Korean War broke out, Japan was placed Police Reserve (the Self-Defense Forces of later), 1951, press the nonparticipation and opposition socialist countries and some Asian countries, signed a peace treaty in San Francisco Peace Conference did. Korean War Japan recovers an independent, was officially abandoned Korea, Taiwan, South Sakhalin, the Kuril. Four northern islands of Habomai, Shikotan, Kunashiri, Etorofu is recognized and since the Treaty of Shimoda of 1855 (Ansei first year in December), Japanese territory. After the Second World War, the former Soviet Union and the Russian Federation continues to occupy four islands, Japan is seeking its return. At the same time, the US-Japan Security Treaty also concluded, on the fact the United States, received pull the defense of Japan, Japan was recognized American military presence, the survival of the military base and the relationship facility. Various alliance was tied to the Cold War era the world During the 1960 treaty revision, the United States of Japan defense obligation has been documented. The United States in 1951, the Philippines and military assistance treaty, and Australia and New Zealand signed a Pacific Ocean Security Treaty (ANZUS), such as to match the Philippines, Thailand, Pakistan ANZUS countries in '54, Southeast Asia Treaty Organization (SEATO) me was formed. Various alliance was tied to the Cold War era the world Various alliance was tied to the Cold War era the world In addition, after the Geneva armistice agreement, against the Democratic Republic of Vietnam, it was to support the Republic of Vietnam was established in military demarcation line south. In the Middle East region in 1955, Baghdad Treaty Organization that the United Kingdom, Pakistan, Iran to participate (Middle East Treaty Organization &lt;METO&gt;) has been formed in Turkey, Iraq. Various alliance was tied to the Cold War era the world 1958, Iraq became the Republic from the monarchy by the revolution, in '59, I want to leave Baghdad Pact. For this reason, the Baghdad Pact was renamed the Central Treaty Organization (CENTO) ➋. Soviet Union and Eastern Europe 8 countries also in 1955, and formed the Eastern Europe Mutual Assistance Treaty (Warsaw Treaty Organization), was against the North Atlantic Treaty Organization. Various alliance was tied to the Cold War era the world During this time, the United States of nuclear weapons monopoly, torn at the atomic bomb production of the Soviet Union in 1949, the United Kingdom also became a nuclear power soon. In '52, when the United States is conducting an experiment of the first hydrogen bomb, it revealed the holdings of the following year the Soviet Union also hydrogen bomb. The US and the Soviet Union two countries while continuing the nuclear arms race, for fear of fall together by nuclear war, to avoid intervention in the direct confrontation and the other side camp, cemented unity of self-camp, force expansion by acquisition of allies, to neutral countries It was opposed by such assistance. Such a state is referred to as the cold war (the Cold War), it was defined international relations over the subsequent long-term. Various alliance was tied to the Cold War era the world Voluntary movement of countries within each camp is limited, the activities of the United Nations should be a place of consensus of the international community, it has been fitted with a severe frame. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.9040076985048513" SCORE="6.58165" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-S-2-4-2-6" RANK="17"> In the 14th century, Ibn Battuta that was departure on a journey of hajj, to between 30 years, East Africa, Russia plains, India, Southeast Asia, that further traveled to China. His travelogue, are such as state of interaction with life and local people of the Muslim in various regions are drawn. He is life, was able to journey of about 12 million km is, at that time, and of inland and sea transportation road safety is secured well, it shows that the free movement of merchants and civilians was possible there. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.8998934580456708" SCORE="6.30692" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-3-8-3-1" RANK="18"> 1929, stock prices was a big crash in the stock exchanges of New York. Since the war, the United States, which had become the center of the world of finance, Europe of gold had been flown by the wartime debt and interest payments. However, a large imbalance has been created in the world economy. Market to the expansion of production not keep up, leading the economy had given rise to overheating of speculation. Once the collapse begins, bankruptcy of the bank after another, people lose a modest savings did not know the number. The flow of capital procurement stagnant, Depression spread to the world, in the early 1930s production and trade has decreased in countries, was brought serious recession to increase unemployment. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.8883117364818389" SCORE="5.64137" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-S-3-10-1-1" RANK="19"> Southeast Asia of fragrant wood and spices, Indian cotton, Chinese ceramics, silk, tea, such as Asia, was a treasure trove of attractive life goods. These are traded by such trade of tributary trade and Muslim merchants of China, it has been exported to Europe. When the new route is pioneered in the 16th century, European countries, was landed in Asia in search of these goods. Portugal in the 16th century, occupied Goa, Malacca, Macau, etc., Spain was based in Manila. European countries, so did not have the goods to be exported to Asia, it brought a large amount of silver from the Americas and Japan. However, until the 17th century, than the trade with the European home country and Asia, more of trade between Asia was greater profits. Industrial Revolution 18-19 century reversed this relationship. Advantage to only European countries in military technology to establish a sovereign nation, a colony by multiplying the political division of the Asian countries, sales market of industrial products, as the supply areas of agricultural and industrial raw materials, to the world-sized capitalist system I went incorporated. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.8864254700766526" SCORE="5.54571" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-12-01-3" RANK="20"> In France, I was subjected to reactionary policies under the constitutional monarchy government to take severe restrictions election system, 10 Charles is respect for the nobility, clergy. The king in 1830, in order to divert public discontent, do the expedition to Algeria under the control Ottoman Empire, Shiita a tyranny such as to dissolve the parliament left untreated convocation. For this reason, July 30, 10 Charles angry revolution in Paris is banished, Orleans home of Louis-Philippe, known as liberals is to welcome the king, monarchy was established in July. The July revolution spread to various places, Belgium is independent from the Netherlands, it became the kingdom of next '31 constitutional system. Works of Delacroix of the Statue of Liberty France to lead the people. Take the subject in 1830 of the French July Revolution, the goddess has to hand the three-color flag and gun. Although rebellion that took place in Poland, Germany and Italy have been put down, Western Europe takes a distance from the Vienna regime, the emphasis of the Vienna regime came to be placed in Central Europe. On the other hand, in the United Kingdom, which had been increasingly liberal nature, are abolished examination method in 1828, a result of O'Connell et al Irish of movement in the next '29, Catholics release method is established, attached to public office other than the country Muslim It became way. In addition, since the electoral system did not match the reality of the society after the Industrial Revolution, when the exercise of determining the election law amendment becomes violently, Whig Cabinet was realized the reform in 1832 (first round election law amendment). This constituency has been re-organized, is election qualification also expanding, including the industrial capitalist, middle class that became rich in the industrial revolution but strengthened the political clout, landed gentry to the then long political leadership also retention was. Voters plummeted and constituencies had (corruption constituency) becomes obsolete, that amount of seats, conventional emerging commercial and industrial city and that has not been recognized as an independent constituency, it is allocated to states with large populations It was. Workers who seek a more democratic electoral system is, from the late 30's, male suffrage, was cause under the banner of the People's Charter, which consists of six Article such as members of property qualifications abolished political movement (Chartist movement). British this time, advantageous free trade policies to industrial capitalists also have been realized, what is its revolutionary, result Cobden Bright et al. Of the motion by the Anti-Corn Law League who participated, Corn Law is abolished in 1846 the difference was so is that. In order to protect the interests of the landed gentry, the law to maintain grain prices over the high rate of customs duties on imports of foreign grain production. In addition, the '49 was abolished also voyage method. In addition, in 1834 the abolition of the China trade monopoly of the East India Company has been carried out. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.885025498570655" SCORE="5.47672" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-4-19-3-9" RANK="21"> After the Russian Revolution, Muslims of Central Asia, intellectuals began the independence movement from Russia become a center. Independent school has been established the Republic and destroy the Bukhara = Khanate and Khiva = Khanate in 1920, and lost to the Soviet Red Army, in 1922 it came under the control of the Soviet regime. Then, Kazakh through the 1930s, it has been reorganized into Uzbek, such as the Socialist Republic of each ethnic group. Even in the Caucasus region, but the establishment of an independent government was attempted at the time of the Russian Revolution, from the fact that to determine the support of the Red Army in order to counter the Turkish troops that invaded Armenia, and entered into under the influence of the Soviet regime. 1922, but this area has become one Republic that make up the Soviet Union as Zakafukasu federal, in '36 I was separated into ethnic another three of the Republic (Georgia, Armenia, Azerbaijan). However, each country was to face a minority inside. Each republic in the Soviet Union dismantling of 1991 is independent, in also involved religious issues in the independence movement of ethnic minorities, this region has become the scene of civil war and conflict. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.883638105776308" SCORE="5.40997" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-2-3-5-6" RANK="22"> 17 century the first half, the Netherlands becomes the center of the world's commercial and financial on behalf of Spain, Britain and France had also appeared as a powerful maritime nation. These countries have entered the market, raw materials, seeking valuable Bussan America, Asia, Africa. Especially in Asia until it Spain, against the trade monopoly by the state of Portugal, given the charter to traders, was engaged in the Asia trade is established East India Company. Western Europe, the international commercial deployment to expand the background to the commodity economy, went to developed capitalism. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.8835239967943505" SCORE="5.40455" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-S-1-1-3-10" RANK="23"> Cleopatra, Ptolemy the Greek system morning was born as Egyptian royal family of second daughter. At the time, other Hellenistic countries has already been conquered by Rome, it was while slipped to last Moments Egypt also gradually Rome of the dependent countries. Married with his brother according to the old habits of Egypt at the age of 17 after the death of his father, was attached to the throne jointly. However, servants of Ototo-o was revolted for fear the ambition of her alone reign. Cleopatra fled from Egypt, but sake of comeback in Syria, this time, the Rome of the influential person Caesar I arrived in Alexandria owed the political opponents. Cleopatra secretly met with Caesar, was restored to the throne and won his aid and love at the same time. In addition after the death of Caesar, and captured the hearts of Antonius became the influential person of east world in its military commander, was married to him. BC '31, Antonius will be suicide by losing to Roman army led by Octavianus, then, Cleopatra is to know that he is taken to Rome as a decoration of victory, he was standing his own life. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.8823407415329549" SCORE="5.34896" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-2-3-4-8" RANK="24"> Thus foray into European in Asia and the Americas began. In Southeast Asia and the Indian Ocean, which has been configured in a variety of social, seen early success, such as Muslim merchants the sea as mediation, had flourished its own trade bloc. Because of this foray into Spain and Portugal of Asia was carried out in the form in accordance with the trade-speaking rules. In the Americas with respect to this, in the form of the destruction of their own civilization, colonization by Europe was advanced. At that time in the Americas, Mexico Aztec empire, but the Peruvian Inca empire had flourished, both empire Cortez, a small number of Spaniards, led by Pizarro, was conquered respectively. Indigenous people that came to be known as Indio was overworked in mines and plantations. Entered the Asian exchange zone by bringing the Americas of silver Spain, they laid a huge amount of wealth. In Russia, Moscow Grand Duchy of Ivan the Terrible in the 16th century (the Terrible) is subjected to tyranny Hold the aristocracy, it was conquered the whole basin of the Volga river. In addition to starting with the expansion of Yell mark, it spreads the territory in Siberia. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.8823091293673326" SCORE="5.34749" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-3-8-2-5" RANK="25"> In the Paris Peace Conference, China delegation will seize an opportunity of sovereignty recover the peace conference, claiming the recovery of the rights that had been in touch with the United States representative who was holding a distrust in Japan's behavior during the war deprived of Shandong Peninsula it was, but it was not observed. In addition, Asia, such as by the submission of African colonial ethnic activists who also petition, requested the ethnic independence. Also from Korea, but independent through exile activists sued, their hope has been silence. Vietnam Ho Chi Minh, in this meeting, at the Nguyen Ai Quoc (阮愛 countries) name, submitted a &quot;weaker southern people's request&quot;, was noted. In this way, &quot;self-determination of principle&quot; was a colonial Asia, is the was only vision is for the nations of Africa. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.8813810832617291" SCORE="5.30468" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-01-02-9" RANK="26"> Alexander the Great is a Philip II of the child, in order to hit the ever Persian, which has been often interfere with the struggle of the Greek countries, was starting before 334 years east expedition led the Macedonian and Greek Allied. The Great and destroyed the Persian after the conquest of Egypt, or stay until India Northwest further recommended the army, built a large empire that spans from east to west. 3 kingdom of Alexander the Empire and the Hellenistic era After he died suddenly, the territory is contested by warlords of subordinates called Diadokoi (successor), was eventually split into countries such as Antigonus morning Macedonia and Seleucid Empire Syria Ptolemaic Egypt. From east expedition of the Great, about 300 years until the longest surviving the Ptolemaic Egypt of destruction (before '30), is referred to as the Hellenistic era. 3 kingdom of Alexander the Empire and the Hellenistic era This is the era built in the city are numerous Orient and around the Greek style, the Greek culture was spread around these cities. Among them, the Egyptian Alexandria, prospered greatly as a central city of economy and culture. In this way, although police weakened political independence by being conquered Macedonia, the city of as the foundation of civilization life in which the police to prototype, and then still went continued to live in the ancient Mediterranean world. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.8802586607656885" SCORE="5.25378" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-2-3-2-3" RANK="27"> In the 16th century began, Asia expansion of Portugal and Spain has been initiated. Portugal occupied Malacca in 1511, in 1557 it won the right of residence in Macao, laid the base for important trade port that connects the East Asia and South Asia. By the Portuguese and the Treaty of Tordesillas at that time, the Earth Spain which has been divided into two and is, to the Earth in 1521 by dispatching the Magellan (Magaryan'isu) in the west around and have reached the Philippines, construction Manila city in 1571 did. In the early 17th century, the Netherlands, United Kingdom, causing the East India Company in search of Asian products France is referred to as &quot;East India&quot;, while compete with Portugal and Spain, went to build a force in Asia. Netherlands is to build a Batavia city in 1619, is 23 years to the exclusion by Amboyna Massacre the United Kingdom, was established supremacy in the region. Once in the late 17th century, the influence of the price revolution which attracted press in Asia converge, Japan's seclusion, trade there is also the influence of the Qing of trade control was decline. When the big crash occurs of pepper price at the end of the 17th century in Europe, international trade is further decline, European countries will begin to shift from the trade center up to it to the area dominate the direction of Southeast Asia advance. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.8796688681195548" SCORE="5.22741" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-3-9-1-12" RANK="28"> Planned economy and it due to the economic efficiency of the poor, a huge bureaucracy, the Soviet Union-type socialism represented by the oppression of freedom, was established in Stalin's domination was 30 years. Under the Communist Party of the dictatorship, the means of production are nationalized, thought control has been carried out thoroughly. Education, publishing and cultural activities is also subject to control, freedom of speech was restricted. It is impossible to openly criticize the state, resisting person in control of the Communist Party was persecuted. How the people of oppression by the state is depicted in such as &quot;The Gulag Archipelago&quot; of dissident writer Solzhenitsyn of the Soviet Union. On the other hand, education and health care are free of, social welfare, which was enriched by the State has been carried out. Communist Party of Eastern Europe before the war, eradication of economic exploitation, set a elimination of social equality of realization and ethnic discrimination, to some extent attract the farmers and workers, in the war to become the center of the resistance movement, its own We were aiming to reform. However, after the war, when the East-West confrontation deepens uniqueness of the countries deprived, it was supposed to be socialism of the Soviet Union type is gradually introduced. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.8782452683255192" SCORE="5.1648" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-3-18-1-0" RANK="29"> Asia in the 17th century was in the poles of prosperity, but I began to show signs of decline from the second half of the century. From the 18th century, Europe was the era of development. In the 19th century, especially from the second half of that, intellectuals of Europe, the West (Europe) is, whereas a society to be free and development, the East (Asia) is free to be dominated by the &quot;oriental despot&quot; rather, it is misunderstood to be a society that stagnation of the original of the late stage of development &quot;Asian mode of production&quot;, and began to look down. European powers, using the military force, which is backed by excellent industrial power, went one after another Asian countries to colonial. Asia was the industrial raw material supply areas, also, as a market of industrial products, the European powers went flourished more and more wealth. From the 19th century, Asian intellectuals also Asia in terms of industrial and military power began to recognize that it is lagging behind in Europe. In Asian countries, and the forces that try to protect each of the tradition, and the forces that seek reform to take Han (Westernization) in Europe, and also political and cultural, each other Semegi conditions occur. Quickly to start was to reform, but was was a province of the Ottoman Empire Egypt, reform by the pressure of the powers is not progress, eventually became a British colony. The only example of a successful reform is there in Japan, it was colonized, such as Taiwan and the Korean Peninsula soon. When it comes to the end of the 19th century, the concept of &quot;race&quot; has began to penetrate in Asia. In Western Europe, already one of the ethnic groups and philosophy that create one of the nation &quot;nation-state&quot; has been established. Such as in a fashion Ottoman Empire and the Qing Dynasty, which had maintained an independent, movement to try to reinvented the existing state to the &quot;nation-state&quot; began. However, in the Ottoman Empire, which consists of a variety of ethnic groups, &quot;national&quot; problem resulted in the dismantling of the state. On the other hand, in areas that had been the colonial, while maintaining the geographical framework of the colony, is a movement that tries to independence as a &quot;nation-state&quot; began. Such as British India and the Netherlands East Indies, even in areas where various ethnic groups coexist, is the construction of the &quot;nation-state&quot; such as &quot;India&quot; and &quot;Indonesia&quot; was sought. Qing empire after it was defeated in the Opium War, came to be exposed to the pressure and armed attack from abroad. Among them, the exercise which aims to constitutional monarchy deployment, also, Han was the overwhelming majority of residents of the empire, began to deepen awareness as ethnic. In the 20th century, ethnic movement of the Han ethnic group has been allowed to establish the Republic of China to defeat the Qing Dynasty, the construction of the &quot;nation-state&quot; did not proceed easily. This chapter, draw the Asian trends from around the 18th century until the First World War. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.8779984096751797" SCORE="5.15409" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-2-6-1-13" RANK="30"> Defeat and of the Opium War, information of Qing weakened by Taiping gives a big shock to the Edo period intellectuals such as Sakuma Xiangshan and Shuhan Takashima, aroused discussion, such as Coastal Defence theory and reverence for the emperor theory along with the arrival of the black ships. Until then, the West information has been transmitted to Japan, even via China, began to gradually be brought about through the Dutch studies and Western studies. After the opening of the country, shogunate, such as actively to dispatch YaO envoy and foreign students, it was directly served to introduce the Western information. After the Meiji Restoration, of Western technology and culture because of the wealth and military strength incorporating it became the supreme challenge. As a result, the Asia of information also will be through Europe, it has been strengthened a tendency to try with respect to the Western civilization in Asia. Such as &quot;World countries exhaustion&quot; of Yukichi Fukuzawa is the it. Thereafter, different oriental history is with it up to the Chinese classics, depicting the Asia image based on the history methodology of the West. The evolutionary view of history is, gave birth to distinguish trend in Asia to civilization and barbarism. The rise of local forces that brought the weakening of the Qing Dynasty central authority is, did not stay in the Qing Dynasty region. China periphery of East Asia, countries of Southeast Asia, you can try to reorganize the relationship between the Qing Dynasty by multiplying this machine, also it was or trying Hakaro independence from there. For Western countries, that accept or reject its influence, policy of seclusion and opening of the country has been at odds strongly in the country. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.8777282955660772" SCORE="5.14242" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-2-6-0-0" RANK="31"> Asia expansion of Europe, Spain from the late 16th century, was in full swing around the Portugal. Its trade was conducted in a manner in accordance with conventional rules for local world and trade area. Had remained within the frame of even limited trade advance the Netherlands followed. But, first cause was British India foray a wave of industrial revolution, it was those approaching the different a new relationship with them. The development of capitalism further traveling fart a transformation called citizen revolution, more and more of the market, asked for more resources. Other European countries such as France also, chasing after the United Kingdom, the centralized system hardening enhance the economic strength, it took a rapid foreign expansion measures. Competition for territory or sphere of influence was intensified. Then, we try to be applied in areas where it has advanced the diplomatic and treaty relations that had made the international relations of the traditional European countries. Asian Modern, is to be initiated by advancing these Europe. For example, East Asian Modern defeat of the Qing and the opium war, has been to be the beginning. Well spoken is the word &quot;Western impact&quot; is, Asia has been expressed whether the perceived how the advance of Europe. Certainly, military power of the US and Europe, Asia is shocked to science and technology and institutions, westernized appeared as an important issue for Asian countries, it has been perceived to be the modernization to be westernized. But, if you look closely at regional, Asian Modern, And has emerged as the transformation of the old order, which has been ongoing prior. Substantive content of &quot;Western impact&quot; for the regional order was processing among the traditional regional order. Many of the movement of modernization, appeared as reform and criticism of the old order, urged the transformation of the old regime. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.8765002673040788" SCORE="5.09" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-3-13-1-0" RANK="32"> Activities of Kublai = Han of 13th century, the history of the Mongol Empire (large Mongolia Urs), were those which form a big picture period. He Hold the capital in large capital of the south, it was revised based on the country name. 1279, Kublai finally destroyed the Southern Song, was extended a hand of attack emboldened in Japan, Burma, Java. Thus Yuan Dynasty that was established in East Asia of the core (Omoto Urs) is, virtually, to give the suzerain of the status of the Mongol Empire bundling Genghis = Han swarming sites (the various Khanate), both road of land and sea it was supposed to be opposed to the west world is suppressed. Yuan Dynasty, although advocated the Mongolian supremacy, but did not make it in to override the traditional governance mechanisms and land system, unawares incorporated into part of the &quot;Chinese Empire&quot;, soon to advocate a revival of &quot;Han Dynasty&quot; it became a passing thing yield its regime to tomorrow morning. Europe forces advanced to the world beyond the sea from the end of the 15th century, in Asia, was only to participate in the trade zone that was cultivated long. During this time, in Asia the 18th century the first half from the 17th century, the Ottoman Empire, Safavid, Mughal Empire, and the Qing Dynasty to be in take the regime &quot;last conquest dynasty&quot; from the Ming Dynasty, had di the aloof respectively. Empires of these Asia, it has a powerful army, equipped with artillery, were centralized governance is highly evolved bureaucracy. European intellectuals of the same era, looked at the administrative system with an admiring eye. Qing empire in particular, with the exception of Japan eager to trade even under national isolation system, Korea (Riasa) and anchored in the original Sakufu system the countries of Ryukyu, etc., cornerstone of international order in East Asia World (Kaname) I continued to play a role. But empires of Asia, including the Qing empire, did not have to take a policy to further develop the country's commerce and industry. Meanwhile, the European trading company that has received the asylum by the nation, was allowed to extend the commercial rights in Asia, eventually will be Yuku undermining the territory of these empires. And falling into the Qing empire boasted a prosperity &quot;declining&quot; is that it since the beginning of the 19th century. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.8762494527255688" SCORE="5.07942" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-S-1-1-3-3" RANK="33"> The second half of the second century BC, gracchi it your decline of the defense force, tried to suppress the large land owned by the wealthy people with the aim of revival of the independent farmer, opposition by the reform of influential people failed. After that, the private army revolt of Hikiita generals of strife and genus citizens is one after another, Rome, etc. happen slave revolt that leaders of the Spartacus was followed by a state of confusion (one century of civil war). Among this confusion, politics went entrusted to a small number of influential politicians. Caesar (Caesar) performs politics Pompey et al and three (1st Triumvirate), later strengthened dominance in Gaul conquest, became the life of the dictator. But his dictatorship leads to rebound, Caesar was assassinated by a Republican. After the death of his adoptive of Octavianus was performed again Triumvirate and Antonius et al. However, since the Antonius may have entered into with Queen Cleopatra of Ptolemaic Egypt, Octavianus is the Allies, before '31, broke in the naval battle of Actium. Yet 30 years ago, can be conquered Egypt to complete the unification of the Mediterranean world, came to an end the era of confusion. Octavianus returning to Rome, before '27, after receiving the title of Augustus (dignity person) from the Senate, began the Empire on the facts, even while respecting the traditions of the Republic. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.8748381924028434" SCORE="5.02067" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-2-3-4-5" RANK="34"> Had prospered by the commercial activities of the Italian cities Mediterranean world, it has changed greatly with the expansion of the Ottoman Empire when it comes to the 15th century. That the area surrounding the eastern Mediterranean Sea came under the domination of the Ottoman Empire, it became a threat to the entire European world not only Italian cities. Italian merchant was engaged in still east trade in Ottoman territory by paying Mitsugu租, but was seeking a way to be at the hands of Asian products such as spices directly. The also the end of the 15th century, a large number of Jews who were expelled from the Iberian Peninsula, moved to Italy and the Ottoman Empire, became the new leaders of the Mediterranean trade. In the Iberian Peninsula, which has been built in the late 13th century by the advance of the Italian merchant in Mediterranean trade zone, Portugal When you enter the 15th century the Atlantic Ocean in search of trade routes to Asia, it appeared embarked as a maritime nation in the Indian Ocean. Was established in 1479, in 1492 continued in Spain which banished the Islamic nation is this, the two countries was carried out financial assistance to the voyage who. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.874542601820572" SCORE="5.00853" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-1-2-1-5" RANK="35"> For ancient people, it is the period of the phases of the moon was easy to understand, annual cycle of the sun was that hard to catch. Therefore, the original of the calendar were often lunar calendar due to the periodic phases of the moon. In Egypt was originally solar calendar is used, but when it comes to the Hellenistic period, is set to one month 30 days and the extra days the 5th addition to the 360 ​​days of 12 months, the Alexandria system to put a day leap every four years It has been established. In Rome, had lunisolar calendar is used for a long time, there is also negligence of priests group that controls the calendar, large deviation occurs over the years. In order to rectify this absurd, Caesar '45 ago, we embarked on a reform to correct the deviation of the season and calendar, adopted the solar calendar by the Alexandria system. By law, normal year was 365 days, in one leap year in four years, it was 366 days by adding a day in February. The leap day at the end of February is placed, in the Roman calendar, because now of March falls Martius of the month (English name March) was the beginning of the year. Calendar named after the clan name of Julius Caesar this is, while being subjected to some modifications by the Gregorian calendar in the 16th century, which extends to today. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.874542601820572" SCORE="5.00853" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-15-02-2" RANK="36"> After the war for a while, international conflicts to rebound to border demarcation and peace conditions are secondary. Ottoman Empire to recover the part of the territory is under Mustafa Kemal =, a Greek fighting, signed a renewed Lausanne Treaty the Sevres treaty. Poland was invaded in 1920 Russia (Poland = Soviet war), give a part of Belarus and Ukraine, Italy also cause Yugoslavia and the border dispute, won the Fiume. Above all, confrontation of France and Germany over the compensation payments, France in 1923 and Belgium has deteriorated enough to occupy the Ruhr area of ​​Germany. However, spreads the momentum after the 1924 international cooperation, in the Locarno Treaty of '25 determines the status quo and the mutual security of the border with Germany and Western European countries, Germany has joined the League of Nations the following year. In general term for a series of treaty group that has been agreed at a meeting in Switzerland of Locarno, in addition to maintaining the status quo of the German western border, Rhineland demilitarization, are the main contents of resolution by arbitration of international disputes. 1928, at the proposal of France Briand Foreign Minister and the United States of Kellogg Secretary of State, signed by the bye Treaty (Briand-Kellogg Treaty) of 15 countries (later 63 countries), is that it does not resort to war as a means of settling international disputes It is sworn. In addition, Washington auxiliary ship that was left at the meeting also limited unity in '30 London Conference, the shareholding ratio between the United States, the United Kingdom, Japan has decided. Owned tonnage ratio, in the United States, the United Kingdom, Japan, was approximately 10, 10 and 7. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.871596811552198" SCORE="4.89056" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-07-02-4" RANK="37"> When you enter the 16th century, the development of maritime trade that connects the various continents, waters all parts of the world are now linked to each other closely, and was bolstered its active long-distance commercial, and met at the increased production of silver It was. By Spain, which recommended the conquest of the Americas have been developed silver mine in Latin America, a large amount of silver in addition to yelling flow to Europe and Asia, the development of silver mine has advanced in Japan. Spanish silver coins the Spanish silver coins (above) and is Chogin (bottom) Spain was cast in the Americas was the international currency that is also used in Asian internal trade. 16th century early 17th century from the second half, Japan's silver also are exported in the form of bullion, such as Chogin, it played an important role in Asian trade. Southeast Asian pepper perfume and Chinese raw silk, Asian specialties such as Indian cotton is purchased by silver, the market has expanded rapidly. Spanish silver coins the Spanish silver coins (above) and is Chogin (bottom) Spain was cast in the Americas was the international currency that is also used in Asian internal trade. 16th century early 17th century from the second half, Japan's silver also are exported in the form of bullion, such as Chogin, it played an important role in Asian trade. The European merchants and local government and merchants who advanced to Asia, sometimes in cooperation Concerning benefits of trade, tied the complex relationships that sometimes conflict. The activities of the European forces, such as smuggling population (Japanese pirates) and Portugal and the Netherlands of Japanese and Chinese is increasingly active also in the waters of East Asia, the Ming sea prohibition policy went collapse. With the development of international commerce, European new style firearms such as matchlock and cannon spread throughout in Asia, and supported the establishment of the emerging regime. Americas crops such as corn, sweet potato, potato, tomato also spread throughout the world, it had a major impact on people's life. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.8703988817657045" SCORE="4.8441" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-03-03-2" RANK="38"> The Tang began to largely the history of East Asia after the fall is a northern ethnic trend. Ryo Kawakami stream at Chigirini who ran the life of Hanno Hanbok (gas) was strengthened force with Uighur decline. In the early 10th century Eastern Mongolia centered on the Emperor Taizu of Liao (King Taejo) is to create a powerful nation, east destroyed the Bohai Sea, the west was holding the Mongolian plateau. As then Khitan compensatory helped founding of KoSusumu of Five Dynasties, plus of Hebei, Shanxi Northern (Sixteen Prefectures) in the territory. After the establishment of the Song also threatened the Song and invade the North China, in the beginning of the 11th century, it signed a voluntary arrangement on condition that Sung sends every year a large amount of silver and silk in the Khitan (and Mei 澶淵). Chigirini is the first nation who ruled also the Chinese mainland while keeping the home as a northern nation, in its territory, such as hunting, nomadic, agriculture, had a various ethnic groups with a variety of occupations. Therefore, even in the control tower, north officer based on a tribal system, by providing a distinction such as south-government based on the province prefecture system, tried to Yuko together a society that made it of personality (double governance system). The country, and when to use the Khitan of the family name, there was a time to use a named Liao of Chinese style. Chigirini has been affected by the early Uighur culture, eventually absorb the Chinese culture, it accepted the Buddhism. Khitan characters Taejo et al. is to have made is affected by both the Uighur characters and Chinese characters. There are a Khitan character Oaza and Koaza. Decryption not progressed enough yet. The northwest frontier of the Shaanxi-Gansu side of the Song Dynasty, weave Tangut Tibetan system, and defeated the neighboring Tibetan Empire and Uighur, eventually called the independently Lee Hiroshi emperor, it is called Western Xia the country name in large summer and was (general ). Asia of the 12th century around Asia of the 12th century around Western Xia is Grasp the cornerstone of trade routes connecting China and the west, was often invade Song. Asia of the 12th century around Buddhism is thriving, many Buddhist scriptures have been translated in Western Xia characters following the structure of the Chinese characters. Thing and there is a Western Xia characters ideographic and phonetic characters, has become quite clear pronunciation and semantic. The eastern part of the sphere of influence of the Khitan, it had received the control of the Khitan to have semi-hunting and a half of agricultural engaged in the life Tungus system of woman true (woman straight) is. Before long Kankao Emperor Taizu of Jin (King Taejo) is I was referred to the independently country with the gold in the early 12th century. Asia of the 12th century around Sung by connecting with emerging of gold blame Liao the (Khitan), Liao I Horon by gold of the attack (1125). At this time, the royal Yelü Dashi of Liao built a national and fled to Central Asia (Kara-Khitan Khanate), to maintain the culture of the Khitan in the west. Asia of the 12th century around After the fall of the Liao, Song and gold dispute On territory, gold occupied the capital opening of the Song and invade the North China. Asia of the 12th century around Gold while maintaining the original military and social organization that Moyasu-HakarigotoKatsu based on the tribal system, in North China inherited the province prefecture system of Song. As with Khitan and Western Xia, own woman true character in true woman it was created. They are made by a woman true character Khitan characters and the Chinese characters to the original, it is currently quite decipher. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.8697868859226818" SCORE="4.82069" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-2-5-2-14" RANK="39"> East and is the designation of viewed from Europe. Near East, Middle East, it is also the same term the Far East. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.8683572490548002" SCORE="4.76684" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-2-3-5-1" RANK="40"> In the Netherlands (lowland region), before becoming the wool industry to brisk commercial activity to the axis than, as a key area of ​​trade connecting the inland of the North Sea and Mediterranean destinations and Western Europe, flourished cities such as Antwerp I have had. However, the route to the Atlantic Ocean and Hirake, and spread the possibility of trade in Africa and Asia, merchants began to advance in these areas and the Baltic Sea area. By these activities, newly Amsterdam of the Netherlands north, was developed shipbuilding industry and international commercial, as a center of finance. Among these, the Netherlands northern seven states are united, and declared independence from Spain in 1581, was later riding the Netherlands Federal Republic and name. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.8665548428200704" SCORE="4.70057" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-2-6-1-6" RANK="41"> The thing of unfavorable treaty in one of which signed a treaty. Unilateral most-favored-nation treatment, extraterritoriality (consular jurisdiction), (loss of tariff autonomy) tariff agreement rights which is the content and the like. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.866252610581446" SCORE="4.68963" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-17-03-3" RANK="42"> Many seen development dictatorship and military regime, or long-term administration in developing countries, to reduce the number and the 1980s, it has been a multi-party system and democracy spread. In Asia, it is committed to the development of export industry, South Korean President Park was cracking down anti-government activity has been assassinated in 1979, the foundation of the military who crackdown anti-government pro-democracy movement in Gwangju in '80, and Chun Doo Hwan, Roh Tae-woo and military personnel born president was followed. During this period, South Korea to recover the Soviet Union and China and diplomatic relations, in '91 was a member of the United Nations along with the Democratic People's Republic of Korea. In the 92 year-end election, the Kim Young Sam became a non-military president for the first time in '32, and then punish the two former President at stake, such as the Kwangju incident, served in the fixing of civilian rule. Dae-Jung Kim becomes president from '98, to promote democracy and the Korean Peninsula of detente, in 2002 Roh Moo-hyun was elected president. Export industry is growing, also wearing a economic strength Taiwan, the domestic has been followed by a one-party rule of the Kuomintang under martial law. However, martial law in 1987 is released, Lee Teng-hui was appointed to the President from '88 was served to democracy promotion. In the 2000 presidential election, Chen Shui-bian was elected that does not belong only to the KMT. In addition, President Marcos of the Philippines, which was in power since 1965, being chased by a popular movement that unauthorized protest of the '86 election, then is followed by a regime by democratic elections. President Suharto that has been in power for more than 30 years in Indonesia, in '98, was deposed by the economic slump in people's opposition movement with discontent. In India, accounting for administration of post-war National Congress faction mainstream, during this time, and repeat the collision On such attribution of Kashmir in between with Pakistan, in 1971 was independent East Pakistan as Bangladesh. However, '84 Prime Minister Indira = Gandhi, the '91 is assassinated Rajiv Gandhi = eldest son who succeeded After, national Congress away from the regime. In 1998, Pakistan also conducted a nuclear test against the Indian nuclear test, became the new nuclear powers. Even in many was Latin America of dictatorship, in 1973, withdrew shortly defeated in referendum the Chilean Allende socialist regime in the Pinochet military regime 88 years was defeated in the coup, challenged the Falklands war in 1982 the United Kingdom Argentina's military regime also been defeated in war, it was shifted to civilian rule. Central America Nicaragua of Somoza long-term dictatorship overthrown in '79 left-wing guerrillas, '90, could centrist government by election. In Africa, Caucasian minority dominated regime has disappeared. 1965, unilaterally independent Rhodesia from the United Kingdom, to accept the black majority domination in the face of criticism of the armed struggle and international public opinion of the liberation movement, has become a '80 Country to the State of black principals and Zimbabwe. South Africa after the Second World War, was introduced the apartheid policy of extremely discriminate against blacks is a majority, was orphaned in response to the economic sanctions of the protest and the United Nations of the African National Congress. In the late 1980s, de Klerk government review the apartheid entirely, abolished the '91 discrimination laws, it was also observed equality suffrage in '94. South African President Mandela (right) in 1994, he was appointed to the results of the presidential election. Caucasian of de Klerk Vice President left had promoted reconciliation with black. Both were both received the previous year Nobel Peace Prize. The results of the election, African National Congress is won the majority was elected president black Mandela, it is then also selected a black president. South African President Mandela (right) in 1994, he was appointed to the results of the presidential election. Caucasian of de Klerk Vice President left had promoted reconciliation with black. Both were both received the previous year Nobel Peace Prize. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.866247626559674" SCORE="4.68945" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-15-03-5" RANK="43"> After the first World War, ethnic movements, also in Southeast Asia was again spread. In Indonesia, the Indonesian Communist Party has advocated independence is founded in 1920. After nearly destroyed by the movement is severe crackdown, students who returned from the Netherlands came to leadership. '27 Kuomintang that the party leader the Sukarno is founded in, and uplifting independent Holding Aloft movement with unity is, the next day in '28 was declared that the aim of the homeland, ethnicity, language that is unified that Indonesia. But 29 leaders were arrested at the end of the year, the exercise was stagnated. In Indochina that France dominates, Ho Chi = = the people formed the Vietnam youth revolution comrades meeting in 1925, Indochina Communist Party has been established it in '30 to the mother. Party, was to expand the peasant movement, such as also to establish a rural Soviet regime while receiving a thorough crackdown. In Myanmar begins ethnic movement from the 1920s, the rise of radical nationalists called Enlightenment and Takin party by the monks was seen. In the Philippines the United States is to govern, Congress opened in 1907, for the legislative and administrative, delegation of authority to the Philippines people were recommended. However, the economic order has advanced greatly dependent on commodity crop production in the United States, beggar-thy-the farmers was repeated the rebellion. As a result, the Philippines independent law enacted in 1934, independent preparation government was established the following year. Under these circumstances, the Asian region is to rush from the end of 1941 in the Pacific War, many were supposed to greet the invasion of the Japanese army. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.8654790554865934" SCORE="4.66185" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-2-6-1-10" RANK="44"> Ratification exchange and additional treaty of Tianjin treaty. Indemnity becomes eight million cars, to add the Tianjin to open ports field, it was ceded part of the Kowloon peninsula to the United Kingdom. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.8653071724264868" SCORE="4.65572" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-2-4-2-10" RANK="45"> When the Napoleonic Wars is over, the United Kingdom, was returned to the Netherlands some of the occupied territories, including Java in Vienna conference. But Britain, was to ensure the Ceylon and the Cape Colony. In addition, in 1819, and was a colonial administrative officer of the United Kingdom Raffles is at hand the right to use the Singapore from the Islamic Emirate of the land, and to build a modern harbor, next year, calling the declaration that this as a free port did. It, as well as suppress the transport hub leading to East Asia from India, which was that you try in the center of the free trade markets of Asia to dominate the British industry. In fact, Singapore is made to the harbor to prosperity There are merchant ships from shortly various regions, it is in the late 19th century and became the cornerstone of the United Kingdom of Asia colonial management together with Hong Kong. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.8652979070678006" SCORE="4.65539" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-15-02-3" RANK="46"> Britain and France after the war, but increased the overseas territories, it does not recover from the economic blow received by the war, suffered the economic recession. In the UK, at the 4th election law amendment of 1918, it is expanding suffrage to men and 30 women over the age of 21 years of age or older, in the 5th election law amendment of '28, and election to the men and women over 21 years of age rights were observed. After the war, per the second party of the status of second only to Labor Party Conservative Party on behalf of the Liberal Party, in 1924 he organized a coalition government with the Labour Party leader McDonald's Liberal Party. This regime was short-lived, the Labour Party in the election of '29 will be the first time first party, McDonald's has once again came to power. Ireland, in 1922, became a self-governing dominion except the northern part of Ulster as the Irish Free State. By a resolution of the 1926 and '30 of the British Empire conference, '31 Westminster Charter is established, each Dominion as a member of the British Commonwealth, give a home and equal status to the original loyalty to the crown. However, Ireland independent faction abolished the loyalty declaration to the crown in '37, it has established its own constitution, has left virtually federal ale as a country. France Land, became the battlefield was also afraid of the powers of Germany after World War II. Therefore France, obligations of the Treaty of Versailles imposed on Germany, in particular demanding a compensation payment, at the time of the Poincare right-wing Cabinet, was forced to rule occupation because of payment defaults. However, versus the German hard-line diplomacy fails bathed the international criticism, in 1924 left-wing coalition government appeared. Briand became the foreign minister in 25 years to strive to reconciliation with Germany, it has contributed to international cooperation. In Germany, although the Communist Party from revolutionary propulsion force and the Social Democratic Party in Germany has been conflict immediately after the war, the Social Democratic Party by connecting with conservatives such as the military, I held down the Communist Party beginning in 1919. German Communist Party, especially in the Spartacus faction Social Democratic Party the most left-wing was organized under the banner of the anti-war, was formed after the war. Leader Rosa = Luxembourg (1870-1919) and Karl Liebknecht = (1871-1919), was murdered in '19 beginning. In the National Assembly, which was held in Weimar, Ebert of the Social Democratic Party is elected president, democratic Constitution (Weimar Constitution) has been established, made the foundation of the Republic (Weimar Republic). However, compensation payments, such as by anti-Republic activities by imperial faction and the right wing, economic and political situation was not stable. In particular, the French rules occupation of 1923 and reduced productivity due to the resistance in disobedience movement, progress in severe inflation. Old bill in the currency inflation currency inflation in Germany is almost worthless, you can be in children's toys instead of the usual, were or are used as wallpaper. The same year summer, Stresemann became the prime minister is to overcome the inflation by issuing the rentenmark, with a successful mitigation and capital introduction of compensation payments in cooperation with the United States, and re-built the economy, was to promote international cooperation diplomacy. In response proposal of experts of international business community (the Dawes Plan), the Allies to reduce the time being the compensation payments of Germany, it decided the German economic recovery by the United States capital. 1929, compresses the total amount, payment period is also extended final payment plan (Young Plan) is determined, total compensation in the Lausanne conference of 1932 was reduced to 30 Oku-kin Marc. However, Nazi Germany = denied the compensation itself. International circulation of capital after the Dawes Plan established Stresemann, who served as foreign minister until 1929 to realize the international Federation, we tried the recovery of the international status of Germany. If during this time Ebert died in 1925, it was the Army Chief of the General Staff of the First World War the late Hindenburg was elected president (in office 1925-34). But in '29, when the foundation of the economy is hit by the Great Depression While not stable, the German economy will be catastrophic situation, people's lives and parliamentary politics was confusion. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.864763453486169" SCORE="4.63643" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-09-04-4" RANK="47"> France is a result of the hundred years war, and almost wiped out the British national, has been on the road to the centralized state. However, in the 16th century Nakaba also a Roman catholicism countries France can no longer be ignored Protestant force of Calvinist called Huguenot, Huguenot war broke out in the original regent Catherine-de-Medicis of Charles IX and his mother. The civil war in that confrontation of old and new sects are associated with partisan strife between the aristocracy, while accompanied by incidents such as the massacre of sambal Barthelemy, it ranged to more than 30 years. A number of new Muslims murder in 1572 in the massacre Huguenot war of sambal Barthelemy. because this was also seen foreign forces intervention, in France, such as Bodin, it went Hitobitogafue to try to prioritize national unity than the religious problem. Bourbon Henri IV is to convert and take the throne from Protestantism to Roman catholicism, giving a significant religious freedom in Huguenot in 1598 in Nantes the king decree (edict), it was Owarase the Huguenot war. In this way, the unity of France as the nation is maintained. France has stayed in the Roman catholicism countries, the idea that claims the independence of the French church to papacy has become stronger. Henri 4 world begins Bourbon morning under, France celebrated its heyday of the absolute monarchy. Louis XIII of vizier Richelieu, do not open the three Group Hold the resisting nobility and Huguenot to kingship, in terms of international politics, three decades during the war, lottery the emperor power of the Habsburgs to stand on the side of the Protestant forces It served To this. After the coronation of the childhood of Louis XIV, in 1648, but the High Court and the aristocracy has caused revolt (the Fronde), policy of kingship strengthening by Chancellor Mazarin was continued. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.8640457472936979" SCORE="4.6112" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-3-13-3-5" RANK="48"> Introduction of Western paintings, begins that Mateo = Rich has brought the Christian iconic image in the late Ming. Castiglione is not an oil paint, drawn using the watercolors and Doroenogu. Western image of chiaroscuro, perspective, realism is, had a major impact on subsequent Chinese painting. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.8638742492505707" SCORE="4.60521" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-S-4-12-1-4" RANK="49"> Allies in order to advantageously expand the war, was to expand the secret diplomacy. UK to confuse Turkey, promised an independent Arab who was under its domination. Also, along with the connecting secret agreement to divide the post-war Turkish territory with France and Russia, promised to build a country of the Jews to Palestine which Arabs live in order to obtain the cooperation of the Jews (Balfour Declaration). These agreements and promises are inconsistent, it became one of the causes of the squares of the Palestinian problem. Asian colony, there was no damage of direct war, is lined with cooperation in the Allied side, we paid a lot of sacrifice. From British colonial India, the promise and the exchange of post-war autonomy, Indian soldier 1.5 million people were sent to the battlefield. In addition to the soldiers and workers from the French colonial Indochina, food was also requisitioned. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.8633297468998795" SCORE="4.58629" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-2-3-3-2" RANK="50"> Uzbeks, 16 century, Bukhara in Central Asia, Khiva, was built three Khanate of Kokand, in both mid-19th century was placed under the control of Russia. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.8617999722286165" SCORE="4.53392" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-1-6-1-4" RANK="51"> Ancient Southeast Asia and Japan there are many people who are like I thought that there is no relationship. However, most parts of Southeast Asia, belongs to the East Asian tribute area, there was also mutual exchange. Song at the famous Abe no Nakamaro of &quot;month might could appear in heaven of the original pretend salmon Kasuga become Mikasa mountain If you look&quot; (Tomei morning equilibrium) is 鎮南 MiyakoMamoru (name of safety Nanto protection after the An Lushan Rebellion) that government was the Secretary of is not well known. Abe no Nakamaro's Kaiyuan 5 (717) years of Japanese students of the tender 16-year-old was accompanied to the envoys, but I want to rush the ranks of the Tang court in no time at all. It becomes a staff of Prince in the mid-30s, emperor immediate secretary audit by the time more than 50 years of age, had become a mandarin of the sub three goods. In addition, also famous in poetry, create a Li Bai and Wang Wei, such as first-class poets and salon, leaving its name to Toshi statement. 760 years turbulent is headed to the convergence Yasushi, Nakamaro is Ninze is to 鎮南 MiyakoMamoru, and went to the current Hanoi, after established the Yunnan communication path, is return to duty 767 years. Center of Nanhai trade, the safety Nanto protection in jobs that benefit, when there was usually make the goods until the quinine, Nakamaro is seemed integrity of officials, which died in Chang'an in 770 years, Tang that has been Zoi the Shu-dai Metropolitan supervision, without any property, the family was in poverty. Imperial Court of Japan heard this I have sent to the bereaved family commissioned the silk and cotton to Tang used. In Abe no Nakamaro Japan, it has not been evaluated only as a poet but, at that time, it was also the finest of international civil servants shining in the history of during the day - - Vietnam three countries. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.8615410845977411" SCORE="4.52517" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-2-6-4-3" RANK="52"> 1796, when the car Jarre morning is satisfied, Georgia asked for protection in Russia, further became the crown colony. In addition, Armenia, also part of Azerbaijan was ceded to Russia in Turkey Man Chai Convention. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.8608260683071566" SCORE="4.50117" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-2-6-1-19" RANK="53"> Japan and Russia, south Sakhalin of ceded to Japan, was a compromise without compensation. Japan in addition, to admit the Korean domination, lease rights and Lushun port of the Liaodong Peninsula, was acquired from the Russian concession (South Manchuria Railway later) railway between Changchun. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.8602976909286301" SCORE="4.48359" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-2-3-5-13" RANK="54"> 16 century, is Western Europe forces, the Atlantic Ocean, creating a trade route to the Pacific Ocean, the Atlantic, the Indian Ocean, trade route is established that connects the Pacific Ocean. Spain is a large amount of silver flows obtained in the Americas, was expanding economic activities beyond the region. 16-17 century, is the era of the large trade on a global scale. In Japan, the early 17th century, the Edo shogunate gave the Netherlands and trade permit in the United Kingdom (the red seal shape). Portugal was conveyed to Japan of Gangnam China silk. Are encouraged shogunate licensed trading ship trade in Southeast Asia, became popular overseas travel, Japan Town, appeared in various places. However, in the 17th century mid-price revolution converge that attracted press in Asia, there is also Suekiyo's first social unrest Ming, the South China Sea, East China Sea trade began to decline. Shogunate will be thorough seclusion in 1641, development of the rural economy by developing Nitta, by the maturity of the urban economy, dependence on foreign trade was not large. Eventually Japan, would be to go to create a domestic self-sufficiency system. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.8594073195375288" SCORE="4.45426" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-02-03-6" RANK="55"> , One which was Qin &quot;Nanao&quot; is, before wearing a national power in the fourth century in the reform of Shang Yang, and one after another conquered the east of 6 country was unified China before 221 years. Asian Hatha Western Han dynasty Qin Wang of the government, instead of the &quot;king&quot;, was adopted the title of &quot;Emperor&quot; with the meaning of &quot;shining God&quot; (Qin Shi Huang). Qin Shi Huang is already enforced in the whole country the county prefecture system that has been carried out in its own country, gave housed in officials that was sent directly from the center. Further balance the unification of money-metrology and characters, such as performing a thought control by the Book burning, Ana儒, it was pushed the absolute reduction and centralization of the emperor power. According to the &quot;Shiji&quot;, baked all the books of non-pharmaceutical and divination and agriculture relationship (Book burning), that was killed by burying hundreds of Confucian in the hole (Ana儒). &quot;Terracotta Warriors&quot; was buried in Boiki of Qin Shi Huang of Ling, it has Monogata~tsu the magnitude of the power of Qin Shi Huang. Qin in the north to counter the Xiongnu of invasion by renovation of the Great Wall since the Warring States period, the south was placed three counties such as Nankai (now Guangzhou) to conquer the South China. Asian Hatha Western Han dynasty However, the rapid unification policy and the burden of foreign war and civil engineering construction tormented people, were growing antipathy to the Qin especially in the east 6 countries in the region that has been conquered by the Qin. It takes place after death shortly rebellion in various parts of the First Emperor, Qin's Horon only 15 years after unification. It happened first peasant revolt by Chen Sheng-Wu Guang. &quot;Princes Masaru phase Izukunzo seed Alanya&quot; Chen Sheng of the word represents well the state of society that first an individual's ability since the Warring States period. Among the rebels of various places, and led the people of the town of his hometown stretched out Xiang Yu and the force is a prestigious out of Liu Bang and Chu of people born that was uprising, the end of four years of fierce fight, unified Liu Bang China Te per position of the emperor (Koso), it was built the Han Dynasty (Han). Asian Hatha Western Han dynasty </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.8593975437200319" SCORE="4.45394" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-2-5-1-14" RANK="56"> 1848 is also the year happened the Gold Rush in California of the United States. In 1851, gold mines have been discovered in Australia. It will increase the immigrants to this land, it stimulated the growth of the city. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.8593975437200319" SCORE="4.45394" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-2-7-1-8" RANK="57"> John Hay is, in the declaration obtained a guarantee for China to Rekkoku, in 1899  捉髢 horsefly Kamoji District 叛光 © 讖滉 Shea 壼插 遲会 shea 900 蟷E縺~O  Hakasusegare 悄菫 晏Ⅹ 繧呈 station 蜚A 縺励 ◆ 縲 Chu ◎ 縺~Yo縺~Yu 繧峨&gt; 縺~Tsu荳~Yuinagosu縺~YoYuzuru~u 逶翫 ∈ 縺~Yo, it was the United States of interruption. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.8586836735584427" SCORE="4.43069" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-2-6-1-9" RANK="58"> Qing is the United Kingdom, France, the United States, each of the tied treaty of Russia. Beijing resident diplomatic mission, Christian certified and protection, foreign inland travel rights, an increase of opened field freedom of trade, and the like 6 million cars in compensation payments to the United Kingdom and France. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.8577994467015906" SCORE="4.40221" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-13-01-0" RANK="59"> Empires of Asia 17-18 century, began to show a trend of division by gradually weakening. At the same time, the movement of the interference and colonization of Europe forces also went into full swing. Ottoman Empire and since the beginning of the 19th century suffered the interference of the European powers associated with it and the independence movement of various ethnic groups, is multiplied by the decline of the Mughal Empire in India 18th century Nakaba later, the United Kingdom has recommended the territorial domination. Opium War after the 19th century Nakaba in the Qing Dynasty, foreign war and civil war followed, national power has waned. In Chapter 13, dealing with trends of these Asian region centered on the 19th century. These to advance European countries, it was a wide variety of correspondence Shikatagami in Asian countries. Some direction to proceed with the modernization in the government-led under the influence of Europe by introducing the technology and political system, knowledge who seeks to resistance Islam and Hinduism, or the private beliefs and new religions in infrastructure to foreign invasion There was and is also popular movement. These streams are entangled, while giving each other the effect, Asian nationalism were being formed. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.8576136527201464" SCORE="4.39627" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-2-6-1-1" RANK="60"> Although the Qing Dynasty was a dynasty of Manchu, the following response to the external governance of basically Ming, Han and other ethnic groups or of, a variety of governance relationship to the peripheral area is built, Hanaebisu order or Chinese We had to maintain a unified international order called order. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.8574427647562697" SCORE="4.39082" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-2-5-2-3" RANK="61"> In France again the Republic was established in 1848 in the revolution, Louis Napoleon was appointed to the President. After that, he caused a coup, defining the Constitution gave the autocratic authority to the President. In '52 and it became emperor by performing a referendum to give the title of Napoleon III. This Second Empire era, France's economy was dramatic development. Is promoted by public works and urban planning business, it was also made large remodeling of Paris. Furthermore the life improvement is grave even for farmers layer is a major foundation of government, even agricultural production increased by technological change. Napoleon III, the goal is to prevent the upset social platform enhances the prestige of the state, was aggressive foreign policy. Crimean War, and intervene in the Italian unification war, in Asia it tried to advance China and Indochina aggression. But the failure of Mexico troops were supposed to lead to the downfall of the emperor of prestige. Although anti-government faction in parliament had done a liberal reform and get a boost, in 1870, it becomes their own prisoner in the Franco-Prussian War, the Second Empire has collapsed. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.8572573115690084" SCORE="4.38492" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-2-6-1-7" RANK="62"> Qing Guangzhou, Xiamen, Fuzhou, open Ningbo, Shanghai 5 harbor, to abolish the public line, and ceded Hong Kong, was recognized compensation six million cars of confiscated opium, military compensation 12 million cars of the payment, the principle of equal diplomatic relations . The following year of five the harbor trade Shotei, in the Treaty of the Bogue, showed consular jurisdiction, agreement tariff, and most-favored-nation treatment. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.8570865275381201" SCORE="4.3795" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-1-0-0-1" RANK="63"> Since the birth of life on Earth, after the evolution over a long period of time, the human race was born. The oldest fossil bone that clearly can be identified with humanity, 400 million years ago monkey who appeared in Africa (Australopithecus earth), use a simple chipped stone tools that pounded the natural stone before more than 250 million years , it had sent a life of hunting-gathering. Then, when it comes ago 1.8 million years, Homo erectus appeared in Africa, it was soon adapted to also live in such as Asia. They are believed to be using the fire, spoke simple words. Before about 20 million years, the old man appeared. They are the master of hunting, Neanderthal was subjected to religious acts such as the burial of the dead. Before long, from at least 30,000 years ago around, rookie corresponding to the direct ancestor of the current humanity, appeared in Asia, Africa, in large areas of Europe. They use the chipped stone tools and bones and horn according to the application, also hope the success of fertility and hunting, you can make a female nude, was or painted animal picture on the wall of the cave. In this way the times I have been using your chipped stone tools of Paleolithic. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.8565444283366996" SCORE="4.36238" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-2-5-2-5" RANK="64"> 19 century the beginning of the War of 1812 after, the United States one after another to expand the territory, it has undergone remarkable development. Starting with the purchase of Louisiana from France, we got Florida, Texas. Also, he won California in the war with Mexico (Mexican-American War). Thus territory reached the Pacific Ocean coast. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.8561958947386985" SCORE="4.35144" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-2-7-2-3" RANK="65"> United Kingdom, which has been developed as a colonial empire retains its interests, in 1914 it had become by the time to dominate the territory and the 400 million people of a population of approximately 28 million square kilometers. France is to ensure incidentally vast colony to the United Kingdom, the expansion has been promoted since the 1870s. Germany is also the United Kingdom, I embarked on the acquisition of overseas territories late for France. One of the focal point of the advance of the great powers in Asia was in China. After the Opium War, powers had been unanimously concluded China and unequal treaties, the Sino-Japanese after the war acquisition of leased land and railroad rights, plunged China through the dispatch of troops and advisers to the &quot;semi-colonial&quot; state It was. Now also one of the subject of the great powers of the activity was Africa. Opening of the 1869 of the Suez Canal to stimulate the expansion into powers of Africa, Africa was the subject of division competition. In Africa, the proportion of the colony, which was less than 1 percent of the entire continent in 1876, in 1900 it was to be up to up to 90%. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.8561882300023309" SCORE="4.3512" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-2-5-1-8" RANK="66"> 1838, British workers have announced the People's Charter of 6 Clause, was determined and limit the abolition of the right to vote by the property. The movement is called the Chartist movement, became the first political movement of workers. Implementation of adult male suffrage became the strong request of Republican and labor movement that claims a new social reform in France. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.8561882300023309" SCORE="4.3512" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-2-6-2-3" RANK="67"> France, under the pretext of the collision in the vicinity of the Qing and the Vietnam border, Taiwan, attacked the Fuzhou. Qing torn in this war is recognized in France protection rights to abandon the suzerainty to Vietnam, trade in Qing southern provinces, he was given the privilege of railway construction in France. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.8558421628219586" SCORE="4.34039" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-S-2-5-3-9" RANK="68"> 4 first half of the century, the Roman emperor Constantine, built a second capital in Byzantine for control of the vast empire. Here face each Asia and Europe across the narrow strait, it was an important town for military and commercial that the Black Sea and the Mediterranean are in contact. Changed the Constantinople and the name, building for political, such as the Senate and palaces, water to draw water from the suburbs, such as a new harbor was built, you increase the population by, for example, sell the cheap bread to the general public . Roman Empire 395 years, and is divided into east and west two, it was more and more prosperous as the east side of the capital. 6 first half of the century, the era of Justinian was built Saint Sophia Cathedral, and became one of the center of the Christian world. Here with is inherited Roman culture, such as law, it was also guarded tradition of Greek classical culture. The city became a center of international trade, Asia, Africa, a large number of people gathered from Europe, a variety of language has been used. 1453, in Constantinople the Ottoman army is entered the castle, the Byzantine empire was ruined. The name of the city changed and Istanbul, St. Sophia Cathedral became a mosque. However, the new name of the city Chinami in Greek, Mehmed the Conqueror was guarantee the safety of the residents from the previous. Although 60% of the residents became Muslims, communities of Christians and Jews was granted autonomy. Mehmed the Conqueror tried to keep the character of an international city. The end of the 15th century Topkapi Palace was built, Islam religious facilities are also many built, along with the expansion of the Ottoman Empire, Asia, Africa, and became the capital of a large empire across Europe. Early 20th century, this town had become electricity, water, gas, tram, a modern city of the Western type subway is complete. Capital when the new Republic of Turkey established has been moved to Ankara, Istanbul is an international city eight million near population today. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.8554699471143214" SCORE="4.32882" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-4-19-2-8" RANK="69"> Versailles system was extremely unstable initially also, we are stable against the background of the recovery and the policy shift of the Soviet Union of Western Europe economy since 1923, it was born momentum of international cooperation among them. Already in 1922, the two countries diplomatic relations are resumed tied the Rapallo Treaty between Germany and the Soviet Union, had fluctuating is Germany and Soviet containment system, the powers except for the United States over the next year from '24 approved one after another Soviet Union . In addition, seven countries including the UK, Germany and France in 1925, to open a meeting in Switzerland of Locarno, Germany western border of the status quo and the inviolability, Rhineland demilitarized, France and Czechoslovakia, respectively Poland such as mutual assistance treaty, it signed a group of the Convention. Driving force behind the Convention established, Stresemann Foreign Minister of Germany, French Foreign Minister Briand, the Nobel Peace Prize of 1925 in the United Kingdom in Austin = Chamberlain Foreign Minister was awarded. This Locarno treaty European collective security system is established, Germany is next in '26, accession to the League of Nations was observed. Also, no-war treaty vowed to renunciation of war as a means of national policy implementation in 1928 (Kellogg = Briand agreement) is also tied, international cooperation has reached the apex. From reflection of the war, reduction of armaments but had been an important issue of the International Federation, national interests did not expedite at odds. However, naval disarmament is a step forward in the prevalence and the upper limit of the national capital ship is determined by the Washington Naval Treaty of 1922, but in '27 of the Geneva disarmament conference ended in failure, London disarmament of '30 prevalence and the upper limit of the auxiliary ship is determined at the meeting, we saw some progress. In Washington Naval Treaty, Ying capital ship owned tonnage ratio, rice, day, Buddha, Lee 5: 5: 3: 1.67: was 1.67. The London Conference on Disarmament, the auxiliary ship owned tonnage ratio Britain, the US, day 10: 10: 7. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.8547644444977444" SCORE="4.30705" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-2-3-4-7" RANK="70"> That Christians called Prester John has built a kingdom to the east, legend that circulated in Europe since the Middle Ages. Many monks and merchants went out on his search. When it comes to the 15th century, is seeking his presence in Ethiopia who are the Christians, Europeans has become one of the driving force to embark on African expedition. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.8546282076310671" SCORE="4.30287" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-01-03-7" RANK="71"> Christianity was born from Palestine under the rule of Rome in the first century. The priests and Pharisees who had led the Judaism at that time and deference to keeping the law formally, also because I have cooperated in Rome dominated as the Jewish ruling, did not try to answer the people's voice suffering from heavy taxes. Before long the people of Palestine, was come to expect relief from this situation. Jesus was born in this land criticized the formalism of the priests and Pharisees, and preach the absolute love and neighborly love of God exerted without rich and poor of the distinction, and promised coming and the Last Judgement of the kingdom of God. The people Messiah Jesus (Messiah. I began to follow his teachings and believe Christ) in Greek. The Messiah &quot;which was poured the plaster&quot; in Hebrew, that is in the sense of what is special blessing from God, and Christ is in the form of the Greek. Priests and Pharisees complained to the governor Pilate to Jesus as a rebel against Rome, he was executed crucified ('30 rollers). But then, resurrected Jesus in between the disciples, death on the cross is born of faith and that was an act of atonement for human sin, Christianity has been established around this. By shortly thereafter Apostle, such as Peter and Paul, missionary work began. Paul, as the God of love also extends to the Gentiles (non-Jewish ethnicity), the missionary to the Roman Empire around, spread the Christianity also in areas other than Palestine. The church is a congregation of the organization also, Asia Minor, Syria, Greece, and was built in the capital Rome. As a result, until around the third century, Christianity, mainly spread around the socially vulnerable, such as slavery, women and lower citizens empire, was soon come to be seen congregation also in the upper citizen. &quot;New Testament&quot; during this time is written in common language Koine Greek, it became the Holy Scripture of Christianity with the &quot;Old Testament&quot;. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.8536975402105598" SCORE="4.27452" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-3-17-2-12" RANK="72"> Isolationism as referred to herein, as the first half of the 19th century the Monroe declaration is a layer, it is the relationship between the logarithmic Europe, early taken the attitude of advancing against Asian. Perry is the forthcoming opening of the country to be landed in Uraga, it was in 1853. John = Hay door open declaration, is one that brute position in this trend. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.853349207400231" SCORE="4.264" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-S-2-5-3-2" RANK="73"> A result of the improvement of agricultural productivity, commerce and development, the city has passed around the powerful lords of the castle and a large church, in such transportation of key area. In addition, in the crusade of activities, remote trade also developed and east-west traffic is become popular, inside Europe, and even was able to Europe and Asia, the commercial route in between the North Africa. Genoa, Pisa, the seaport cities such as Venice, in the transaction of goods from Asia, such as silk and pepper, also, cities such as Hamburg and Lubeck in northern Germany flourished in the transaction, such as wood and fur, seafood. Such as wine and wool were exported from Western Europe. People of the city and organized the occupation each of Brotherhood (Guild), was carried out autonomy further representative of the guild is gathered. Many things Among the cities of Italy for independence as a city republic, cities that evolved from the Baltic Sea through the North Sea was against the neighboring lords and have formed the Hanseatic League. In the cities of the United Kingdom and France, citizens seeking autonomy it signed with the king in order to escape from the control of the neighboring lords. Wealthy merchants such as Fugger and Florence of the Medici family of Augsburg was left and right the international politics. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.852642271036952" SCORE="4.2428" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-99-02-1" RANK="74"> Thus integrated world, people were required many years until to share time. Plight and of a variety of human life living in the world of foreign country, different for even the shape and culture of the city by area, accurate information were being accumulated little by little fart a lot of the times. Greek astronomers, we believe that the Earth is a sphere, was devised to represent it to the map on the plane. The world view of Ptolemy drew just is, but were generally accurate for around the Mediterranean, Africa and Southeast Asia had been to be a still Rikutsuzuki. In the Islamic world, which inherited the tradition of Greek geography, based on the Observations of merchants and geographers, more detailed map of the world has been made. Islamic world map drawn in the top of the world view south of Idorishi. 12 century Nakaba, Idorishi work. Islam of cartography is brought to the Chinese Yuan Dynasty, in Korea in the early 15th century is affected by this, revolutionary world view including a West Asia and Europe has been made. Islamic world map drawn in the top of the world view south of Idorishi. 12 century Nakaba, Idorishi work. However, in between the Chinese intellectuals, then many that the world view of the country center is drawn, Chinese cartography is spread the interest and to the world, Mateo = rich is a world view and the globe is in Kanji it was that it is from the making. Kunyu wanguo quantu Jesuit missionary Matteo = rich drew China first world map. 1602, Beijing. In the Middle Ages of Europe, under the influence of Christian theology, the world view is drawn actively that centered on the Holy Land Jerusalem. The Kaaba of the Muslims of the same era Mecca considered the navel of the world, it would be similar to those regarded as that made stretched out this is a land inhabited by humans and animals. Out exit such a religious view of the world, had resulted in a geographic information actually help, it was a merchant and travel home, such as Marco Polo and Ibn = = Battuta. Line of Marco Polo = out on a journey from Venice to Asia The information their tell, regional fantasy becomes a reality, around the cities and rural areas was to be reproduced as a bustling living space that people engaged in life. 16 century, European merchants and explorers, missionaries, or such as the colonial bureaucracy visited Asia and Africa, and was Kakinokoshi are searching to various describe the kingdom and the city of &quot;unknown&quot;. Line of Marco Polo = out on a journey from Venice to Asia As seen in the spread of the calendar and standard time, the integration of the world by expanding into Asia, was carried out on the basis of European-led. These things by reference to, for example, is thinking or why of what we have come to live life every day to watch now, also examined the footprints of travel home and explorers who opened up an unknown world The Try that it will be able to also. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.85192083017782" SCORE="4.22137" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-S-3-7-4-1" RANK="75"> After the Mongol Empire collapsed in the 14th century, among which Turkey and Mongolia system of nations are competing, four large empire was unified these was born in southwest Asia. There, under the despotic power of the monarch, are grave coexistence of various ethnic and sectarian, in the center of the painting and architecture, deployment of new Islamic culture was observed. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.85192083017782" SCORE="4.22137" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-2-3-2-2" RANK="76"> Early 16th century is the golden age of the Ottoman Empire, Mughal Empire was also established as the Islamic empire. On the basis of the background, called the eastward advance of Islam, the Islam of penetration into Southeast Asia was seen. The already 15 century Malacca had been receiving Islam, in 1534 Aceh Kingdom signed the Ottoman Empire and diplomatic relations. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.8518433269244584" SCORE="4.21908" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-10-02-1" RANK="77"> At the time the Europeans have moved to Asia, mainly the form to participate in the existing Asia in trade, to become as territorial domination is important is the 18 century. Portugal, which pioneered the sea route to India, the occupied Goa of India (1510), which was the base ground of Asian trade, while conflicts with Muslim merchants who had monopolized the spice trade until then, Sri Lanka, Malacca and the Moluccas also it was placed under the control and the like. 1517, Portugal will open the Ming and trade in Guangzhou, give a right of residence in Macau in '57, he fought versus China trade here on base. Furthermore, in the wake of 1543 the ship was riding the Portuguese in the (astronomy 12 years) has been shipwrecked on Tanegashima Island, they were landed in Hirado, and with Japan and trade relations until the early 17th century. However, the Portuguese forces in Asia, in order for the trade did not lead to the development of the domestic industry in the monopoly of the royal family, did not last long. On the other hand Spain is to sovereignty over the Philippines to Felipe II era, by connecting it with Mexico, it was to expand the Asia trade was based in Manila. The Netherlands was established East India Company in 1602 and expanded into Asia, to base ground the Java of Batavia (now Jakarta), it was at the helm of the spice trade while eliminating the Portuguese merchant. Further banning the Amboyna Massacre British forces in the turning point from Indonesia, and solidified Dutch East foundation of India later, also laid the Cape Colony in South Africa as a transit area to Asia (1652). 1623, in Amboina island of eastern Indonesia Moluccas, in the reason for the conspiracy of the Dutch trading house raids (including employment Japanese) British trading house employees a number of incidents Dutch were killed. Netherlands system has been allowed to complete even trade with Japan (1639) After the &quot;seclusion&quot; in Japan, the temporary Taiwan was also occupied. On the other hand, the United Kingdom, Amboyna Massacre after, focus on India management, as a base to Madras, Bombay, Calcutta, expand the thriving trade activities, through three pairs Netherlands war, the end of the world trade in the 17th century It came to hegemony. It is France that has become the United Kingdom of the last competitor. While being founded in the early 17th century, the French East India Company, which was to stop the activity soon will be rebuilt in 1664, and entered the India under Colbert, it was against the United Kingdom the Pondicherry-Chandernagor as a base. Britain and France, has been advanced to India under the emperor and local administration of the Mughal Empire approval, Empire and fall into infighting, it expands the power struggle that involved local also of powerful families. The two countries in the 18th century, has been repeated collisions in other regions of the world such as North America, and caused the war in Europe, it has also spread abroad. During the Seven Years' War, in India, Clive, who led the mercenary army of the British East India Company, the Allied France and local government broke out in the battle of 1757 of Plassey, it laid the foundation of British India. France Governor duplex (1697-1763) was plunged into predicament a temporary United Kingdom, but was summoned to the home country in 1754. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.8512112027316925" SCORE="4.20049" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-3-7-3-9" RANK="78"> 19 century 20 century the beginning from the end, European countries focus on colonial acquisition and competing, in between the countries, conflicts and tensions without constantly was followed. On the other hand, non-European world, such as Asia and Africa, many are colonized, the region that did not become a colony also is dependent on the world economy that is centered on Europe, unstable place to the interests of the great powers are intertwined I went. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.8508562807635434" SCORE="4.19012" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-2-3-2-5" RANK="79"> This time China and done the US and is actively sugar trade, South China from merchants and immigrants of China (Overseas Chinese) is currently in Thailand and Vietnam, it moved to the Indonesian region, participated in the tribute trade under the King while, we were subjected to the activities of private trade and investment. And soon, Southeast Asia and South China Metropolitan of trade merchants and labor migration, network to invest trade funds have built up. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.850686276133194" SCORE="4.18517" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-S-1-0-0-2" RANK="80"> The oldest human beings to be confirmed today, before more than 400 million years is a monkey who appeared in Africa (Australopithecus earth), I was already using a simple stone wrote out a pebble (gravel stone). Then, I began to live the Man through Asia from Africa (Homo erectus) from before about 150 million years. Java Man of Indonesia (Java), the Peking Man of China is famous. They create a more advanced chipped stone tools, speak simple words, is believed to have used the fire. When it comes before about 20 million years, it appeared old people represented by Neanderthal found in Germany (Homo sapiens • The value Andel Taren cis). They are the master of hunting, defeated a large animal, such as Mammoth skillfully using a spear wearing a sharp stone tools ahead of the tree. In addition, since the carefully buried the dead, it is already believed to have had a primitive religion consciousness. Direct ancestor of the current human race is said to rookie (modern humans, Homo sapiens sapiens), and appeared on the earth before about 40,000 years. Rookie such as Cro-Magnon in Asia, Africa, live in large areas of Europe, it began to eventually adapt to each of the local climate and culture. This time, the human race is the Americas was a Rikutsuzuki, and went live move also to the Australian continent. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.8497922576673494" SCORE="4.15932" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-2-6-4-5" RANK="81"> France is followed in occupied temporarily Egypt in the late 18th century, in 1830, began again Algeria of aggression was the Ottoman Empire. Abd Al Kadeer led but was followed by the people of the resistance, in the 1870s, immigration policy has been promoted under the third Republic. Then in 1881, France was occupied Tunis. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.8487294595704737" SCORE="4.12898" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-2-3-5-10" RANK="82"> European countries of the absolute monarchy period, opened a permanent diplomatic relations and to exchange resident diplomatic envoys. Diplomatic rights from the fact that the king had been seized, this time of diplomacy is called a court diplomacy. Countries of kings and nobles are closely linked in such marriage, the court was shaped the international society with a common way of life for the French as a common language. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.8480211178000223" SCORE="4.10899" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-2-6-3-4" RANK="83"> It started from the use denial incident of ammunition wrapped. April 1857, in the regiment of the Delhi suburb of Meerut, were widespread rumors that painted a beef tallow and lard to the newly distributed the medicine package. Cattle for Hindus is a sacred, pigs are repellent for Muslims. Sepoy us, it rejects the use of this medicine package, which triggered the revolt. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.847667183250374" SCORE="4.09907" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-2-3-5-2" RANK="84"> Edo Shogunate was a merchant was admitted only trade from the Netherlands State Union in Europe. In the Netherlands, because the ruler of the King of Spain was oppression of the new Muslims, war of independence began in the late 16th century. Holland is a province that was its center, from Holland man was the bearer of international commerce at the time, but not a formal country, the Netherlands has become a street. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.847284320886484" SCORE="4.08839" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-4-19-3-4" RANK="85"> In the United Kingdom after the first World War, the economy is stagnant, the labor movement has been uplifting. Government, but survived the offensive of workers by attaching the cooperation of moderate union leadership, workers got a new right to vote in the fourth-order election law amendment in war, put the expectation in Labour Party It became way. In the fourth-order election law amendment of 1918, voting rights of suffrage and 30 years of age or older women of men over 21 years of age it was observed, in the fifth-order election law amendment of 1928, to men and women all over 21 years of age suffrage was given. In the general election of 1923 the Labour Party, which became the second party, per the first time government in coalition with the Liberal Party the following year, the first-order McDonald's Cabinet is satisfied. The Labour Party Cabinet, it has been recommended a social policy to accept the Soviet Union, was short-lived. However, this after Liberals continue to decline, politics came to an two-party era of the Conservative Party and the Labour Party. United Kingdom in the face of exaltation of ethnic movement after the war, while suppress the independence movement of India and Egypt, and recognized the autonomy to Ireland with the exception of northern Ulster, in 1922 the Irish Free State was established. Although Ireland Autonomy Law was established in 1914, when the First World War begins, implementation has been postponed. The country was declared the full independence in 1937, is referred to as Yale, it was renamed the ale (Ireland) Republic in '49. In addition, the Dominion, which cooperated in the home country at war, and recognize the relationship between the home country and equal in the British Empire Conference of 1926, was organized the British Commonwealth. Then this system has been legislated by '31 Westminster Charter. On the other hand France, sometimes you have lost huge claims against Imperial Russia in the Russian Revolution, it joined the Soviet Union interference war, demanded excessive compensation in Germany. However, it fails to rule the occupation of 1923, left-wing coalition government has been established. Briand Foreign Minister aim to cooperation with Germany, is withdrawal from the rule in 1925, it signed a Locarno treaty. Then, in '28 it was passed a no-war treaty in cooperation with the Secretary of State Kellogg of the United States. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.8460827347606845" SCORE="4.05521" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-A-2-7-2-4" RANK="86"> Europeans who over the New World 100 years up to the First World War is also Oyobi to 6 million people, the 19th century was a very century of immigration. From the first half of the century north-west Europe, in the second half seen many immigrants from Southern and Eastern Europe, which shows the shift of the Industrial Revolution. Not only economic factors such as population growth and poverty, were also made immigrants from political factors as the Jews were persecuted. While immigrants from Europe until the 18th century was mainly labor immigration that took the form of indentured, free immigration has become mainstream in the 19th century. In addition, when black slaves is released in the 19th century Nakaba, and hired workers from China and India, supplemented with the labor force shortage. In Asia and Africa of the colonial European countries, the colonial from the policy in Europe was done for colonial management. It had been supporting the colonial management in Southeast Asia, rubber and tin of the Malay Peninsula, in agricultural production of Indonesia, there has been required the labor force has been procured from southern China and southern India. Even more things to advance to the commercial activity Along with this, these Chinese immigrants (Overseas Chinese) and Indian immigrants, then, had to have a big influence in Southeast Asia. Also as immigrants to Africa many from India, under the British Empire it was also made colonization of inter-British colony. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.8460294361126269" SCORE="4.05375" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="Y-JH-12-01-2" RANK="87"> French Revolution and liberalism and nationalism woke up under the Napoleonic domination (nationalist) caused a variety of rebellious movement against the Vienna regime. Students' Union Bull Shen shaft and Italian anti-government movement of the secret society of the Carbonari Germany, but has occurred, such as a constitutional revolution of Spain, both have been put down. Austria is a multi-ethnic nation, but he was from the standpoint of conservatism in its suppression, the United Kingdom in early 1820 began to show the attitude to leave the Vienna regime. In Latin America, as triggered by the resistance movement by Tusan = Ruvu~eru tulle, it becomes black republic independent French territory Haiti in 1804, in the 1810's fingerprint = Bolivar in the northern part of South America, Saint-Martin is independence movement in the south and teaching, and was achieved independence beginning Mexico also uprising of Hidalgo. Haiti became the end of the 15th century the Spanish, but I was changed in the 17th century the end of French colonial. Independence of Latin America These movements, which was a mainly a Kurioryo layer is a white colonial-born, dominated the squire of Kurioryo was followed in the Republic was born after independence from Spain. Did constitute a Latin American residents, in addition to the Kurioryo, Mestizo (Indigenous and whites of mixed race), Indio (indigenous people), mulatto (whites and blacks of mixed race), it was a hierarchy, such as black. On the other hand Brazil, prince of Portugal became an independent empire (in 1889 after the Republic) for the throne. However, the President of the United States Monroe cast Americas and Europe of mutual non-interference in the Monroe State of the Union of 1823, because it was recognized the independence of countries in the United Kingdom Foreign Minister Canning also aimed at the development of the Latin America market, Metternich interference to these independence movement it was not able to. In Europe, and Greece causes a war of independence from 1821 the Ottoman Empire, since the United Kingdom, France and Russia helped it from interests for the Balkans, is independence achieved in 1829, approval of Rekkoku at the London conference of '30 me painting. December 1825 In Russia, when Nikolai I's coronation, but young officer of noble has caused a turbulent of Decembrists (December party members) seeking liberal reform, and was immediately put down. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.8460265145929032" SCORE="4.05367" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-3-14-2-2" RANK="88"> Portugal and Spain entered the various waters of Asia, Asia and Europe, as a result of now Americas is tied largely in Asia was supposed to be trade activities between various waters is further activated. Malacca was occupied by the Portuguese in 1511. However, Malacca royal family was transferred the trade centers on the island along the same Straits of Malacca, for a collection of Muslim merchants, Malacca of Portugal was isolated. In addition, Muslim merchants also to avoid the Malacca Strait to the rule of Portugal, you can fart the west coast of Sumatra from the Indian Ocean, is missing the Sunda Strait between Sumatra and Java, he pioneered the route to enter the Java Sea. As a result, Sumatra Aceh Kingdom and the northern end facing the Indian Ocean, the Banten Kingdom press the thriving West Java of the position to pepper production to the outlet of the Sunda Strait flourished. Both in the Islamic nation, Aceh performs trade directly with the Ottoman Empire, became both the center of Southeast Asia of Islam. Around the same time, it takes place Islam of Mataram kingdom in Central Java, was flourished by connecting the trade routes of the rice producing area and the Java Sea of ​​Java. In this way, triggered by the Malacca conquest of Portugal, a number of trade centers has been established in Southeast Asia. The second half of the 16th century, and loosen Umikin policy of China, a large number of Chinese merchants now landed, Southeast Asian sea trade was booming. On the other hand, inland, it becomes to supply actively rice and tropical products in various port city to prosperity, this along with the political restructuring has occurred. Since 13-of-the-century of Pagan kingdom collapse, in Burma, which has been split, To~ungu kingdom was successful across the country unified in the early 16th century. To~ungu kingdom, but the debacle once in 1599, will be rebuilt in 1605. This kingdom, as well as carry out the trade that connects the Southeast Asia inland and the Bay of Bengal, but in the second half of the 16th century was capture the Ayutthaya kingdom, was soon split. Re-independent Ayutthaya kingdom in the late 16th century, while supplying the rice in various port city of Southeast Asia, Japan and China, Portugal, and in the 17th century, the Netherlands, the United Kingdom, both France conducted trade, flourished as a commercial nation. In Vietnam Later Le Dynasty Okoshi country, but domestic had split from the 16th century mid, influential Mr. Zheng of the Later Le Dynasty is I have rebuilt the Okoshi country entered the Hanoi at the end of the 16th century. However, 阮氏 to be opposed to Mr. Zheng has built a wide south (Gangnam) kingdom moved to Hue in Central, both forces are both Portuguese ship and Dutch ships, was actively trade and trading ships licensed by the shogunate of Japan. </PASSAGE>
      <PASSAGE NORMALIZED_SCORE="0.8458206392942388" SCORE="4.04804" SOURCE_ID_TYPE="QALab3" SOURCE_ID="T-WH-B-4-19-5-8" RANK="89"> After the war, in Eastern Europe that many of the independent country was born, after countries that had the complex ethnic problem, the impact of the global agricultural recession, the political was also economically unstable. For this reason, in most of the country, from the previously 1920s, conservative dictatorship was made by landowners and military. In Hungary, also dictatorship 25 years since 1919 Horuti continued, Pilsudski has started the military dictatorship from '26 in Poland. Yugoslavia is shifted to the king dictatorship in 1929, Bulgaria, Romania king also, in the 1930s was declared one after another the dictatorship government. Comintern, which could not be prevented from fascism and militaristic dictatorship regime, at the 7th Congress of 1935, it was converted policies to hostile social democratic parties of up to it, all the forces opposed to cooperate to fascism We have proposed the formation of the Popular Front (antifascist united front). In France, it established the Popular Front cabinet that Prime Minister Blum of the Socialist Party in 1936, was enacted and paid leave law that triggers of today's Vacances. In Spain, second Republic is established in 1931, separation of church and state and land reform has been grave. Landowners and with a sense of crisis in this, capitalist, is support to the church forces, and right-wing political parties to rise, such as the Socialist Party and the Communist Party in 1936 was born the Popular Front government in cooperation. On the other hand, Franco generals revolted in Morocco, civil war spread throughout the country, Germany and Italy helped Franco to send troops. The Popular Front side the Soviet Union to help, also for intellectuals and workers in each country, such as Hemingway and the United Kingdom of Orwell of the United States participated as international volunteers, the Spanish civil war and the field of international confrontation of the Popular Front and fascism became. However, in addition to the non-interference policy of Britain and France, there is also opposition inside the Popular Front, civil war by fall Madrid in 1939, and the end to the Franco side of victory, Franco's dictatorship was followed thereafter. In Portugal, Salazar of dictatorship it has been carried out since 1933. </PASSAGE>
    </PASSAGE_SET>
  </TOPIC>
</TOPIC_SET>